快  一點  啦  今天  大  日子  耶
kuài   yī diǎn   la   jīn tiān   dà   rì zi   yé
rapid a little la  today     big day    ye
Hurry up, it's a big day.
你  想  讓  新娘  子  等  你  一個人  喔
nǐ   xiǎng   ràng   xīn niáng   zi   děng   nǐ   yī gè rén   ō
you think  allow bride      offspring wait  you A person   cry
You don't want to make the bride wait for you, do you?
老  闆  一樣
lǎo   bǎn   yī yàng
old  boss same
The usual, boss.
錢  一樣  跟  我  媽  算
qián   yī yàng   gēn   wǒ   mā   suàn
money same     with I   mother count
Put it on my mom's tab.
好  ok
hǎo   ok
good ok
All right, no problem
1994  年
1994  nián
1994 year
那一  年  我  十六歲
nà yī   nián   wǒ   shí liù suì
That one year  I   Sixteen years old
I was 16 that year
張  雨  生  的  歌聲  還  在
zhāng   yǔ   shēng   de   gē shēng   hái   zài
stretch rain life   of  singing   still in
Chang Yu-Sheng's voice was still heard on TV shows.
張  學  友  的  「    吻別  」    大  賣了  一百  多  萬  張卡  帶
zhāng   xué   yǒu   de   「    wěn bié   」    dà   mài le   yī bǎi   duō   wàn   zhāng kǎ   dài
stretch learning friend of  「  Kiss the other 」  big sold    hundred much innumerable Zhang card take
Jacky Cheung sold more than one million cassettes for the "KissGoodbye" album.
組  頭  還沒  開始  看  中  華  職  棒
zǔ   tóu   hái méi   kāi shǐ   kàn   zhōng   huá   zhí   bàng
class head not yet  Start    look central flowery duty stick
The bookies hadn't started watching CPBL
經  典  的  龍  象  大戰  總是  滿  場
jīng   diǎn   de   lóng   xiàng   dà zhàn   zǒng shì   mǎn   chǎng
through law   of  dragon elephant War      always    fill field
and the classic Dragon-Elephant games were always sold out.
那  年
nà   nián
that year
That year
有  一個  皮膚  黑  黑  的  女生  五  度  五  關  (    張  惠  妹  )
yǒu   yī gè   pí fū   hēi   hēi   de   nǚ shēng   wǔ   dù   wǔ   guān   (    zhāng   huì   mèi   )
have One    skin   black black of  Girls     five degree five close (  stretch favor younger sister )
a girl with tanned skin won the championship on the local talent show
贏得  了  五  燈  獎  的  冠軍
yíng dé   le   wǔ   dēng   jiǎng   de   冠軍
win      is  five lantern prize  of  冠軍
for five consecutive rounds.
那一  年  …
nà yī   nián   …
That one year  …
That year...
那些  年
nà xiē   nián
those   year
Those years.
我  叫  柯  景  騰
wǒ   jiào   kē   jǐng   téng
I   call  stalk scenery fly
My name is Ko Ching-Teng.
同  學  都  叫  我  柯  騰
tóng   xué   dōu   jiào   wǒ   kē   téng
same  learning all  call  I   stalk fly
My friends called me Ko-Teng
我  國中  念  的  是  彰  化  市  精  誠  中  學
wǒ   guó zhōng   niàn   de   shì   zhāng   huà   shì   jīng   chéng   zhōng   xué
I   secondary  recall of  is   clear  change market essence sincere central learning
I went to Jingcheng in Changhua City for junior high school.
高  中  念  的  也是  精  誠  中  學
gāo   zhōng   niàn   de   yě shì   jīng   chéng   zhōng   xué
high central recall of  Also too essence sincere central learning
As for high school, I stuck to the same one, too.
這  是  許  博  淳
zhè   shì   xǔ   bó   chún
this is   allow gamble honest
This is Hsu Bo-Chun.
從  國中  起  就是  我  最好  的  朋友
cóng   guó zhōng   qǐ   jiù shì   wǒ   zuì hǎo   de   péng yǒu
from  secondary  onward That is  I   best     of  friend
He has been my best friend since junior high school.
許  博  淳  隨時隨地  都  在  勃  起
xǔ   bó   chún   suí shí suí dì   dōu   zài   bó   qǐ
allow gamble honest Anytime         all  in   suddenly onward
He's always getting a boner
所以  外  號  叫  「    勃  起  」
suǒ yǐ   wài   hào   jiào   「    bó   qǐ   」
and so  out  day  call  「  suddenly onward 」
that's why we named him "Boner".
幹
gàn
trunk
Fuck!
幹  三  小
gàn   sān   xiǎo
trunk three small
Fuck what?
死  柯  騰  別  跑
sǐ   kē   téng   bié   pǎo
die stalk fly   separate run
You are dead meat. Don't run.
這  是  阿  和
zhè   shì   ā   hàn
this is   a  and
This is A-Ho.
我們  從  國  小  就  一直  同  班  到  高  中
wǒ men   cóng   guó   xiǎo   jiù   yī zhí   tóng   bān   dào   gāo   zhōng
us      from  nation small just Always  same  class arrive high central
We have been in the same class all the way from elementary to high school.
每一  個  故事  都  有  一個  胖  子
měi yī   ge   gù shì   dōu   yǒu   yī gè   pàng   zi
Each one piece story   all  have One    fat   offspring
There is a fat guy in every story.
阿  和  就是  那一  個  胖  子
ā   hàn   jiù shì   nà yī   ge   pàng   zi
a  and  That is  That one piece fat   offspring
A-Ho is the fat guy in our story.
你們  很  煩  耶
nǐ men   hěn   fán   yé
you     very bother ye
Stop bugging me.
剛剛  好  啦
gāng gāng   hǎo   la
just       good la
Why not?
教  官  早
jiào   guān   zǎo
teach official early
Good morning, Sir.
早
zǎo
early
Good morning.
教  官  早
jiào   guān   zǎo
teach official early
Good morning, Sir.
早
zǎo
early
Good morning.
教  官  早
jiào   guān   zǎo
teach official early
Good morning, Sir.
教  官  早
jiào   guān   zǎo
teach official early
Good morning, Sir.
早
zǎo
early
Good morning.
教  官  早
jiào   guān   zǎo
teach official early
Good morning, Sir.
頭髮  太  長  囉
tóu fà   tài   chǎng   luō
hair    very long   nag
Your hair is too long.
該  剪  的  要  剪  一  剪  了
gāi   jiǎn   de   yào   jiǎn   yī   jiǎn   le
should scissors of  need scissors one scissors is
It's time to get a haircut.
你  不要  每天  都  這樣  好不好
nǐ   bù yào   měi tiān   dōu   zhè yàng   hǎo bù hǎo
you Do not  every day all  such      ok
Gosh, can you stop that?
怎樣
zěn yàng
how
What?
不要  每次  都  從  後面  嚇  人  啊
bù yào   měi cì   dōu   cóng   hòu miàn   xià   rén   a
Do not  Each    all  from  Behind    scare man  ah
Stop doing that
跟  你  講  幾  次  了
gēn   nǐ   jiǎng   jǐ   cì   le
with you explain some order is
I have told you a million times!
所以  咧
suǒ yǐ   liě
and so  grimace
Why not?
很  浪費  啊
hěn   làng fèi   a
very waste     ah
You totally wasted my food
我  熱  狗  只吃  一口
wǒ   rè   gǒu   zhǐ chī   一口
I   hot dog  Eat only 一口
I only had one bite of that hotdog.
所以
suǒ yǐ
and so
So...
啊  你  是  不會  接  喔
a   nǐ   shì   bù huì   jiē   ō
ah you is   will not receive cry
Don't you know how to catch?
曹  雞  巴
cáo   jī   bā
surname chickens desire
Cock Tsao.
一大  早就  那麼  雞  巴
yī dà   zǎo jiù   nà me   jī   bā
A big one Long ago like that chickens desire
Why are you such a jackass in the morning.
我  跟  你  說
wǒ   gēn   nǐ   shuō
I   with you speak
You know what?
昨天  我  抽  到  Grant  Hill  1:  40  的  限定  卡
zuó tiān   wǒ   chōu   dào   Grant  Hill  1:  40  de   xiàn dìng   kǎ
yesterday I   sprout arrive Grant Hill 1: 40 of  limited    card
I won a Grant Hill 1 to 40 limited edition card yesterday.
這  是  老  曹
zhè   shì   lǎo   cáo
this is   old  surname
This is Tsao.
老  曹  從  國中  跟  我  同  班  就是  一個  很  雞  巴  的  人
lǎo   cáo   cóng   guó zhōng   gēn   wǒ   tóng   bān   jiù shì   yī gè   hěn   jī   bā   de   rén
old  surname from  secondary  with I   same  class That is  One    very chickens desire of  man
We have been classmates ever since junior high and he has always been an ass.
所以  有  時候  我  會叫  老  曹
suǒ yǐ   yǒu   shí hou   wǒ   huì jiào   lǎo   cáo
and so  have time     I   Will be called old  surname
We called him.
(Cock, Cocky, Dumbass Tsao or "Tsao motherfucker")
這麼  雞  巴
zhè me   jī   bā
so      chickens desire
Show off?
不然  你  拿  你  1:  100  的  Penny  Hardaway  來  換
bù rán   nǐ   ná   nǐ   1:  100  de   Penny  Hardaway  lái   huàn
otherwise you take you 1: 100 of  Penny Hardaway come change
We can switch then for your 1 to 100 Penny Hardaway cards.
我  才不  要  咧
wǒ   cái bù   yào   liě
I   never   need grimace
No way!
不要  不要  還  來
bù yào   bù yào   hái   lái
Do not  Do not  still come
Piss off, then.
我  這  幾個  好  朋友  唯  一  的  共  通  點
wǒ   zhè   jǐ gè   hǎo   péng yǒu   wéi   yī   de   gòng   tōng   diǎn
I   this several good friend    only one of  all   common dot
The only thing that these boys shared in common with...
就是  喜歡  班  上  最  乖  的  好  學生
jiù shì   xǐ huan   bān   shàng   zuì   guāi   de   hǎo   xué shēng
That is  like     class on     most rebel of  good student
was that they all had a crush on the honor student in the class.
沈  佳  宜
chén   jiā   yí
sink  good suitable
Shen Chia-Yi.
在  我  看起來
zài   wǒ   kàn qǐ lái
in   I   Looks like
From my point of view.
沈  佳  宜  只是  比  一般  的  女生  還要  再  漂亮  一點點  而已
chén   jiā   yí   zhǐ shì   bǐ   yī bān   de   nǚ shēng   hái yào   zài   piào liang   yī diǎn diǎn   ér yǐ
sink  good suitable just     liken general of  Girls     But also again Pretty      a little bit  Just now
Shen Chia-Yi was only slightly prettier than the other girls.
真  搞  不懂
zhēn   gǎo   bù dǒng
real  clear Do not understand
Don't know what the guys were thinking.
欸  沈  佳  宜
āi   chén   jiā   yí
sigh sink  good suitable
Shen Chia-Yi.
幹  嘛
gàn   ma
trunk ma
Yes?
妳  昨天  有  看  玫瑰  之夜  嗎
nai   zuó tiān   yǒu   kàn   méi guī   zhī yè   ma
nǎi  yesterday have look rose     night of ?
Did you watch Rose Night yesterday?
妳  說  那個  太  極  峽谷  的  那個  照片  啊
nai   shuō   nà gè   tài   jí   xiá gǔ   de   nà gè   照片  a
nǎi  speak that one very extreme canyon  of  that one 照片 ah
Are you talking about the Taichi Gorge photo?
對  呀  我  覺得  超  可怕  的
duì   ya   wǒ   jué de   chāo   kě pà   de
to   yeah I   feel    surpass terrible of
Yeah, the picture was horrifying
而且  我  全身  都  起  雞  皮  疙  瘩  了
ér qiě   wǒ   quán shēn   dōu   qǐ   jī   pí   gē   da   le
and     I   whole body all  onward chickens skin pimple pimples is
I got goose bumps all over.
那個  故事  聽起來  很  可怕
nà gè   gù shì   tīng qǐ lái   hěn   kě pà
that one story   sound        very terrible
The story sounds terrifying but...
可是  那  張照片  我  看  不太  出來  耶
kě shì   nà   zhāng zhào piàn   wǒ   kàn   bù tài   chū lái   yé
but     that a photograph     I   look Not too much come out ye
I can't really tell from the picture though
我  覺得  只是  拍  攝  角度  的  問題
wǒ   jué de   zhǐ shì   pāi   shè   jiǎo dù   de   wèn tí
I   feel    just     clap absorb angle    of  problem
I think it was the shooting angle that does the trick.
真的  嗎
zhēn de   ma
Really   ?
You think so?
第五  課  跟  第六  課  的  考  卷
dì wǔ   kè   gēn   dì liù   kè   de   kǎo   juǎn
fifth  lesson with sixth   lesson of  examine scroll
Now, start doing the exercises for lesson five and six.
寫  不  完  的  升  旗  後  繼續  寫
xiě   bù   wán   de   shēng   qí   hòu   jì xù   xiě
write no  complete of  arise  banner after carry on write
Continue after the assembly if you can't finish.
自己  寫  自己  的
zì jǐ   xiě   zì jǐ   de
self   write self   of
Focus on your own exercises.
不可以  討論
bù kě yǐ   tǎo lùn
Can not   discuss
No discussion.
這  是  廖  英  宏
zhè   shì   liào   yīng   hóng
this is   surname petal wide
This is Liao Ying-Hung.
廖  這個  姓
liào   zhè ge   xìng
surname This one surname
His surname, Liao, is a verb in Chinese.
是個  動  詞
shì gè   dòng   cí
Is      move  words
And it means to scratch.
既然是  個  動  詞
jì rán shì   ge   dòng   cí
Since it is piece move  words
Since it's a verb
就  不能  白白  浪費
jiù   bù néng   bái bái   làng fèi
just Can not  in vain  waste
we should make good use of this verb.
所以  我們  幫  他  取  了  個  綽號
suǒ yǐ   wǒ men   bāng   tā   qǔ   le   ge   chuò hào
and so  us      assist he  take is  piece nickname
Thus, we gave him a nickname.
叫  「    廖  該  邊  」
jiào   「    liào   gāi   biān   」
call  「  surname should side  」
"Groin" (Scratching Groin)
該  邊  當然  也  喜歡  沈  佳  宜
gāi   biān   dāng rán   yě   xǐ huan   chén   jiā   yí
should side  of course also like     sink  good suitable
"Groin" likes Shen Chia-Yi, too.
因為  該  邊  喜歡  班  上  每一  個  女生
yīn wèi   gāi   biān   xǐ huan   bān   shàng   měi yī   ge   nǚ shēng
because  should side  like     class on     Each one piece Girls
That's because he likes every girl in the class.
一大  清早  就  這麼
yī dà   qīng zǎo   jiù   zhè me
A big one Early in the morning just so
It's early morning and everyone looks half asleep.
沒  精神
méi   jīng shén
not  spirit
Stand straight.
還  睡
hái   shuì
still sleep
Wake up!
站  好
zhàn   hǎo
station good
Stand straight.
還  動
hái   dòng
still move
Stop moving.
起立
qǐ lì
stand up
Stand up.
立  正
lì   zhèng
stand right
Attention.
敬禮
jìng lǐ
salute
Salute.
老師  好
lǎo shī   hǎo
teacher  good
Good morning, Miss Chou.
各位  同  學好  坐下
gè wèi   tóng   xué hǎo   zuò xià
Everybody same  Learn well sit down
Good morning, everyone. Sit down.
乾  隆  丁  亥  年
gān   lóng   dīng   hai   nián
dry  prosperous robust hài  year
In year 1974, it was still the Qing dynasty.
也就  在
yě jiù   zài
Also    in
So it means that.
丁  亥  年  就  在  我們  乾  隆  的  三十  二年
dīng   hai   nián   jiù   zài   wǒ men   gān   lóng   de   sān shí   èr nián
robust hài  year  just in   us      dry  prosperous of  thirty   Two years
It was the thirty second year that China was ruled under Emperor Qianlong.
其實  高  中  跟  國中  差  不了  多少
qí shí   gāo   zhōng   gēn   guó zhōng   chà   bù liǎo   duō shǎo
in fact high central with secondary  different No more than that How many
There was really not that much difference between junior high and senior high.
地獄  十七  層  跟  十六  層  的  差  別  而已
dì yù   shí qī   céng   gēn   shí liù   céng   de   chà   bié   ér yǐ
hell   Seventeen storey with sixteen  storey of  different separate Just now
Just a matter of how deep you are in hell.
唸  書  考試  整個  很  無聊
niàn   shū   考試  zhěng gè   hěn   wú liáo
recite book 考試 entire    very bored
Endless studies, exams... it's all very boring!
有  人物  時間  還有  再來  就是  地點
yǒu   rén wù   shí jiān   hái yǒu   zài lái   jiù shì   dì diǎn
have character time      and also Come again That is  location
There is the character, the time and then it's the place.
那  地點  是  在  哪裡  呢
nà   dì diǎn   shì   zài   nǎ lǐ   ne
that location is   in   where  this
Where is the place?
地點  就  在  我們  的  上  元  之  …
dì diǎn   jiù   zài   wǒ men   de   shàng   yuán   zhī   …
location just in   us      of  on     first it   …
The place...
但  想  辦法  找  一點  事  做  就  不會  那麼  無聊  了
dàn   xiǎng   bàn fǎ   zhǎo   yī diǎn   shì   zuò   jiù   bù huì   nà me   wú liáo   le
only think  Method  search a little thing work just will not like that bored    is
But, we can always find a way to entertain ourselves!
許  博  淳
xǔ   bó   chún
allow gamble honest
Hsu Bo-Chun
起來  念  下  一段
qǐ lái   niàn   xià   yī duàn
stand up recall under A paragraph
stand up and read the next section.
站起來  念  啊
zhàn qǐ lái   niàn   a
stand up     recall ah
Stand up and read.
上  到  哪一  段  都  不知道
shàng   dào   nǎ yī   duàn   dōu   bù zhī dào
on     arrive Which one section all  do not know
You don't even know where we are.
有  沒有  在  上  課  啊
yǒu   méi yǒu   zài   shàng   kè   a
have No       in   on     lesson ah
Hello... are you in the classroom.
柯  景  騰
kē   jǐng   téng
stalk scenery fly
Ko Ching-Teng
你  在  笑  什麼
nǐ   zài   xiào   shén me
you in   smile what
what are you laughing at?
你  念
nǐ   niàn
you recall
You read it.
汝  以  一  念  之  貞  遇  人  仳  離
rǔ   yǐ   yī   niàn   zhī   zhēn   yù   rén   pǐ   lí
you thereby one recall it   virtuous meet man  separate leave
(Reading paragraphs from the textbook)
站起來  念
zhàn qǐ lái   niàn
stand up     recall
Stand up and read.
不是  很  方便
bù shì   hěn   fāng biàn
not     very Convenience
It's not very convenient.
什麼  叫做  「    不是  很  方便  」
shén me   jiào zuò   「    bù shì   hěn   fāng biàn   」
what     Called it 「  not     very Convenience 」
What do you mean "not very convenient"?
站起來
zhàn qǐ lái
stand up
Stand up.
上  課  打  手  槍
shàng   kè   dǎ   shǒu   qiāng
on     lesson strike hand  spear
Jerking off.
上  課  打  手  槍
shàng   kè   dǎ   shǒu   qiāng
on     lesson strike hand  spear
Jerking off right in the class
我  教  書  教  這麼  多年
wǒ   jiào   shū   jiào   zhè me   duō nián
I   teach book teach so      for many years
I have been a teacher for so many years
考試  作  弊  的
考試  zuò   bì   de
考試 make evil of
I have seen students who cheat
打架  的
dǎ jià   de
fight   of
get into fights
勒索  同  學  的
lè suǒ   tóng   xué   de
blackmail same  learning of
black mail.
甚至  於  想  打  老師  的
shèn zhì   yú   xiǎng   dǎ   lǎo shī   de
even      in  think  strike teacher  of
Or even those who beat up teachers!
什麼  壞  學生  我  沒  見過
shén me   huài   xué shēng   wǒ   méi   jiàn guò
what     bad   student    I   not  Seen it
I have seen all kinds of problematic students
我  就  沒  見過  像  你們  這樣  變  態  的
wǒ   jiù   méi   jiàn guò   xiàng   nǐ men   zhè yàng   biàn   tài   de
I   just not  Seen it   image  you     such      change manner of
but just no perverts like you!
又  沒有  射
yòu   méi yǒu   shè
and  No       shoot
I didn't even ejaculate.
你  還說
nǐ   hái shuō
you Said
And that's an excuse?
對  呀
duì   ya
to   yeah
Yeah.
我們  只是  打好  …
wǒ men   zhǐ shì   dǎ hǎo   …
us      just     Play well …
We were just fooling around...
你  也  一樣
nǐ   yě   yī yàng
you also same
You, too.
你們  父母  花  這麼  多錢  把  你們  送到  學校  來  讀書
nǐ men   fù mǔ   huā   zhè me   duō qián   bǎ   nǐ men   sòng dào   學校  lái   dú shū
you     parents flower so      Rich      take you     Sent to   學校 come reading
Your parents spent so much money to send you to school
你們  不知道  好好  珍惜
nǐ men   bù zhī dào   hǎo hǎo   zhēn xī
you     do not know Well     Cherish
and you guys don't even cherish how lucky you are.
什麼  是  打  手  槍  啊
shén me   shì   dǎ   shǒu   qiāng   a
what     is   strike hand  spear  ah
What's jerk off?
上  課  打  手  槍
shàng   kè   dǎ   shǒu   qiāng
on     lesson strike hand  spear
Jerking off in the classroom.
喂
wèi
hey
Hey?
我  不知道  耶
wǒ   bù zhī dào   yé
I   do not know ye
I don't know.
沈  佳  宜
chén   jiā   yí
sink  good suitable
Shen Chia-Yi
你  出來  一下
nǐ   chū lái   yí xià
you come out a bit
come out here for a second.
沈  佳  宜
chén   jiā   yí
sink  good suitable
Shen Chia-Yi
柯  景  騰  以後  坐  在  你  前面
kē   jǐng   téng   yǐ hòu   zuò   zài   nǐ   qián miàn
stalk scenery fly   after   sit  in   you front
from now on, Ko Ching-Teng will sit in front of you.
你  幫  老師  好好  管  管  他
nǐ   bāng   lǎo shī   hǎo hǎo   guǎn   guǎn   tā
you assist teacher  Well     manage manage he
Keep an eye on him for me.
千萬  不要  讓  他  把  其他  同  學  帶  壞
qiān wàn   bù yào   ràng   tā   bǎ   qí tā   tóng   xué   dài   huài
Ten million Do not  allow he  take other  same  learning take bad
Don't let him be a bad influence on others.
順便  督  促  一下  他  功  課
shùn biàn   dū   cù   yí xià   tā   gōng   kè
By the way supervise urge a bit   he  achievement lesson
Give him a push on his schoolwork, as well.
知  不知道
zhī   bù zhī dào
know do not know
Okay?
許  博  淳
xǔ   bó   chún
allow gamble honest
Hsu Bo-Chun.
以後
yǐ hòu
after
In the future
你  坐  在  謝  明和  前面
nǐ   zuò   zài   xiè   míng hé   qián miàn
you sit  in   thank Ming and front
you will sit in front of Hsieh Ming-Ho.
一樣
yī yàng
same
The same goes for you.
不要  給  我  作  怪
bù yào   gěi   wǒ   zuò   guài
Do not  give I   make strange
Don't goof around again.
再  作  怪  的話  我  請  你  父母  到  學校  來
zài   zuò   guài   de huà   wǒ   qǐng   nǐ   fù mǔ   dào   學校  lái
again make strange if      I   ask   you parents arrive 學校 come
If you do, I will ask your parents to come to school.
聽到  沒有
tīng dào   méi yǒu
Hear it   No
Get it?
聽到
tīng dào
Hear it
Got it.
都  上  課  去
dōu   shàng   kè   qù
all  on     lesson go
Now, go to your class.
謝謝  老師
xiè xiè   lǎo shī
Thank you teacher
Thank you, sir.
雖然  沈  佳  宜  國中  已經  跟  我  同  班  了  三年
suī rán   chén   jiā   yí   guó zhōng   yǐ jīng   gēn   wǒ   tóng   bān   le   sān nián
although sink  good suitable secondary  already  with I   same  class is  Three years
Even though Shen Chia-Yi and I have been in the same class ever since junior high
但  好  學生  跟  壞  學生  之間  的  距離
dàn   hǎo   xué shēng   gēn   huài   xué shēng   zhī jiān   de   jù lí
only good student    with bad   student    between   of  distance
the distance between an honor student and a bad student
並沒有  因此  有  任何  的  改變
bìng méi yǒu   yīn cǐ   yǒu   rèn hé   de   gǎi biàn
not at all    therefore have any     of  change
always stayed the same.
換  到  這  種  鳥  地方  倒  霉  啊  倒  霉  啊
huàn   dào   zhè   zhǒng   niǎo   dì fāng   dào   méi   a   dào   méi   a
change arrive this seed   bird  place    inverted mildew ah inverted mildew ah
It's shitty luck to sit in such a shitty seat.
到底是  誰  倒  霉  啊
dào dǐ shì   sheí   dào   méi   a
In the end is who   inverted mildew ah
Who has bad luck now?
坐  在  我  前面
zuò   zài   wǒ   qián miàn
sit  in   I   front
You are sitting in front of me now.
你  不要  再  搞  一些  幼稚  的  把  戲
nǐ   bù yào   zài   gǎo   yī xiē   yòu zhì   de   bǎ   xì
you Do not  again clear some    naive    of  take show
You better stop your childish pranks.
造成  我  的  困擾
zào chéng   wǒ   de   kùn rǎo
Cause      I   of  Troubled
So you don't bring me unnecessary troubles.
當  好  學生  真好
dāng   hǎo   xué shēng   zhēn hǎo
that  good student    that's nice
It must be nice to be an honor student.
只要  成  績  好
zhǐ yào   chéng   jī   hǎo
as long as completed spin good
Just because you have good marks
就  能  亂  嗆  人
jiù   néng   luàn   qiāng   rén
just can   confusion choke  man
doesn't mean you can boss people around.
誰  稀  罕  管  你  啊
sheí   xī   hǎn   guǎn   nǐ   a
who   rare rare manage you ah
Who cares about what you think?
欸  你  也不  用  太  管  他  啦
āi   nǐ   yě bù   yòng   tài   guǎn   tā   la
sigh you nor    use   very manage he  la
Don't mind him, don't let him bother you.
對  呀
duì   ya
to   yeah
That's right.
他  只是  上  課  愛  打  手  槍  而已  啦
tā   zhǐ shì   shàng   kè   ài   dǎ   shǒu   qiāng   ér yǐ   la
he  just     on     lesson love strike hand  spear  Just now la
He just likes to masturbate in the classroom.
幹
gàn
trunk
Fuck.
你  會  喜歡  作  怪  就是  因為  你  平常  不好  好  唸  書  的  關係
nǐ   huì   xǐ huan   zuò   guài   jiù shì   yīn wèi   nǐ   píng cháng   bù hǎo   hǎo   niàn   shū   de   guān xì
you can  like     make strange That is  because  you usually     not good good recite book of  relationship
The reason you like to goof around is because you don't concentrate on your studies.
對  啊
duì   a
to   ah
Yeah.
你  好  強  喔  你  好  會  讀書  喔
nǐ   hǎo   qiáng   ō   nǐ   hǎo   huì   dú shū   ō
you good strong cry you good can  reading cry
You're so clever, you are such a smart ass.
像  沈  佳  宜  這  種  好  學生
xiàng   chén   jiā   yí   zhè   zhǒng   hǎo   xué shēng
image  sink  good suitable this seed   good student
A nerd like Shen Chia-Yi
逮到  機會  就  喜歡  多管閒事
dǎi dào   jī huì   jiù   xǐ huan   duō guǎn jiān shì
Caught   opportunity just like     busy body
likes to poke her nose into other people's business whenever she gets a chance.
整天  畫  這  種  智  障  的  東西
zhěng tiān   huà   zhè   zhǒng   zhì   zhàng   de   dōng xi
All day     draw this seed   wisdom separate of  thing
All you do is drawing these retarded figures every day.
沒  前途  啦
méi   qián tú   la
not  future   la
Where's the future in that?
要  你  管  啊
yào   nǐ   guǎn   a
need you manage ah
It's none of your business
是  沒有  要  管  啊  只是  想  笑  一下  而已  呀
shì   méi yǒu   yào   guǎn   a   zhǐ shì   xiǎng   xiào   yí xià   ér yǐ   ya
is   No       need manage ah just     think  smile a bit   Just now yeah
I'm pretty much minding my own business. I just want to have a good laugh.
沒  品
méi   pǐn
not  article
Moron.
為什  麼  你  畫  的  智  障  每個  都是  光頭  啊
為什  me   nǐ   huà   de   zhì   zhàng   měi gè   dōu shì   guāng tóu   a
為什 insignificant you draw of  wisdom separate Each one Are all  Bald head  ah
How come every retard you drew is bald?
你  是  歧視  光頭  還  是  歧視  智  障
nǐ   shì   qí shì   guāng tóu   hái   shì   qí shì   zhì   zhàng
you is   Discrimination Bald head  still is   Discrimination wisdom separate
Do you discriminate against bald heads or retards?
管好  你  自己  就  好
guǎn hǎo   nǐ   zì jǐ   jiù   hǎo
Good management you self   just good
Mind your own business.
你  烏  龜  喔
nǐ   wū   guī   ō
you crow cuckold cry
Man, you are as slow as a turtle!
拜  拜
bài   bài
bow  bow
Bye.
柯  騰
kē   téng
stalk fly
Ko-Teng.
柯  騰
kē   téng
stalk fly
Ko-Teng.
啊
a
ah
What?
你  不要  一直  為難  沈  佳  宜
nǐ   bù yào   yī zhí   wéi nán   chén   jiā   yí
you Do not  Always  Embarrassed sink  good suitable
Stop giving Shen Chia-Yi a hard time.
媽  啦
mā   la
mother la
Yeah right.
就  這樣
jiù   zhè yàng
just such
That's all.
還  這樣  咧
hái   zhè yàng   liě
still such      grimace
That's all???
每個  男人  都  想要  成為  最強  的  男人
měi gè   nán rén   dōu   xiǎng yào   chéng wéi   zuì qiáng   de   nán rén
Each one man      all  Want to    become     strongest  of  man
Every man wants to be the strongest man.
我  也不  例外
wǒ   yě bù   lì wài
I   nor    exception
Including me.
總有  一天
zǒng yǒu   yī tiān
always    one day
One day
我  一定  要  成為  跟  師  父  一樣  強  的  男人
wǒ   yī dìng   yào   chéng wéi   gēn   shī   fù   yī yàng   qiáng   de   nán rén
I   for sure need become     with teacher father same     strong of  man
I will be as strong as my master.
你  已經  死了
nǐ   yǐ jīng   sǐ le
you already  died
You are D.E.A.D.
我  的  個  性  之所以  這麼  豪  邁  跟  我  的  家人  大有  關係
wǒ   de   ge   xìng   zhī suǒ yǐ   zhè me   háo   mài   gēn   wǒ   de   jiā rén   dà yǒu   guān xì
I   of  piece nature reason why  so      brave step with I   of  family   Great   relationship
The fact that I am so reckless has got something to do with my family.
媽  洗  髮  精  沒了
mā   xǐ   fà   jīng   méi liǎo
mother wash hair essence Gone
Ma, shampoo is out.
唉  唷  穿衣  服  啦
āi   yo   chuān yī   fú   la
alas yō  dressing  clothes la
Hey, put some clothes on.
都  這麼  大  了
dōu   zhè me   dà   le
all  so      big is
You're a grown-up now
真的  很大  吼
zhēn de   hěn dà   hǒu
Really   Very big roar
I know, it has grown so big, right?
我  老爸  在家  裡  也是  脫  褲  懶
wǒ   lǎo bà   zài jiā   lǐ   yě shì   tuō   kù   lǎn
I   Daddy   At home  inside Also too strip trousers lazy
My father also likes to walk around butt naked in the house.
今天  學校  有  打  電話  來
jīn tiān   學校  yǒu   dǎ   電話  lái
today     學校 have strike 電話 come
The school called today.
男女  合  校  就  男女  合  校
nán nǚ   hé   xiào   jiù   nán nǚ   hé   xiào
men and women combine school just men and women combine school
What's the big deal about coed school?
在  學校  就  專心  讀書
zài   學校  jiù   zhuān xīn   dú shū
in   學校 just concentrate reading
Concentrate at school.
不要  搞  一些  有  的  沒  的  嘛
bù yào   gǎo   yī xiē   yǒu   de   méi   de   ma
Do not  clear some    have of  not  of  ma
Stop goofing around.
搞  什麼
gǎo   shén me
clear what
What did I do?
趁  熱  吃  趁  熱  吃
chèn   rè   chī   chèn   rè   chī
rip off hot eat  rip off hot eat
Eat first, while it's still hot.
吃完  再說  啦
chī wán   zài shuō   la
Finished eating Say again la
Talk later.
你  成  績  一直  都  吊  車  尾  是  不是  都  不  讀書
nǐ   chéng   jī   yī zhí   dōu   diào   chē   wěi   shì   bù shì   dōu   bù   dú shū
you completed spin Always  all  condole cart tail is   not     all  no  reading
Why are your grades always in the bottom percentile?
整天  只想  搞  一些  談  情  說  愛  的  事
zhěng tiān   zhǐ xiǎng   gǎo   yī xiē   tán   qíng   shuō   ài   de   shì
All day     Just want to clear some    talk feeling speak love of  thing
Is it because you are thinking about girls all the time, is that why?
我  對  女生  沒  興趣  啦
wǒ   duì   nǚ shēng   méi   興趣  la
I   to   Girls     not  興趣 la
No, I am not interested in girls!
我  對  男  生  也沒  興趣  啊
wǒ   duì   nán   shēng   yě méi   興趣  a
I   to   male life   also not 興趣 ah
I'm not interested in guys, either.
說到  談  情  說  愛
shuō dào   tán   qíng   shuō   ài
Speaking of talk feeling speak love
Speaking of girls.
我  那些  好  朋友
wǒ   nà xiē   hǎo   péng yǒu
I   those   good friend
Each one of my good friend
每個人  喜歡  沈  佳  宜  的  方式  都  不  一樣
měi gè rén   xǐ huan   chén   jiā   yí   de   fāng shì   dōu   bù   yī yàng
everyone    like     sink  good suitable of  way       all  no  same
liked Shen Chia-Yi in a different way.
廖  該  邊  你  想  幹  嘛
liào   gāi   biān   nǐ   xiǎng   gàn   ma
surname should side  you think  trunk ma
Groin, what are you doing?
沈  佳  宜
chén   jiā   yí
sink  good suitable
Shen Chia-Yi
我  剛剛  發明  了  一個  新  魔  術
wǒ   gāng gāng   發明  le   yī gè   xīn   mó   shù
I   just       發明 is  One    new  demon art
I have just invented a new magic trick
第一  個  變  給  你  看
dì yī   ge   biàn   gěi   nǐ   kàn
first  piece change give you look
I want you to be the first one to see it.
胡  家  瑋  你  要  不要  順便  也看  一下
hú   jiā   wěi   nǐ   yào   bù yào   shùn biàn   yě kàn   yí xià
recklessly house rare you need Do not  By the way See also a bit
Hu Chia-Wei, do you want to see it, too.
搞  笑  的  嗎
gǎo   xiào   de   ma
clear smile of  ?
Is it a prank?
哪  是  啊  是  很  厲害  的
nǎ   shì   a   shì   hěn   lì hài   de
where is   ah is   very Powerful of
No way. It's amazing.
看清楚  喔
kàn qīng chu   ō
See clearly   cry
Look closely.
該  邊  的  方法  基本  上  沒錯
gāi   biān   de   fāng fǎ   jī běn   shàng   méi cuò
should side  of  method   Basic   on     That's right
Basically, Groin was on the right track.
就是  逗  女孩  子  開心
jiù shì   dòu   nǚ hái   zi   kāi xīn
That is  tempt girl    offspring Happy
It's to cheer the girls up and make them laugh.
這  隻手  也沒有
zhè   zhī shǒu   yě méi yǒu
this Hand only nor
Nothing in this hand, either.
看清楚  喔
kàn qīng chu   ō
See clearly   cry
Look closely.
廖  該  邊  你  很  無聊
liào   gāi   biān   nǐ   hěn   wú liáo
surname should side  you very bored
Groin, you are such a bore.
比起  該  邊  的  弱  智  魔  術
bǐ qǐ   gāi   biān   de   ruò   zhì   mó   shù
Compared to should side  of  weak wisdom demon art
Besides Groin's retarded magic.
老  曹  討  女生  開心  的  方式  …
lǎo   cáo   tǎo   nǚ shēng   kāi xīn   de   fāng shì   …
old  surname beg  Girls     Happy    of  way       …
Tsao had a very different way to make girls happy.
沈  佳  宜
chén   jiā   yí
sink  good suitable
Shen Chia-Yi.
曹  國  勝
cáo   guó   shèng
surname nation victory
Tsao Kuo-Sheng.
沒人  理解
méi rén   lǐ jiě
no one   understanding
And no one gets it.
阿  和  很  喜歡  看  一些  大人  在  看  的  雜誌
ā   hàn   hěn   xǐ huan   kàn   yī xiē   dà rén   zài   kàn   de   雜誌
a  and  very like     look some    grown ups in   look of  雜誌
A-Ho liked to read what grown-ups read.
對  很多  我  不想  懂  的  事  都  非常  瞭解
duì   hěn duō   wǒ   bù xiǎng   dǒng   de   shì   dōu   fēi cháng   liǎo jiě
to   a lot of I   Do not want to understand of  thing all  very much  To understanding
So he knew many things that we didn't.
沈  佳  宜
chén   jiā   yí
sink  good suitable
Shen Chia-Yi.
你  記  不  記得  我  之前  有  借  你  一張  Air  Supply  的  專輯
nǐ   jì   bù   jì de   wǒ   zhī qián   yǒu   jiè   nǐ   yī zhāng   Air  Supply  de   專輯
you record no  remember I   prior to  have borrow you One       Air Supply of  專輯
Do you remember the Air Supply album that I lent you.
嗯
n
ń
Um... I remember.
下  個月  他們  要  來  開  演唱會
xià   gè yuè   tā men   yào   lái   kāi   演唱會
under month   they    need come open 演唱會
They are coming next month.
如果  我  拿到  票  要  不要  一起去
rú guǒ   wǒ   ná dào   piào   yào   bù yào   yī qǐ qù
in case I   Get it  ticket need Do not  go together
Do you want to go if I have tickets?
去  台北  看  嗎
qù   tái běi   kàn   ma
go  Taipei   look ?
To Taipei?
坐  火車  去  啊
zuò   huǒ chē   qù   a
sit  train    go  ah
We can take the train.
胡  家  瑋
hú   jiā   wěi
recklessly house rare
Hu Chia-Wei.
要  不要  一起去
yào   bù yào   yī qǐ qù
need Do not  go together
Do you want to go with us?
好啊  …
hǎo a   …
Okay   …
Yes, sure.
聽起來  很有  趣  耶
tīng qǐ lái   hěn yǒu   qù   yé
sound        Very much attraction ye
Sounds fun.
用  大人  的  方式  追  沈  佳  宜  最不  著  痕跡
yòng   dà rén   de   fāng shì   zhuī   chén   jiā   yí   zuì bù   jiáo   hén jī
use   grown ups of  way       pursue sink  good suitable Least   manifest trace
The adult's way is the most subtle way to chase after Shen Chia-Yi.
Air  Supply  是  誰  啊
Air  Supply  shì   sheí   a
Air Supply is   who   ah
Who is Air Supply?
有  人說
yǒu   人說
have 人說
Someone said.
展現  自己  最  笨拙  的  一面  也是  追求  女孩  的  一種  方式
zhǎn xiàn   zì jǐ   zuì   bèn zhuō   de   yī miàn   yě shì   zhuī qiú   nǚ hái   de   yī zhǒng   fāng shì
Show       self   most clumsy    of  one side Also too pursue    girl    of  One kind  way
Showing one's clumsy side is also another way to pursuit girls
我  想
wǒ   xiǎng
I   think
I think.
勃  起  充分  驗證  了  這個  方式  …
bó   qǐ   chōng fèn   yàn zhèng   le   zhè ge   fāng shì   …
suddenly onward full       verification is  This one way       …
Boner has tried this many times.
許  博  淳
xǔ   bó   chún
allow gamble honest
Hsu Bo-Chun.
你  可不可以  不要  再  吹了  啊
nǐ   kě bù kě yǐ   bù yào   zài   chuī le   a
you can we       Do not  again Blow     ah
Can you stop playing?
並不  管  用
bìng bù   guǎn   yòng
And not  manage use
And it proves that his way doesn't work at all.
我  也有  喜歡  的  女生
wǒ   yě yǒu   xǐ huan   de   nǚ shēng
I   There are also like     of  Girls
Me? Yes, there's also a girl I like.
只是  我們  之間  暫時  不可能
zhǐ shì   wǒ men   zhī jiān   zhàn shí   bù kěn éng
just     us      between   temporarily impossible
But it's unlikely that we can develop anything at that point in time.
沒  關係
méi   guān xì
not  relationship
That's fine
我  會  慢慢  長大
wǒ   huì   màn man   zhǎng dà
I   can  Slowly   grow up
I will grow up.
成為  一個  配得  上  她  的  男人
chéng wéi   yī gè   pèi de   shàng   tā   de   nán rén
become     One    worthy  on     she of  man
One clay, I will turn to be the man that deserves her.
那一  天
nà yī   tiān
That one day
That day.
英  文  老師  不曉得  是  股  票  輸  錢
yīng   wén   lǎo shī   bù xiǎo de   shì   gǔ   piào   shū   qián
petal literature teacher  do not know is   thighs ticket transport money
Nobody knew if the English teacher had lost money in the stock market
還  是  月  經  亂  掉
hái   shì   yuè   jīng   luàn   diào
still is   moon through confusion turn
or her menstruation period went wild.
整  張  臉  跟  大  便  一樣  臭
zhěng   zhāng   liǎn   gēn   dà   biàn   yī yàng   chòu
orderly stretch face  with big then  same     smell
She had a shitty face.
散發  出  比  平常  更重  的  殺  氣
sàn fà   chū   bǐ   píng cháng   gèng zhòng   de   shā   qì
Distributed leave liken usually     heavier     of  kill air
She looked like she was about to kill someone.
起立
qǐ lì
stand up
Stand up.
坐下  上  課
zuò xià   shàng   kè
sit down on     lesson
Sit down. Let's begin
原本  我  以為
yuán běn   wǒ   yǐ wéi
original  I   think
I thought
如果有  一天  能夠  看到  品  學  兼  優  的  沈  佳  宜  出  糗
rú guǒ yǒu   yī tiān   néng gòu   kàn dào   pǐn   xué   jiān   yōu   de   chén   jiā   yí   chū   qiǔ
If there is one day  were able see      article learning unite superior of  sink  good suitable leave embarrassing
it would be great fun to see the smart ass student, Shen Chia-Yi
一定  是  上  學  最大  的  樂趣
yī dìng   shì   shàng   xué   zuì dà   de   lè qù
for sure is   on     learning maximum of  pleasure
makes a blunder
我  是說
wǒ   是說
I   是說
I meant.
原本
yuán běn
original
"I thought."
沒  帶  課本  的  站起來
méi   dài   課本  de   zhàn qǐ lái
not  take 課本 of  stand up
Stand up if you didn't bring your textbook.
柯  景  騰
kē   jǐng   téng
stalk scenery fly
Ko Ching-Teng
學  期  已經  過了  三分之一  了
xué   qí   yǐ jīng   guò le   sān fēn zhī yī   le
learning date already  pass    one third       is
we have gone through a third of this semester.
每天  要  用  的  英  文  課本  你  都  沒  帶
měi tiān   yào   yòng   de   yīng   wén   課本  nǐ   dōu   méi   dài
every day need use   of  petal literature 課本 you all  not  take
And you don't even have your English textbook with you, which we use every day.
你  有  沒有  心  上  課  啊
nǐ   yǒu   méi yǒu   xīn   shàng   kè   a
you have No       heart on     lesson ah
Are you serious about getting an education?
椅子
yǐ zi
chair
Chair.
你  知道  私  立  學校  的  學  費  很  貴  嗎
nǐ   zhī dào   sī   lì   學校  de   xué   fèi   hěn   guì   ma
you know     private stand 學校 of  learning expenses very expensive ?
Don't you know private schools are expensive?
連  最  基本  的  課本  都  不帶
lián   zuì   jī běn   de   課本  dōu   bù dài
join  most Basic   of  課本 all  Without
If you don't even have your textbook
你  來  學校  幹  嘛
nǐ   lái   學校  gàn   ma
you come 學校 trunk ma
then why do you even bother coming to school?
來  吃  便  當  啊
lái   chī   biàn   dāng   a
come eat  then  that  ah
Here to eat your lunchbox?
便  當  本來  就  要  吃  啊
biàn   dāng   běn lái   jiù   yào   chī   a
then  that  originally just need eat  ah
Lunch is essential! Of course I have to eat it.
你  還  蠻  會  開玩笑  的  嘛
nǐ   hái   mán   huì   kāi wán xiào   de   ma
you still barbarians can  joke          of  ma
You think you're very funny, huh?
你  到底有  沒有  羞恥  心  啊
nǐ   dào dǐ yǒu   méi yǒu   xiū chǐ   xīn   a
you In the end there is No       shame    heart ah
Have you no shame?
手  舉  高  一點
shǒu   jǔ   gāo   yī diǎn
hand  raise high a little
Raise your arms higher.
再  高  一點
zài   gāo   yī diǎn
again high a little
Raise them higher.
你  是  沒  吃飯  是  不是
nǐ   shì   méi   chī fàn   shì   bù shì
you is   not  eat      is   not
So weak! Didn't you eat?
出去  外面  跳  十  圈  再  進來
chū qù   wài miàn   tiào   shí   quān   zài   jìn lái
Go out  outside   jump  ten  corral again Come in
Go do 10 rounds of squat jumps outside.
我  有  叫  你  放下  來  嗎
wǒ   yǒu   jiào   nǐ   fàng xià   lái   ma
I   have call  you lay down  come ?
Did I ask you to put your hands down?
舉  高
jǔ   gāo
raise high
Higher!
I say to you today
my friends
that in spite of the difficulties and frustrations of the moment
I still have a dream
I still have a dream.
It is a dream deeply rooted in the American dream
I have a dream
that one day this nation will rise up.
沈  佳  宜  如果  不是  那麼  假  正  經  其實  還  滿  可愛  的
chén   jiā   yí   rú guǒ   bù shì   nà me   jiǎ   zhèng   jīng   qí shí   hái   mǎn   kě ài   de
sink  good suitable in case not     like that falsehood right  through in fact still fill lovely of
(Shen Chia-Yi would be kind of cute if she wasn't such a prude)
and live up the true meaning of its dream.
你  在  想  什麼  啊
nǐ   zài   xiǎng   shén me   a
you in   think  what     ah
What are you thinking?
一  整天  都  怪  怪  的
yī   zhěng tiān   dōu   guài   guài   de
one All day     all  strange strange of
You've been weird all day long.
沒有  啊
méi yǒu   a
No       ah
Nothing.
要  不要  帶  你  去  收  驚  啊
yào   bù yào   dài   nǐ   qù   shōu   jīng   a
need Do not  take you go  collect frighten ah
Do you need an exorcism?
你  想  太多  了
nǐ   xiǎng   tài duō   le
you think  too much is
You are thinking too much.
訓  導  處  報告
xùn   dǎo   chù   bào gào
teach direct place report
Head office announcement
三年  二  班  周  傑  倫
sān nián   èr   bān   zhōu   jié   lún
Three years two class circumference hero relationships
Jay Chou in third year
馬上  到  訓  導  處  來
mǎ shàng   dào   xùn   dǎo   chù   lái
immediately arrive teach direct place come
please come to the head office now.
哎  唷  屌  哦
ai   yo   diao   ó
āi  yō  diǎo  Oh
Sweet.
幹  嘛  啊
gàn   ma   a
trunk ma  ah
What?
昨天  謝謝
zuó tiān   xiè xiè
yesterday Thank you
Thank you for yesterday.
沒  差  反正  我  臉  皮  厚
méi   chà   fǎn zhèng   wǒ   liǎn   pí   hòu
not  different Anyway     I   face  skin thick
No big deal. I have no shame anyway.
謝謝
xiè xiè
Thank you
Thank you.
我  看  你  乾脆  請  我  喝  飲料  好了
wǒ   kàn   nǐ   gān cuì   qǐng   wǒ   hē   yǐn liào   hǎo le
I   look you simply   ask   I   drink Drink     All right
Why not just buy me a drink?
不然  一直  聽  你  說  謝謝  很  奇怪
bù rán   yī zhí   tīng   nǐ   shuō   xiè xiè   hěn   qí guài
otherwise Always  hear  you speak Thank you very strange
It's weird to hear you keep on saying "thank you".
我  可以  問你  一個  問題  嗎
wǒ   kě yǐ   wèn nǐ   yī gè   wèn tí   ma
I   can    ask you One    problem ?
Can I ask you a question?
問  啊
wèn   a
ask  ah
Go ahead.
你  幹  嘛  不  讀書
nǐ   gàn   ma   bù   dú shū
you trunk ma  no  reading
Why don't you want to study?
沒有  不  讀  啊
méi yǒu   bù   dú   a
No       no  read ah
It's not like I don't want to
要是  我  認真  唸  書  起來
yào shi   wǒ   rèn zhēn   niàn   shū   qǐ lái
if       I   serious   recite book stand up
I am afraid if I really tried
實  力  強  到  連  我  自己  都  會  害怕
shí   lì   qiáng   dào   lián   wǒ   zì jǐ   dōu   huì   hài pà
real power strong arrive join  I   self   all  can  Afraid
I would be so good that I would even scare myself.
小心  我  一  唸  書
xiǎo xīn   wǒ   yī   niàn   shū
Be careful I   one recite book
You better watch out then if I do study
立刻  就  把  妳  幹  掉
lì kè   jiù   bǎ   nai   gàn   diào
Immediately just take nǎi  trunk turn
I would beat you immediately.
挑  一下  啊
tiāo   yí xià   a
carry a bit   ah
Wanna take up the challenge?
怕  你  喔
pà   nǐ   ō
fear you cry
Sure, why not.
柯  景  騰
kē   jǐng   téng
stalk scenery fly
Ko Ching-Teng.
幹  嘛
gàn   ma
trunk ma
What?
這  是  我  自己  出  的  考  卷
zhè   shì   wǒ   zì jǐ   chū   de   kǎo   juǎn
this is   I   self   leave of  examine scroll
This is a quiz I made up myself.
你  拿  回家  寫
nǐ   ná   huí jiā   xiě
you take Return home write
Take it and do it at home.
明天  帶來  給  我  改
míng tiān   dài lái   gěi   wǒ   gǎi
tomorrow   bring    give I   change
Bring it back tomorrow.
真的  假  的  啦
zhēn de   jiǎ   de   la
Really   falsehood of  la
Are you for real?
還  愛心  考  卷
hái   ài xīn   kǎo   juǎn
still Love    examine scroll
A quiz made out of love.
還有  這  本  數  學  參  考  書
hái yǒu   zhè   běn   shù   xué   cān   kǎo   shū
and also this root number learning intervene examine book
And here is a math exercise book.
我  用  黃色  螢  光  筆  劃  下來  的  地方  算  三  遍
wǒ   yòng   huáng sè   yíng   guāng   bǐ   huà   xià lái   de   dì fāng   suàn   sān   biàn
I   use   yellow    glow-worm light  write divide Down     of  place    count three everywhere
See the questions I've highlighted in yellow? Do them three times.
下次  小  考  應該  就  有  五十  分  了
xià cì   xiǎo   kǎo   yīng gāi   jiù   yǒu   wǔ shí   fēn   le
Next time small examine should    just have fifty   divide is
You will probably score at least 50% in the next quiz.
才  五十
cái   wǔ shí
talent fifty
Only 50%
我  沒說  考  好  成  績  很  容易  呀
wǒ   méi shuō   kǎo   hǎo   chéng   jī   hěn   róng yì   ya
I   Did not say examine good completed spin very easy     yeah
I didn't say it's easy to get good grades
算  完了  基本  題
suàn   wán liǎo   jī běn   tí
count Finished it Basic   forehead
I will give you some harder problems
我  再出  難  一點  的  給  你
wǒ   zài chū   nán   yī diǎn   de   gěi   nǐ
I   And then out difficult a little of  give you
after you finish the basics.
欠  你  錢  喔
qiàn   nǐ   qián   ō
owe   you money cry
What do I owe you?
我  幹  嘛  聽  你的
wǒ   gàn   ma   tīng   nǐ de
I   trunk ma  hear  your
Why should I listen to you?
因為  我  不想  瞧不起  你
yīn wèi   wǒ   bù xiǎng   qiáo bù qǐ   nǐ
because  I   Do not want to look down   you
Because I don't want to look down on you.
媽  啦
mā   la
mother la
Yeah right!
成  績  好  就  可以  瞧不起  人
chéng   jī   hǎo   jiù   kě yǐ   qiáo bù qǐ   rén
completed spin good just can    look down   man
You can be so stuck up just because you have good grades.
那  你  繼續  好了  我  又  沒  差
nà   nǐ   jì xù   hǎo le   wǒ   yòu   méi   chà
that you carry on All right I   and  not  different
Go on then, I don't really care
我  瞧不起  的  不是  成  績  不好  的  人
wǒ   qiáo bù qǐ   de   bù shì   chéng   jī   bù hǎo   de   rén
I   look down   of  not     completed spin not good of  man
I don't look down on people with bad grades
我  瞧不起  的
wǒ   qiáo bù qǐ   de
I   look down   of
I look down on you because
是  一個  明明  自己  不  努力  唸  書
shì   yī gè   míng míng   zì jǐ   bù   nǔ lì   niàn   shū
is   One    Obviously  self   no  Effort recite book
you pick on people with good grades
卻  只會  瞧不起  用  功  唸  書  的  人
què   zhǐ huì   qiáo bù qǐ   yòng   gōng   niàn   shū   de   rén
still Only will look down   use   achievement recite book of  man
while you don't even try to work hard.
穿衣  服  啦
chuān yī   fú   la
dressing  clothes la
Put on some clothes.
不然  會  感  冒
bù rán   huì   gǎn   mào
otherwise can  feel risk
Otherwise you'll catch a cold.
哪有  可能
nǎ yǒu   kě néng
How can there be may
That's impossible.
我  師  父  是  李  小  龍  耶
wǒ   shī   fù   shì   lǐ   xiǎo   lóng   yé
I   teacher father is   plum small dragon ye
My master is Bruce Lee.
吞下去  再說
tūn xià qù   zài shuō
Swallow it up Say again
Swallow your food before you speak.
你  衛  生  紙  怎麼  用  那麼  快  啊
nǐ   wèi   shēng   zhǐ   zěn me   yòng   nà me   kuài   a
you guard life   paper how     use   like that rapid ah
Why is our tissue paper running out so fast?
幹  嘛
gàn   ma
trunk ma
What?
考  卷
kǎo   juǎn
examine scroll
Your quiz.
你  錯  很多  耶
nǐ   cuò   hěn duō   yé
you error a lot of ye
You made so many mistakes.
你回去  沒  看  參  考  書  就  直接  寫了  對不對
你回去  méi   kàn   cān   kǎo   shū   jiù   zhí jiē   xiě le   duì bù duì
你回去 not  look intervene examine book just direct   wrote   right
You did the problems without reading the exercise book, didn't you?
這  兩  題  你  可以  從  參  考  書  上  找  解答
zhè   liǎng   tí   nǐ   kě yǐ   cóng   cān   kǎo   shū   shàng   zhǎo   jiě dá
this two    forehead you can    from  intervene examine book on     search answer
You can find the answers for these two problems in the exercise book.
這  一  題  比較  難
zhè   yī   tí   bǐ jiào   nán
this one forehead Comparison difficult
This one is harder.
不是  背  公  式  就  可以  解  的
bù shì   bèi   gōng   shì   jiù   kě yǐ   jiě   de
not     back fair  style just can    loosen of
It's not the kind of problem you can solve with a formula.
需要  用  到  這裡  跟  這裡  的  概  念
xū yào   yòng   dào   zhè lǐ   gēn   zhè lǐ   de   gài   niàn
need    use   arrive Here    with Here    of  generally recall
You need to use these theories.
我  圈  起來  了  你回去  自己  看
wǒ   quān   qǐ lái   le   你回去  zì jǐ   kàn
I   corral stand up is  你回去 self   look
You go home and read the parts I circled.
唸  書  好  煩
niàn   shū   hǎo   fán
recite book good bother
It's such a pain to study.
所以  會  唸  書  的  人  很  厲害  啊
suǒ yǐ   huì   niàn   shū   de   rén   hěn   lì hài   a
and so  can  recite book of  man  very Powerful ah
That's why people who are good at studying rule.
你  為什  麼  要  盯  柯  景  騰  唸  書  啊
nǐ   為什  me   yào   ding   kē   jǐng   téng   niàn   shū   a
you 為什 insignificant need dīng  stalk scenery fly   recite book ah
Why are you helping Ko Ching-Teng to study?
他  成  績  能  看  嗎
tā   chéng   jī   néng   kàn   ma
he  completed spin can   look ?
Did you see his grades?
也不  干  你的  事  啊
yě bù   gàn   nǐ de   shì   a
nor    oppose your   thing ah
It's none of your business.
真的  很  爛  耶
zhēn de   hěn   làn   yé
Really   very rotten ye
They are really bad.
那  也不  干  你的  事  啊
nà   yě bù   gàn   nǐ de   shì   a
that nor    oppose your   thing ah
Still, it has nothing to do with you.
來  小  姐  這  是  你的  這  是  你的
lái   xiǎo   jiě   zhè   shì   nǐ de   zhè   shì   nǐ de
come small older sister this is   your   this is   your
Miss, this is yours and this is yours.
謝謝  老  闆
xiè xiè   lǎo   bǎn
Thank you old  boss
Thank you!
謝謝
xiè xiè
Thank you
Thank you!
真  不像  你
zhēn   bù xiàng   nǐ
real  Not like  you
It's so not you
我  討厭  什麼  都  不  努力  卻  一點也沒  有  自覺  的  人
wǒ   tǎo yàn   shén me   dōu   bù   nǔ lì   què   yī diǎn yě méi   yǒu   zì jué   de   rén
I   hate     what     all  no  Effort still Not at all      have conscious of  man
I hate people who are lazy and have no sense of self-awareness at all.
喔
ō
cry
Ok
我  又  不是  在  說你
wǒ   yòu   bù shì   zài   shuō nǐ
I   and  not     in   saying you
I'm not talking about you.
沒有  在  說  我  啊
méi yǒu   zài   shuō   wǒ   a
No       in   speak I   ah
You sure?
唸  書  好  無聊  哦
niàn   shū   hǎo   wú liáo   ó
recite book good bored    Oh
It's so boring to study
為什  麼  沈  佳  宜  可以  這樣  每天  唸  書  咧
為什  me   chén   jiā   yí   kě yǐ   zhè yàng   měi tiān   niàn   shū   liě
為什 insignificant sink  good suitable can    such      every day recite book grimace
I don't understand why Shen Chia-Yi can do this every day.
你  說說  看  啊
nǐ   shuō shuō   kàn   a
you Talk about it look ah
Do you have any idea?
我  跟  你  說  哦
wǒ   gēn   nǐ   shuō   ó
I   with you speak Oh
Let me tell you.
這  種  尖  酸  的  題目  就算  解  得出來
zhè   zhǒng   jiān   suān   de   題目  jiù suàn   jiě   得出來
this seed   sharp tart  of  題目 Even if   loosen 得出來
Being able to solve these tricky math questions.
對  人生  還  是  一點  幫助  都  沒有  啦
duì   rén shēng   hái   shì   yī diǎn   bāng zhù   dōu   méi yǒu   la
to   life       still is   a little help      all  No       la
Does nothing good in life!
來
lái
come
Here.
怎麼  那麼  用  功  啊
zěn me   nà me   yòng   gōng   a
how     like that use   achievement ah
Why do you work so hard?
沒有  啊  隨便  念
méi yǒu   a   suí biàn   niàn
No       ah casual    recall
No, I just study when I feel like it.
要  念  就  要  認真  念
yào   niàn   jiù   yào   rèn zhēn   niàn
need recall just need serious   recall
If you want to study, study hard then.
什麼  隨便  念
shén me   suí biàn   niàn
what     casual    recall
What do you mean "when you feel like it"?
好  啦  我  考慮  一下
hǎo   la   wǒ   kǎo lǜ   yí xià
good la  I   consider a bit
Fine, I will think about it.
吃  稀  飯
chī   xī   fàn
eat  rare food
Eat porridge.
省  著  點  用  喔
shěng   jiáo   diǎn   yòng   ō
province manifest dot   use   cry
Don't finish it too quickly.
對了
duì le
correct
By the way
老  闆  前  幾天  剛  進一  批  新  貨  都  沒有  拆
lǎo   bǎn   qián   jǐ tiān   gāng   jìn yī   pī   xīn   huò   dōu   méi yǒu   chāi
old  boss forward A few days hard  Into one comment new  goods all  No       destroy
there was a new shipment in the store a few days ago. The whole package was unopened
可是  他  要  整  盒  賣
kě shì   tā   yào   zhěng   hé   mài
but     he  need orderly casket sell
so the store owner wants to sell the whole thing together.
所以  你們  覺得  要  買  整  盒  的  SKYBOX    還  是  兩  盒  CC  啊
suǒ yǐ   nǐ men   jué de   yào   mǎi   zhěng   hé   de   SKYBOX    hái   shì   liǎng   hé   CC  a
and so  you     feel    need buy  orderly casket of  SKYBOX  still is   two    casket CC ah
Do you think I should buy the whole package of SKYBOX or two boxes of CC?
SKYBOX  太  貴  了
SKYBOX  tài   guì   le
SKYBOX very expensive is
SKYBOX is too expensive.
所以  兩  盒  CC  囉
suǒ yǐ   liǎng   hé   CC  luō
and so  two    casket CC nag
So, two boxes of CC?
你  昨天  是  打  幾  次  啊
nǐ   zuó tiān   shì   dǎ   jǐ   cì   a
you yesterday is   strike some order ah
How many times did you jerk off yesterday?
這麼  想  睡  哦
zhè me   xiǎng   shuì   ó
so      think  sleep Oh
Why are you so tired?
打你  的  頭  啦
dǎ nǐ   de   tóu   la
Beat you of  head la
Jerk off your ass.
你  自己  頭  自己  打  不要  打  我  的  啦
nǐ   zì jǐ   tóu   zì jǐ   dǎ   bù yào   dǎ   wǒ   de   la
you self   head self   strike Do not  strike I   of  la
Mind your own business.
幹
gàn
trunk
Fuck!
起來  吃肉  圓  啦
qǐ lái   chī ròu   yuán   la
stand up Eat meat circle la
Get up and eat your meatballs.
你  不吃  我  把  你  吃掉  喔
nǐ   bù chī   wǒ   bǎ   nǐ   chī diào   ō
you Do not eat I   take you Eat it    cry
If you don't eat it, I'm going to finish yours, too.
沈  佳  宜  你  看  新  魔  術
chén   jiā   yí   nǐ   kàn   xīn   mó   shù
sink  good suitable you look new  demon art
Shen Chia-Yi, check out my new magic.
你  白  癡  耶
nǐ   bái   chī   yé
you white silly ye
You idiot.
該  邊  還不  錯  喔
gāi   biān   hái bù   cuò   ō
should side  Not yet error cry
Not bad!
太  噁  了  啦
tài   ě   le   la
very nastiness is  la
Gross!
他  今年  變  過  最好  的
tā   jīn nián   biàn   guò   zuì hǎo   de
he  this year change pass best     of
It's the best this year.
今年  最好  的  對不對
jīn nián   zuì hǎo   de   duì bù duì
this year best     of  right
Isn't it?
你們  在  幹  嘛
nǐ men   zài   gàn   ma
you     in   trunk ma
What are you guys doing?
新  魔  術  啦
xīn   mó   shù   la
new  demon art  la
It's a new magic.
真的  假  的  我  要  看  我  要  看
zhēn de   jiǎ   de   wǒ   yào   kàn   wǒ   yào   kàn
Really   falsehood of  I   need look I   need look
For real? Show me! Show me!
我  變  一次  給  你  看
wǒ   biàn   yī cì   gěi   nǐ   kàn
I   change once   give you look
I will show you.
超  噁  的
chāo   ě   de
surpass nastiness of
It's gross.
就  假裝  有  喝  其實  沒有
jiù   jiǎ zhuāng   yǒu   hē   qí shí   méi yǒu
just pretend     have drink in fact No
Just pretend that you are drinking, but don't swallow it.
你  很  遜  耶
nǐ   hěn   xùn   yé
you very humble ye
You suck.
你  好  噁  喔  你
nǐ   hǎo   ě   ō   nǐ
you good nastiness cry you
You are so gross.
訂  正
dìng   zhèng
arrange right
Make correction
十分  鐘
shí fēn   zhōng
very     clock
10 minutes.
依  我  的  聰明才智
yī   wǒ   de   cōng míng cái zhì
consent I   of  Ingenuity
Because I am so damn smart
五分  鐘  就  綽  綽  有  餘  了
wǔ fēn   zhōng   jiù   chuò   chuò   yǒu   yú   le
Five points clock  just graceful graceful have surplus is
5 minutes is more than enough.
要  念  出來  念  啦
yào   niàn   chū lái   niàn   la
need recall come out recall la
Don't study in the toilet
恁  母  啊  我  尿  快  要  閃  出來  了  啦
nèn   mǔ   a   wǒ   niào   kuài   yào   shǎn   chū lái   le   la
that mother ah I   urine rapid need flash come out is  la
I am going to pee in my pants.
媽  你  不要  嚇  我  啦
mā   nǐ   bù yào   xià   wǒ   la
mother you Do not  scare I   la
Ma, stop scaring me.
我  嚇  你  幹  嘛  啦
wǒ   xià   nǐ   gàn   ma   la
I   scare you trunk ma  la
Why would I?
棒  棒  咧  緊  出來
bàng   bàng   liě   jǐn   chū lái
stick stick grimace tense come out
Dump it out and come out.
快  啦
kuài   la
rapid la
Hurry up.
這  晚  還不  睏
zhè   wǎn   hái bù   kùn
this night Not yet sleepy
Why are you up so late?
咧  衝  三  小  啊
liě   chōng   sān   xiǎo   a
grimace rush   three small ah
What the hell are you doing in there?
在  念  英  文  啦
zài   niàn   yīng   wén   la
in   recall petal literature la
I am studying English
英  文  以後  用  不  到  啦
yīng   wén   yǐ hòu   yòng   bù   dào   la
petal literature after   use   no  arrive la
English is useless for you
I FUCK YOU
好  睏  啊  啦
hǎo   kùn   a   la
good sleepy ah la
Go to sleep
I sleep late because I study English very hard.
謝  明和
xiè   míng hé
thank Ming and
Hsieh Ming-Ho
八十  七  分
bā shí   qī   fēn
eighty  seven divide
87%
好  不錯  不錯
hǎo   bù cuò   bù cuò
good Yes     Yes
Not bad, not bad.
繼續  努力
jì xù   nǔ lì
carry on Effort
Keep it up
張  家  琪
zhāng   jiā   qi
stretch house qí
Chang Chia-Chi
四十  四  分
sì shí   sì   fēn
forty   four divide
44%
家  琪  要  加  油  喔
jiā   qi   yào   jiā   yóu   ō
house qí  need increase oil  cry
Work harder.
柯  景  騰
kē   jǐng   téng
stalk scenery fly
Ko Ching-Teng
七十  五分
qī shí   wǔ fēn
seventy Five points
75%
最近  有  比較  用  功  喔
zuì jìn   yǒu   bǐ jiào   yòng   gōng   ō
recent   have Comparison use   achievement cry
You have been studying hard lately?
沒有  啦  天才
méi yǒu   la   tiān cái
No       la  genius
Not really, I am a genius.
那  都要  這樣  天才  喔
nà   dōu yào   zhè yàng   tiān cái   ō
that have to  such      genius    cry
Then, be a genius from now on.
好  啦  下  課
hǎo   la   xià   kè
good la  under lesson
Okay, Class dismiss.
記住  下  禮拜  還要  考試  哦
jì zhù   xià   lǐ bài   hái yào   考試  ó
remember under worship But also 考試 Oh
Remember the test next week.
還  天才  啊
hái   tiān cái   a
still genius    ah
Genius?
真  敢  講耶
zhēn   gǎn   jiǎng yē
real  venture Speak yeah
Are you serious?
其實  會  解  這  種  題目  有  什麼  了  不起  的
qí shí   huì   jiě   zhè   zhǒng   題目  yǒu   shén me   le   bù qǐ   de
in fact can  loosen this seed   題目 have what     is  Can not afford to of
It's not a big deal that you know how to solve these problems
我  敢  跟  妳  賭
wǒ   gǎn   gēn   nai   dǔ
I   venture with nǎi  bet
I bet you
十年  後  我  連  Log  是  什麼  都  不知道
shí nián   hòu   wǒ   lián   Log  shì   shén me   dōu   bù zhī dào
ten years after I   join  Log is   what     all  do not know
in 10 years time, I wouldn't even know what log is
還  是  可以  活得  好好  的
hái   shì   kě yǐ   huó de   hǎo hǎo   de
still is   can    Live to live Well     of
and it makes no difference to my life.
嗯
n
ń
Emmmm...
妳  不  相信
nai   bù   xiāng xìn
nǎi  no  Believe
You don't believe me?
我  相信  啊
wǒ   xiāng xìn   a
I   Believe    ah
I do.
相信  妳  還  那麼  用  功  讀書
xiāng xìn   nai   hái   nà me   yòng   gōng   dú shū
Believe    nǎi  still like that use   achievement reading
Then, why do you still work so hard?
人生  本來  就  有  很多  事  是  徒勞無功  的  啊
rén shēng   běn lái   jiù   yǒu   hěn duō   shì   shì   tú láo wú gōng   de   a
life       originally just have a lot of thing is   Futile          of  ah
You don't expect returns from everything you do.
妳  真的  很  喜歡  學  大人  講道  理  耶
nai   zhēn de   hěn   xǐ huan   xué   dà rén   jiǎng dào   lǐ   yé
nǎi  Really   very like     learning grown ups sermon     reason ye
You really like to pitch high notes like adults, don't you?
像  你  這麼  幼稚  對  你的  人生  一點  幫助  也沒有
xiàng   nǐ   zhè me   yòu zhì   duì   nǐ de   rén shēng   yī diǎn   bāng zhù   yě méi yǒu
image  you so      naive    to   your   life       a little help      nor
It will be no help to your life whatsoever if you continue to be so childish like this.
妳  又  沒  做  過
nai   yòu   méi   zuò   guò
nǎi  and  not  work pass
How would you know
妳  怎麼  知道
nai   zěn me   zhī dào
nǎi  how     know
if you've never been childish ever?
很多  事  不用  做  就  知道  沒有  意義  啊
hěn duō   shì   bù yòng   zuò   jiù   zhī dào   méi yǒu   yì yì   a
a lot of thing No need to work just know     No       meaning ah
You know something is meaningless without trying it.
爛  斃  了
làn   bì   le
rotten kill is
This is shit.
來  下  一  隊
lái   xià   yī   duì
come under one team
Next group
聽說  被  殭  屍  咬  到  也會  變  殭  屍
tīng shuō   bèi   jiang   shī   yǎo   dào   yě huì   biàn   jiang   shī
heard      by   jiāng  corpse bite arrive Will also be change jiāng  corpse
I heard you will become a zombie if you are bitten by one
我  不  相信  這  件事
wǒ   bù   xiāng xìn   zhè   jiàn shì
I   no  Believe    this Something
I don't buy that.
這  件事  一定  是  假  的  啊
zhè   jiàn shì   yī dìng   shì   jiǎ   de   a
this Something for sure is   falsehood of  ah
This must be some rumors.
可是  我  覺得  一定  是有  個  依  據  他  才會  講
kě shì   wǒ   jué de   yī dìng   shì yǒu   ge   yī   jù   tā   cái huì   jiǎng
but     I   feel    for sure there is piece consent occupy he  Will only explain
But he had to learn this from somewhere, right?
怎麼辦
zěn me bàn
How to do
What are we going to do?
喂
wèi
hey
Hey.
幹  嘛
gàn   ma
trunk ma
What?
你  有  沒有  聽到  大家  最近  都  在  聊  的  傳說  啊
nǐ   yǒu   méi yǒu   tīng dào   dà jiā   zuì jìn   dōu   zài   liáo   de   chuán shuō   a
you have No       Hear it   everyone recent   all  in   somewhat of  legend      ah
Have you heard that rumor lately?
我  很  帥  這  件事  已經  變  傳說  囉
wǒ   hěn   shuài   zhè   jiàn shì   yǐ jīng   biàn   chuán shuō   luō
I   very commander this Something already  change legend      nag
You mean the one that every girl wants to date me?
白  癡
bái   chī
white silly
Moron.
好  啦  幹  嘛
hǎo   la   gàn   ma
good la  trunk ma
Okay, what is it?
聽說  有  一批  大陸  偷  渡  客  偷  渡  到一  半  就  淹死  了
tīng shuō   yǒu   yī pī   dà lù   tōu   dù   kè   tōu   dù   dào yī   bàn   jiù   yān sǐ   le
heard      have Batch  mainland burglar cross guest burglar cross To one  half just Drowned is
I heard some stowaways from China were drowned.
屍體  被  衝  上岸  後
shī tǐ   bèi   chōng   shàng àn   hòu
Corpse  by   rush   Ashore    after
And they had became zombies
都  變成  殭  屍  了  耶
dōu   biàn chéng   jiang   shī   le   yé
all  become      jiāng  corpse is  ye
after their bodies were washed up on shore.
喔  你  說  那  群  殭  屍  喔
ō   nǐ   shuō   nà   qún   jiang   shī   ō
cry you speak that crowd jiāng  corpse cry
Oh! Those zombies
我  知道  啊
wǒ   zhī dào   a
I   know     ah
I've heard about them.
他們  就  沿路  一直  跳  一直  跳  一直  跳
tā men   jiù   yán lù   yī zhí   tiào   yī zhí   tiào   yī zhí   tiào
they    just Along the way Always  jump  Always  jump  Always  jump
They jumped, jumped and jumped all the way here.
媽  啦
mā   la
mother la
Shit.
那是  真的  嗎
nà shì   zhēn de   ma
That is Really   ?
Are you for real?
廢話
fèi huà
nonsense
Of course.
一堆  人  晚上  不  睡覺  在  山  上  跳跳  跳
yī duī   rén   wǎn shàng   bù   shuì jiào   zài   shān   shàng   tiào tiào   tiào
pile    man  at night   no  go to bed  in   mountain on     Jumping    jump
With whole bunch of people jumping around up in the hills at night
不是  殭  屍  是  什麼
bù shì   jiang   shī   shì   shén me
not     jiāng  corpse is   what
what do you think they are?
我  記得  前  幾天  報紙  也有  寫  吧
wǒ   jì de   qián   jǐ tiān   報紙  yě yǒu   xiě   ba
I   remember forward A few days 報紙 There are also write !
Yes, I remember seeing that on the newspaper a few days ago.
如果  他們  努力  一點  的話
rú guǒ   tā men   nǔ lì   yī diǎn   de huà
in case they    Effort a little if
If they jumped harder
現在  應該  已經  跳到  八  卦  山  了
xiàn zài   yīng gāi   yǐ jīng   tiào dào   bā   guà   shān   le
now       should    already  Jump to   eight fortune mountain is
they should have reached Baguashan Mountain by now.
怎樣  要  去  看  嗎
zěn yàng   yào   qù   kàn   ma
how       need go  look ?
So, do you want to see them?
誰  要  去  看  啊
sheí   yào   qù   kàn   a
who   need go  look ah
No way
可是  就算  是  真的  要  看  也看  不  到  吧
kě shì   jiù suàn   shì   zhēn de   yào   kàn   yě kàn   bù   dào   ba
but     Even if   is   Really   need look See also no  arrive !
I don't think you can see them even if they are real.
說不定  他們  在  八  卦  山  上  迷  了  路
shuō bu dìng   tā men   zài   bā   guà   shān   shàng   mí   le   lù
maybe         they    in   eight fortune mountain on     bewitch is  road
Maybe they got lost in Baguashan Mountain
就  直接  跳進  彰  化  市  區  了  啊
jiù   zhí jiē   tiào jìn   zhāng   huà   shì   qū   le   a
just direct   jump into clear  change market area is  ah
and jumped directly into Changhua city.
別說  不可能
bié shuō   bù kěn éng
Do not say impossible
Don't think it's impossible.
殭  屍  又  沒有  方向  感
jiang   shī   yòu   méi yǒu   fāng xiàng   gǎn
jiāng  corpse and  No       direction   feel
Zombies don't have a sense of direction.
幹  嘛
gàn   ma
trunk ma
What?
你  最近  跟  沈  佳  宜  好像  很有  話  聊
nǐ   zuì jìn   gēn   chén   jiā   yí   hǎo xiàng   hěn yǒu   huà   liáo
you recent   with sink  good suitable like       Very much speech somewhat
You and Shen Chia-Yi seem to have a lot to talk about lately.
幫  我  一個  忙
bāng   wǒ   yī gè   máng
assist I   One    busy
Do me a favor.
該  不會  是
gāi   bù huì   shì
should will not is
No way.
寫  情書  這  種  爛  梗  吧
xiě   情書  zhè   zhǒng   làn   geng   ba
write 情書 this seed   rotten gěng  !
Don't tell me you want to write a love letter?
你  寫好
nǐ   xiě hǎo
you Write well
You write it
我  照  抄
wǒ   zhào   chāo
I   shine copy
and I copy it
可是  一  瓶  飲料  好像  不夠  耶
kě shì   yī   píng   yǐn liào   hǎo xiàng   bù gòu   yé
but     one jug   Drink     like       not enough ye
I don't think one drink is enough
幫  我  告  白  成功  的話
bāng   wǒ   gào   bái   chéng gōng   de huà
assist I   tell white success     if
if she says yes
我  請  你  一年  份
wǒ   qǐng   nǐ   yī nián   fèn
I   ask   you A year   portion
I will buy you one year worth.
加  一張  Grant  Hill  100:  1  明星  賽  球  員  卡
jiā   yī zhāng   Grant  Hill  100:  1  míng xīng   sài   qiú   yuán   kǎ
increase One       Grant Hill 100: 1 Celebrity  compete ball member card
Plus a Grant Hill 100:1 All-Star Card.
好  一言為定
hǎo   yī yán wéi dìng
good Make a statement
Alright, deal.
柯  景  騰
kē   jǐng   téng
stalk scenery fly
Ko Ching-Teng.
你  晚上  有  沒有  要  補  習
nǐ   wǎn shàng   yǒu   méi yǒu   yào   bǔ   xí
you at night   have No       need mend practice
Are you going to cram school tonight?
補  個  屁  呀
bǔ   ge   pì   ya
mend piece fart yeah
What for?
你  這麼  笨  還不  補  習
nǐ   zhè me   bèn   hái bù   bǔ   xí
you so      foolish Not yet mend practice
You are so dumb, how can you not go!
你  管  我
nǐ   guǎn   wǒ
you manage I
Mind your own business.
今天  晚上  開始
jīn tiān   wǎn shàng   kāi shǐ
today     at night   Start
Starting tonight
你  留  在  學校  唸  書
nǐ   liú   zài   學校  niàn   shū
you stop in   學校 recite book
you stay here and study after school.
晚上  留  校
wǎn shàng   liú   xiào
at night   stop school
Stay at school?
有  沒有  搞  錯  啊
yǒu   méi yǒu   gǎo   cuò   a
have No       clear error ah
What's your problem?
我  也會  留  啊
wǒ   yě huì   liú   a
I   Will also be stop ah
I will stay, too.
哪  招  啊
nǎ   zhāo   a
where beckon ah
What the hell?
原來  沈  佳  宜  只要  沒有  補  習
yuán lái   chén   jiā   yí   zhǐ yào   méi yǒu   bǔ   xí
original  sink  good suitable as long as No       mend practice
It turned out that Shen Chia-Yi stayed behind to study
都  會  一個人  留  在  學校  唸  書
dōu   huì   yī gè rén   liú   zài   學校  niàn   shū
all  can  A person   stop in   學校 recite book
when she didn't have to go to cram school.
欸  你  是  不是  怕  那  群  偷  渡  上岸  的  殭  屍  跳到  這裡
āi   nǐ   shì   bù shì   pà   nà   qún   tōu   dù   shàng àn   de   jiang   shī   tiào dào   zhè lǐ
sigh you is   not     fear that crowd burglar cross Ashore    of  jiāng  corpse Jump to   Here
So, you asked me to stay behind at school with you
才  叫  我  陪  你  啊
cái   jiào   wǒ   péi   nǐ   a
talent call  I   accompany you ah
only because you are afraid of those zombies, right?
我  是  怕  你  笨
wǒ   shì   pà   nǐ   bèn
I   is   fear you foolish
I am just worried you're getting stupid.
對了
duì le
correct
Right.
這裡  有  封信  是  老  曹  叫  我  拿給  你的
zhè lǐ   yǒu   fēng xìn   shì   lǎo   cáo   jiào   wǒ   ná gěi   nǐ de
Here    have Letter    is   old  surname call  I   Show it your
Tsao asked me to give you this letter.
我  親愛  的  沈  佳  宜  同  學
wǒ   qīn ài   de   chén   jiā   yí   tóng   xué
I   dear    of  sink  good suitable same  learning
My dear Shen Chia-Yi
我  很  喜歡  你
wǒ   hěn   xǐ huan   nǐ
I   very like     you
I like you very much.
俗話說  ：  Nothing'  s  gonna  change  my  love  for  you
sú huà shuō   ：  Nothing'  s  gonna  change  my  love  for  you
As the saying goes ： Nothing' s gonna change my love for you
As the song goes, "Nothing's gonna change my love for you.
Making love out of nothing at all
勉強  可以  表達  我  對  你的  感覺
miǎn qiáng   kě yǐ   biǎo dá   wǒ   duì   nǐ de   gǎn jué
reluctantly can    expression I   to   your   feel
barely expresses my feelings for you.
這  是  你的  字  耶
zhè   shì   nǐ de   zì   yé
this is   your   letter ye
This is your handwriting.
柯  景  騰
kē   jǐng   téng
stalk scenery fly
Ko Ching-Teng
我  不得不  說  耶
wǒ   bù dé bù   shuō   yé
I   have to   speak ye
I must say
你  寫  情書  的  文  筆  真的  很  差  耶
nǐ   xiě   情書  de   wén   bǐ   zhēn de   hěn   chà   yé
you write 情書 of  literature write Really   very different ye
you suck at writing love letters.
哪  可能
nǎ   kě néng
where may
What do you mean?
明明  就  寫  得  氣  勢  非凡  好不好
míng míng   jiù   xiě   dé   qì   shì   fēi fán   hǎo bù hǎo
Obviously  just write obtain air power extraordinary ok
I am that close to William Shakespeare, okay?
有  時間  幫  人家  寫  情書  啊
yǒu   shí jiān   bāng   rén jiā   xiě   情書  a
have time      assist People   write 情書 ah
Since you have the time to write love letters for someone else.
不如  用  這些  時間  拿去  背  單  字
bù rú   yòng   zhè xiē   shí jiān   ná qù   bèi   dān   zì
Not as well use   these    time      Take it back single letter
Why don't you use the time to memorize some English vocabulary?
說  真的
shuō   zhēn de
speak Really
Ok.
雖然  我  很  帥  人  聰明  又會  講  笑話
suī rán   wǒ   hěn   shuài   rén   cōng míng   yòu huì   jiǎng   xiào huà
although I   very commander man  clever     Will again explain joke
Even though I am cute, smart and incredibly humorous
但  妳  不要  輕易  的  喜歡  上  我
dàn   nai   bù yào   qīng yì   de   xǐ huan   shàng   wǒ
only nǎi  Do not  easily   of  like     on     I
don't fall in love with me easily.
因為  我  是  孤獨  的  風  中一  匹狼
yīn wèi   wǒ   shì   gū dú   de   fēng   zhōng yī   pǐ láng
because  I   is   lonely of  wind  In one    Wolf
Because I am a lone wolf traveling in the wild wind.
謝謝  喔
xiè xiè   ō
Thank you cry
Oh, thanks
我  又  不喜歡  比  我  笨  的  男  生
wǒ   yòu   bù xǐ huan   bǐ   wǒ   bèn   de   nán   shēng
I   and  dislike     liken I   foolish of  male life
I'm not interested in guys who are dumber than me.
沈  佳  宜  不喜歡  比  她  笨  的  男  生
chén   jiā   yí   bù xǐ huan   bǐ   tā   bèn   de   nán   shēng
sink  good suitable dislike     liken she foolish of  male life
Shen Chia-Yi doesn't like guys that are dumber than her.
笨
bèn
foolish
Dumb?
我  是  怕  搶了  妳  全  校  第一  名  的  頭銜
wǒ   shì   pà   qiǎng le   nai   quán   xiào   dì yī   míng   de   tóu xián
I   is   fear Robbed    nǎi  whole school first  name  of  title
Come on, I let you win on purpose
才  一直  忍  妳  讓  妳
cái   yī zhí   rěn   nai   ràng   nai
talent Always  endure nǎi  allow nǎi
I don't study hard cause I don't want to beat you
故意  輸  給  妳  好不好
gù yì   shū   gěi   nai   hǎo bù hǎo
deliberately transport give nǎi  ok
and I don't want to hurt your feelings!
這  怎麼  好意思  啊
zhè   zěn me   hǎo yì si   a
this how     Sorry      ah
Pardon me.
拜  託  你  不用  這麼  忍耐
bài   tuō   nǐ   bù yòng   zhè me   rěn nài
bow  entrust you No need to so      patience
Save your kindness, mister. You are welcome to try to beat me anytime!
敢不  敢  跟  我  打  一個  賭
gǎn bù   gǎn   gēn   wǒ   dǎ   yī gè   dǔ
Dare not venture with I   strike One    bet
I dare you to bet with me.
賭
dǔ
bet
Let's bet on...
頭髮
tóu fà
hair
Your hair.
怎麼  賭
zěn me   dǔ
how     bet
How?
如果  妳  月  考  考  贏  我  的話
rú guǒ   nai   yuè   kǎo   kǎo   yíng   wǒ   de huà
in case nǎi  moon examine examine win   I   if
If you beat me in the next midterm
妳  要  怎麼  整  我  都  可以
nai   yào   zěn me   zhěng   wǒ   dōu   kě yǐ
nǎi  need how     orderly I   all  can
you can do whatever you want to me.
但  如果  我  考  贏  妳  的話
dàn   rú guǒ   wǒ   kǎo   yíng   nai   de huà
only in case I   examine win   nǎi  if
But, if I won
妳  要  綁  一個  月  的  馬  尾
nai   yào   bǎng   yī gè   yuè   de   mǎ   wěi
nǎi  need bind  One    moon of  horse tail
you will have to wear a ponytail for a month.
隨便  啊
suí biàn   a
casual    ah
Sure, whatever.
反正  又  不可能
fǎn zhèng   yòu   bù kěn éng
Anyway     and  impossible
It's not like you would win anyway!
這  種  超  雞  巴  的  自信  我  又  被  電  到了
zhè   zhǒng   chāo   jī   bā   de   zì xìn   wǒ   yòu   bèi   diàn   dào le
this seed   surpass chickens desire of  confidence I   and  by   electricity Arrived
I was struck by her cocky confidence right away.
喂
wèi
hey
Hey, you.
三  更  半夜  不  睡覺
sān   gèng   bàn yè   bù   shuì jiào
three more  midnight no  go to bed
Why on earth you need to study freaking English
背  什麼  死人  骨頭  英  文
bèi   shén me   sǐ rén   gǔ tou   yīng   wén
back what     dead    bone    petal literature
in the middle of the night?
I fuck you
I fuck you too
I fuck your mother.
你  幹  嘛  幹  嘛  啦
nǐ   gàn   ma   gàn   ma   la
you trunk ma  trunk ma  la
What's wrong with you?
Fuck you fuck you
I love you
I LOVE YOU
老  闆
lǎo   bǎn
old  boss
Hey, Ma'am.
來  碗  超  帥  的  光頭
lái   wǎn   chāo   shuài   de   guāng tóu
come bowl surpass commander of  Bald head
A super hot and charming jar head, please.
三  八  啦  光頭  哪有  帥  的
sān   bā   la   guāng tóu   nǎ yǒu   shuài   de
three eight la  Bald head  How can there be commander of
Idiot, how can a jar head be handsome?
有  啦
yǒu   la
have la
Of course there is.
不信  你  剪  剪  看
bù xìn   nǐ   jiǎn   jiǎn   kàn
Do not believe you scissors scissors look
Give it a try if you don't believe me.
不  欠  你  啦
bù   qiàn   nǐ   la
no  owe   you la
Here, I don't owe you any more.
不要  弄  啦
bù yào   nòng   la
Do not  do    la
Stop that.
我  在  補  習  班  聽說
wǒ   zài   bǔ   xí   bān   tīng shuō
I   in   mend practice class heard
Rumor has it that Inoue Takehiko has died a couple weeks ago!
井  上  雄  彥  啊  前  幾個  禮拜  出  車  禍  死了
jǐng   shàng   xióng   yàn   a   qián   jǐ gè   lǐ bài   chū   chē   huò   sǐ le
well  on     hero   elegant ah forward several worship leave cart misfortune died
I heard that he died in a car accident.
是  喔
shì   ō
is   cry
Really.
難怪  我  感覺  他  畫  風  有  點  變
náng uài   wǒ   gǎn jué   tā   huà   fēng   yǒu   diǎn   biàn
No wonder I   feel     he  draw wind  have dot   change
No wonder I felt something was different in his drawing style.
突然  變  強  而已  這  種  天才  怎麼  可能  說  死  就  死  啊
tú rán   biàn   qiáng   ér yǐ   zhè   zhǒng   tiān cái   zěn me   kě néng   shuō   sǐ   jiù   sǐ   a
suddenly change strong Just now this seed   genius    how     may      speak die just die ah
More powerful that is, how can such a genius die just like that.
你  覺  不覺  得
nǐ   jué   不覺  dé
you conscious 不覺 obtain
Don't you think...
覺得  怎樣
jué de   zěn yàng
feel    how
Think What?
你  覺  不覺  得  沈  佳  宜  有  點  喜歡  我
nǐ   jué   不覺  dé   chén   jiā   yí   yǒu   diǎn   xǐ huan   wǒ
you conscious 不覺 obtain sink  good suitable have dot   like     I
Don't you think Shen Chia-Yi likes me?
不然  今天  怎麼  綁  馬  尾
bù rán   jīn tiān   zěn me   bǎng   mǎ   wěi
otherwise today     how     bind  horse tail
If not, why would she wear a ponytail today?
也許  喔
yě xǔ   ō
Maybe  cry
Maybe!
沈  佳  宜  怎麼  知道  我  喜歡  綁  馬  尾  的  女生  啊
chén   jiā   yí   zěn me   zhī dào   wǒ   xǐ huan   bǎng   mǎ   wěi   de   nǚ shēng   a
sink  good suitable how     know     I   like     bind  horse tail of  Girls     ah
How did Shen Chia-Yi know I like girls who wear ponytails?
是嗎
shì ma
is it
You too?
我  一直  一直  都  很  喜歡  綁  馬  尾  的  女生  啊
wǒ   yī zhí   yī zhí   dōu   hěn   xǐ huan   bǎng   mǎ   wěi   de   nǚ shēng   a
I   Always  Always  all  very like     bind  horse tail of  Girls     ah
I always like girls who wear ponytails.
我  也是
wǒ   yě shì
I   Also too
So do!
我  不知道  沈  佳  宜  為什  麼  贏了  還要  綁  馬  尾
wǒ   bù zhī dào   chén   jiā   yí   為什  me   yíng le   hái yào   bǎng   mǎ   wěi
I   do not know sink  good suitable 為什 insignificant Won      But also bind  horse tail
I don't know why Shen Chia-Yi wore a ponytail that day even though she won the bet.
但  從此  以後
dàn   cóng cǐ   yǐ hòu
only Since then after
However, ever since then
努力  用  功  讀書  竟然  變成  一件  非常  熱  血  的  事
nǔ lì   yòng   gōng   dú shū   jìng rán   biàn chéng   yī jiàn   fēi cháng   rè   xiè   de   shì
Effort use   achievement reading actually  become      One      very much  hot blood of  thing
studying hard had become an enthusiastic thing for me.
幾千塊  錢  的  班  費  不  見了
jǐ qiān kuài   qián   de   bān   fèi   bù   見了
Thousands of pieces money of  class expenses no  見了
The class funds went missing.
第六  節  課  的  時候  班長  檢查  還  在
dì liù   jié   kè   de   shí hou   bān zhǎng   jiǎn chá   hái   zài
sixth   holiday lesson of  time     Squad leader an examination still in
It was still here when the class leader checked about an hour ago.
現在  要  放  學  了
xiàn zài   yào   fàng   xué   le
now       need put   learning is
Now school is almost finished.
偷錢  的  人  還會  有  誰
tōu qián   de   rén   hái huì   yǒu   sheí
Stealing money of  man  Will also be have who
Who else could have stolen that money?
一定  是  你們  班  上  自己  的  同  學
yī dìng   shì   nǐ men   bān   shàng   zì jǐ   de   tóng   xué
for sure is   you     class on     self   of  same  learning
It must be someone sitting in this classroom!
把  錢  偷走  的  再不  自  首  的話
bǎ   qián   tōu zǒu   de   zài bu   zì   shǒu   de huà
take money Stolen   of  No again self head  if
Whoever stole that money, you better turn yourself in right now.
就  不要  怪  教  官  不  客  氣
jiù   bù yào   guài   jiào   guān   bù   kè   qì
just Do not  strange teach official no  guest air
Otherwise, don't blame me for being too harsh afterwards.
好
hǎo
good
Fine.
不敢  承認  也沒有  關係
bù gǎn   chéng rèn   yě méi yǒu   guān xì
Dare not recognition nor         relationship
It's okay if no one wants to admit it
反正  這個  小偷  就  在  你們  這個  班  上
fǎn zhèng   zhè ge   xiǎo tōu   jiù   zài   nǐ men   zhè ge   bān   shàng
Anyway     This one Thief     just in   you     This one class on
I guarantee that the thief is sitting right here in this room.
他  一定  覺得  自己  很  聰明
tā   yī dìng   jué de   zì jǐ   hěn   cōng míng
he  for sure feel    self   very clever
The person must thinks that he can get away with this.
好
hǎo
good
Good
很好
hěn hǎo
well
very good.
現在  每一  個人  把  紙  筆  拿出來
xiàn zài   měi yī   gè rén   bǎ   zhǐ   bǐ   ná chū lái
now       Each one people  take paper write take it out
Now, take out your pen, everyone.
寫下  你  認為  可能是  小偷  的  人  的  名字
xiě xià   nǐ   rèn wéi   kě néng shì   xiǎo tōu   de   rén   de   míng zì
Write down you think    maybe        Thief     of  man  of  first name
And write down the name of the person that you think it's most likely to be the thief.
投  票  結果  前  三  名
tóu   piào   jié guǒ   qián   sān   míng
throw ticket result   forward three name
The top three named
把  書  包  倒  在  講台  上  讓  我  檢查
bǎ   shū   bāo   dào   zài   jiǎng tái   shàng   ràng   wǒ   jiǎn chá
take book wrap inverted in   Podium     on     allow I   an examination
will have to bring your bags forward, and I will check them personally.
立刻
lì kè
Immediately
Now!
馬上  把  隨  堂  測  驗  紙  拿出來
mǎ shàng   bǎ   suí   táng   cè   yàn   zhǐ   ná chū lái
immediately take follow hall  measure test paper take it out
Take out your paper right now.
曹  國  勝
cáo   guó   shèng
surname nation victory
Tsao Kuo-Sheng.
你  幹  什麼
nǐ   gàn   shén me
you trunk what
What are you doing?
教  官
jiào   guān
teach official
Sir.
你  憑  什麼  叫  我們  懷疑  自己  的  同  學
nǐ   píng   shén me   jiào   wǒ men   huái yí   zì jǐ   de   tóng   xué
you because of what     call  us      doubt    self   of  same  learning
Who do you think you are to have us suspect our own classmates?
我  是  教  官  還  是  你  是  教  官
wǒ   shì   jiào   guān   hái   shì   nǐ   shì   jiào   guān
I   is   teach official still is   you is   teach official
Now who is the supervisor? Are you or am I?
你  是  教  官
nǐ   shì   jiào   guān
you is   teach official
You are, sir.
但  你  是個  爛  人  啦
dàn   nǐ   shì gè   làn   rén   la
only you Is      rotten man  la
But you are an ass hole!
你  說什  麼
nǐ   shuō shén   me
you Say it     insignificant
What did you say?
我  說你  爛  人
wǒ   shuō nǐ   làn   rén
I   saying you rotten man
I said you are an asshole.
柯  景  騰  曹  國  勝
kē   jǐng   téng   cáo   guó   shèng
stalk scenery fly   surname nation victory
Ko Ching-Teng, Tsao Kuo-Sheng
我  看  你們  兩  個  是  做  賊  心  虛
wǒ   kàn   nǐ men   liǎng   ge   shì   zuò   zéi   xīn   xū
I   look you     two    piece is   work thief heart false
I think you guys are bluffing
把  你們  的  書  包  給  我  拿  過來  第一  個  檢查
bǎ   nǐ men   de   shū   bāo   gěi   wǒ   ná   guò lái   dì yī   ge   jiǎn chá
take you     of  book wrap give I   take come     first  piece an examination
bring your bags now and I will check yours first.
報告  教  官
bào gào   jiào   guān
report   teach official
Excuse me, Sir.
你  不可以  這樣
nǐ   bù kě yǐ   zhè yàng
you Can not   such
You have no right to do that
不可以  怎麼樣
bù kě yǐ   zěn me yàng
Can not   how is it
I have no right to do what?
不可以  叫  我們  投  這  種  票
bù kě yǐ   jiào   wǒ men   tóu   zhè   zhǒng   piào
Can not   call  us      throw this seed   ticket
You can't ask us to write down names and vote on such a thing.
不可以  叫  我們  懷疑  自己  的  同  學
bù kě yǐ   jiào   wǒ men   huái yí   zì jǐ   de   tóng   xué
Can not   call  us      doubt    self   of  same  learning
You can't ask us to suspect our own classmates.
大  不了  大家  再把  錢  繳  一次  就  好了
dà   bù liǎo   dà jiā   zài bǎ   qián   jiǎo   yī cì   jiù   hǎo le
big No more than that everyone Again   money deliver once   just All right
We can just all pay the fees again.
這  也沒  什麼
zhè   yě méi   shén me
this also not what
It's no big deal.
對  啊
duì   a
to   ah
Exactly.
再  繳  一次  就  好了  嘛
zài   jiǎo   yī cì   jiù   hǎo le   ma
again deliver once   just All right ma
We can just pay again.
妳  不要  以為  你  成  績  好  說什  麼  都  沒有  關係
nai   bù yào   yǐ wéi   nǐ   chéng   jī   hǎo   shuō shén   me   dōu   méi yǒu   guān xì
nǎi  Do not  think   you completed spin good Say it     insignificant all  No       relationship
Being an honor student doesn't mean that you can say whatever you want.
把  你的  書  包  拿  過來
bǎ   nǐ de   shū   bāo   ná   guò lái
take your   book wrap take come
Bring your bag over here.
我們  不要
wǒ men   bù yào
us      Do not
No way.
我們  又  不是  小偷
wǒ men   yòu   bù shì   xiǎo tōu
us      and  not     Thief
We are not thieves.
爛  人
làn   rén
rotten man
Douche.
你  說什  麼
nǐ   shuō shén   me
you Say it     insignificant
What did you say?
爛  人  啦
làn   rén   la
rotten man  la
I said you are a douchebag.
統統  把  書  包  給  我  拿  過來
tǒng tǒng   bǎ   shū   bāo   gěi   wǒ   ná   guò lái
all        take book wrap give I   take come
Bring your bags over now, all of you.
不要
bù yào
Do not
No.
教  官
jiào   guān
teach official
Sir
我  現在  合理  的  懷疑  你  沒有  小雞  雞
wǒ   xiàn zài   hé lǐ   de   huái yí   nǐ   méi yǒu   xiǎo jī   jī
I   now       reasonable of  doubt    you No       chick    chickens
I now suspect that you have no balls.
褲子  脫下
kù zi   tuō xià
pants  Take off
Take your pants off now.
你  說什  麼
nǐ   shuō shén   me
you Say it     insignificant
What did you say?
褲子  脫下  啦
kù zi   tuō xià   la
pants  Take off la
Take your pants off.
把  書  包  拿  過來
bǎ   shū   bāo   ná   guò lái
take book wrap take come
Bring your bags over.
要  就  給  你  啦
yào   jiù   gěi   nǐ   la
need just give you la
Fine, here you go!
你們  不要  一直  看  我
nǐ men   bù yào   yī zhí   kàn   wǒ
you     Do not  Always  look I
Stop staring at me.
我  覺得很  丟臉
wǒ   jué de hěn   diū liǎn
I   Feel very   Lose face
It's very embarrassing. I feel so ashamed.
一點  都  不丟  臉  啊
yī diǎn   dōu   bù diū   liǎn   a
a little all  Not lost face  ah
There is nothing to be ashamed of.
妳  超  厲害  的  耶
nai   chāo   lì hài   de   yé
nǎi  surpass Powerful of  ye
You kicked ass!
半  蹲  不用  太  認真  啦
bàn   dūn   bù yòng   tài   rèn zhēn   la
half squat No need to very serious   la
Don't need to be too serious about this.
沈  佳  宜
chén   jiā   yí
sink  good suitable
Shen Chia-Yi.
稍微  休息  一下
shāo wéi   xiū xí   yí xià
a little  rest    a bit
Relax a bit.
蹲  個  意思  意思  就  好了  啊
dūn   ge   yì si   yì si   jiù   hǎo le   a
squat piece meaning meaning just All right ah
Just pretend, it's no big deal.
反正  那些  老師  根本  沒  在  看
fǎn zhèng   nà xiē   lǎo shī   gēn běn   méi   zài   kàn
Anyway     those   teacher  fundamental not  in   look
Those teachers are not watching anyway.
偶  爾  當  一下  壞  學生  很  爽  的
ǒu   ěr   dāng   yí xià   huài   xué shēng   hěn   shuǎng   de
accidentally you that  a bit   bad   student    very happy   of
It's kind of nice to be a bad student once in a while, isn't it?
好  丟臉
hǎo   diū liǎn
good Lose face
I am so ashamed.
認識  妳  從  國中  到  現在
rèn shi   nai   cóng   guó zhōng   dào   xiàn zài
understanding nǎi  from  secondary  arrive now
Ever since I knew you from junior high
剛剛  是  我  唯  一  覺得  妳  比  我  厲害  的  時候
gāng gāng   shì   wǒ   wéi   yī   jué de   nai   bǐ   wǒ   lì hài   de   shí hou
just       is   I   only one feel    nǎi  liken I   Powerful of  time
that was the only time I was amazed by how tough you really are.
沈  佳  宜  妳  超  正  點  的  耶
chén   jiā   yí   nai   chāo   zhèng   diǎn   de   yé
sink  good suitable nǎi  surpass right  dot   of  ye
Shen Chia-Yi, you rock!
哭  起來  也  超  正  的
kū   qǐ lái   yě   chāo   zhèng   de
weep stand up also surpass right  of
You look so pretty even when you cry.
對  啊
duì   a
to   ah
Yeah.
超  正  的
chāo   zhèng   de
surpass right  of
Super duper cool.
令人  刮  目  相  看
lìng rén   guā   mù   xiāng   kàn
It is     shave eye mutual look
Unbelievably cool.
不像  考  卷  所有  複雜  困難  的  問題  都  能  得到  一個  解答
bù xiàng   kǎo   juǎn   suǒ yǒu   fù zá   kùn nán   de   wèn tí   dōu   néng   dé dào   yī gè   jiě dá
Not like  examine scroll all      complex difficult of  problem all  can   get     One    answer
Unlike quizzes
真實  人生  裡有  些事  永遠  也沒有  答案
zhēn shí   rén shēng   li yǒu   xiē shì   yǒng yuǎn   yě méi yǒu   dá àn
real      life       inside  Some things forever    nor         answer
you never find a correct answer in life.
到底是  誰  偷了  班  費  沒有  人  知道
dào dǐ shì   sheí   tōu le   bān   fèi   méi yǒu   rén   zhī dào
In the end is who   Stolen  class expenses No       man  know
No one really knew who stole our money, but no one really cared.
只  記得  那天  的  沈  佳  宜  真的
zhǐ   jì de   nèi tiān   de   chén   jiā   yí   zhēn de
only remember That day  of  sink  good suitable Really
All I remembered from that day was Shen Chia-Yi's face
好  美好  美
hǎo   měi hǎo   měi
good Beautiful beautiful
beautifully and delicately engraved in my heart.
六年  前  剛剛  踏  進  精  誠  中  學  國中  部  的  時候
liù nián   qián   gāng gāng   tà   jìn   jīng   chéng   zhōng   xué   guó zhōng   bù   de   shí hou
Six years forward just       trample advance essence sincere central learning secondary  part of  time
Six years ago, when we first stepped in to Jing-Cheng high school
十二歲  的  我們  懵  懵  懂  懂
shí èr suì   de   wǒ men   měng   měng   dǒng   dǒng
Twelve years old of  us      stupid stupid understand understand
we were all young and immature.
雖然  對於  未來  有  無限  的  想像
suī rán   duì wū   wèi lái   yǒu   wú xiàn   de   xiǎng xiàng
although for     future   have unlimited of  imagine
Although we had great dreams about our future
卻  不知道  能  在  這裡  學習  到  什麼  收穫  到  什麼
què   bù zhī dào   néng   zài   zhè lǐ   xué xí   dào   shén me   shōu huò   dào   shén me
still do not know can   in   Here    Learn   arrive what     reward    arrive what
we weren't really sure what we were going to learn and encounter during these years.
幸  好  一路上  有  師  長  的  諄  諄  教誨
xìng   hǎo   yī lù shàng   yǒu   shī   chǎng   de   zhūn   zhūn   jiào huì
favor good Along the way have teacher long   of  patient patient Teach
Thanks to the teachers who led us and furnished us with abundant knowledge.
同  學  們也  建立  了  深厚  的  情誼
tóng   xué   men yě   jiàn lì   le   shēn hòu   de   qíng yì
same  learning Also too set up   is  deep      of  Friendship
Thanks to all the peers who accompanied us throughout the years
一起  經歷  困難  挫折  也  一起  攜  手  成長
yì qǐ   jīng lì   kùn nán   cuò zhé   yě   yì qǐ   xié   shǒu   chéng zhǎng
together experience difficult frustration also together carry hand  growing up
with bitter and sweet memories.
我  說  精  誠  中  學  就是  我們  的  青春
wǒ   shuō   jīng   chéng   zhōng   xué   jiù shì   wǒ men   de   qīng chūn
I   speak essence sincere central learning That is  us      of  youth
Ching-Chen high school represents our young and crazy days
也是  最美  好  的  行囊
yě shì   zuì měi   hǎo   de   xíng nāng
Also too most beautiful good of  Luggage
it gave us the most wonderful times of our life.
畢  業  典禮  後
bì   yè   diǎn lǐ   hòu
end profession ceremony after
From now on
讓  我們  用力  的  張開  翅膀  飛  向  各自  不同  的  夢想
ràng   wǒ men   yòng lì   de   zhāng kāi   chì bǎng   fēi   xiàng   gè zì   bù tóng   de   mèng xiǎng
allow us      Forced   of  Open       wing      fly  toward respective different of  dream
it's time for us to spread our wings and chase our dreams.
各位  同  學
gè wèi   tóng   xué
Everybody same  learning
So long, my friends.
我們  珍重  再見
wǒ men   zhēn zhòng   zài jiàn
us      treasure    Goodbye
So long, my friends.
真  羨慕  妳
zhēn   xiàn mù   nai
real  envy     nǎi
How I envy you.
國中  三年  高  中  三年  都  有  這麼  多人  追  妳
guó zhōng   sān nián   gāo   zhōng   sān nián   dōu   yǒu   zhè me   多人  zhuī   nai
secondary  Three years high central Three years all  have so      多人 pursue nǎi
You have so many guys chasing after you throughout the years!
被  喜歡  其實是  很不  錯
bèi   xǐ huan   qí shí shì   hěn bù   cuò
by   like     Actually    Very bad error
Yes, it's quite nice to be liked by someone.
但是
dàn shì
but
But...
妳  該  不會  想說  被  這麼  多人  追  其實  很  困擾  吧
nai   gāi   bù huì   xiǎng shuō   bèi   zhè me   多人  zhuī   qí shí   hěn   kùn rǎo   ba
nǎi  should will not Want to say by   so      多人 pursue in fact very Troubled !
Don't tell me that you feel annoyed because you are too popular.
不是  啦
bù shì   la
not     la
No
我  只是  覺得  自己  是個  很  幸福  的  人
wǒ   zhǐ shì   jué de   zì jǐ   shì gè   hěn   xìng fú   de   rén
I   just     feel    self   Is      very happy    of  man
I just think that I am a very lucky girl.
那  妳  決定  好了  嗎
nà   nai   jué dìng   hǎo le   ma
that nǎi  Decision  All right ?
So, have you decided?
決定  什麼
jué dìng   shén me
Decision  what
Decided what?
決定  跟  誰  在一起  啊
jué dìng   gēn   sheí   zài yī qǐ   a
Decision  with who   Together   ah
Decided whom you want to be with.
幹  嘛  啊  連  我  都  不能  說  喔
gàn   ma   a   lián   wǒ   dōu   bù néng   shuō   ō
trunk ma  ah join  I   all  Can not  speak cry
Come on, you can't even tell me?
如果  …
rú guǒ   …
in case …
Ok, if...
…    我  會  很  高興  的
…    wǒ   huì   hěn   gāo xìng   de
…  I   can  very happy     of
I will be really happy.
畢  業  快樂
bì   yè   kuài lè
end profession happy
Happy graduation.
終於  聯  考  了
zhōng wū   lián   kǎo   le
at last   connect examine is
Finally, the colleague entrance exam came.
對  我  來說  聯  考  好像  不是  去  考  大學
duì   wǒ   lái shuō   lián   kǎo   hǎo xiàng   bù shì   qù   kǎo   大學
to   I   For example connect examine like       not     go  examine 大學
To me, the exam was more like a test for Shen Chia-Yi's special training programs
而是  驗  收  沈  佳  宜  對  我  的  特  訓  成果
ér shì   yàn   shōu   chén   jiā   yí   duì   wǒ   de   tè   xùn   chéng guǒ
Instead test collect sink  good suitable to   I   of  special teach Results
rather than an exam for college.
升  大學  前  最後  一個  夏天  的  主題  是  咸  咸  的  海水
shēng   大學  qián   zuì hòu   yī gè   xià tiān   de   zhǔ tí   shì   xián   xián   de   hǎi shuǐ
arise  大學 forward At last  One    summer    of  theme   is   together together of  seawater
We spent most of our time at the beach during the summer before college.
真的  很  幼稚
zhēn de   hěn   yòu zhì
Really   very naive
They are so childish
超  幼稚  的
chāo   yòu zhì   de
surpass naive    of
I know, so childish.
你  應該  不太  喜歡  幼稚  的  男  生  吧
nǐ   yīng gāi   bù tài   xǐ huan   yòu zhì   de   nán   shēng   ba
you should    Not too much like     naive    of  male life   !
You don't really like childish guys, do you?
嗯
n
ń
No.
那  你  覺得  裡面  誰  最  幼稚
nà   nǐ   jué de   lǐ miàn   sheí   zuì   yòu zhì
that you feel    inside   who   most naive
Who do you think is the most childish one among them all.
柯  騰  吧
kē   téng   ba
stalk fly   !
Ko-Teng, maybe?
那  我  呢
nà   wǒ   ne
that I   this
How about me?
你  很  幼稚  耶
nǐ   hěn   yòu zhì   yé
you very naive    ye
You are so childish.
畢  業  了  耶
bì   yè   le   yé
end profession is  ye
Now that we have graduated
你們  有  沒有  想過  以後  要  幹  嘛
nǐ men   yǒu   méi yǒu   xiǎng guò   yǐ hòu   yào   gàn   ma
you     have No       Thought about it after   need trunk ma
have you thought about what you want to do in the future?
我  想去  科  學  園  區  上  班
wǒ   xiǎng qù   kē   xué   yuán   qū   shàng   bān
I   Want to go section learning garden area on     class
I want to work in the Hsinchu Science and Industrial Park
分  股  票  賺  大  錢
fēn   gǔ   piào   zhuàn   dà   qián
divide thighs ticket earn   big money
so I can get stocks for bonuses and tons of money.
然後  娶  沈  佳  宜
rán hòu   qǔ   chén   jiā   yí
then     marry sink  good suitable
And then I can marry Shen Chia-Yi...
或  胡  家  瑋
huò   hú   jiā   wěi
or   recklessly house rare
or Hu Chia-Wei.
誰  要  嫁給  你  啊
sheí   yào   jià gěi   nǐ   a
who   need Marry    you ah
Who wants to marry you?
我  想出  國  唸  書  耶
wǒ   xiǎng chū   guó   niàn   shū   yé
I   Come up    nation recite book ye
I want to study abroad.
你  出國  很  浪費  錢  啦
nǐ   chū guó   hěn   làng fèi   qián   la
you Go abroad very waste     money la
It'll be such a waste of money, okay?
你  靠  腰  哦
nǐ   kào   yāo   ó
you trust waist Oh
Oh, fuck off.
出國  唸  書
chū guó   niàn   shū
Go abroad recite book
Study abroad?
我  也想  出國  唸  書
wǒ   yě xiǎng   chū guó   niàn   shū
I   also want Go abroad recite book
I want to study abroad, too.
去  申  請  公  費  留  學  念  MBA
qù   shēn   qǐng   gōng   fèi   liú   xué   niàn   MBA
go  report ask   fair  expenses stop learning recall MBA
Maybe I will apply for government scholarships and get an MBA degree
我  想  一直  打  籃  球  下去  打進  校  隊
wǒ   xiǎng   yī zhí   dǎ   lán   qiú   xià qù   dǎ jìn   xiào   duì
I   think  Always  strike basket ball Go on   Scored on school team
I want to keep on playing basketball.
最後  打進  美國  職  籃
zuì hòu   dǎ jìn   美國  zhí   lán
At last  Scored on 美國 duty basket
And maybe one day make my way to NBA.
家  瑋  呢
jiā   wěi   ne
house rare this
What about you, Chia-Wei?
我  啊
wǒ   a
I   ah
Me?
找個  有  錢  人  嫁  掉  就  好  啦
zhǎo gè   yǒu   qián   rén   jià   diào   jiù   hǎo   la
Find a   have money man  marry turn  just good la
I think I will find myself a rich man to marry.
干  你  屁  事
gàn   nǐ   pì   shì
oppose you fart thing
Go away.
沈  佳  宜  咧
chén   jiā   yí   liě
sink  good suitable grimace
What about you, Shen Chia-Yi?
我  對  自己  的  未來  其實  沒有  太多  想像
wǒ   duì   zì jǐ   de   wèi lái   qí shí   méi yǒu   tài duō   xiǎng xiàng
I   to   self   of  future   in fact No       too much imagine
I don't expect much about my future, really.
還有  一個人  還沒  說  耶
hái yǒu   yī gè rén   hái méi   shuō   yé
and also A person   not yet  speak ye
Ko-Teng, it's your turn
我  想  成為  一個  很  厲害  的  人
wǒ   xiǎng   chéng wéi   yī gè   hěn   lì hài   de   rén
I   think  become     One    very Powerful of  man
I want to be a kickass person.
你  這  有  說  跟  沒說  根本  一樣  嘛
nǐ   zhè   yǒu   shuō   gēn   méi shuō   gēn běn   yī yàng   ma
you this have speak with Did not say fundamental same     ma
What are you talking about?
怎樣  才是  厲害  的  人  啊
zěn yàng   cái shì   lì hài   de   rén   a
how       Is it    Powerful of  man  ah
What is a kickass person?
讓  這個  世界  因為  有  了  我  而有  一點點  的  不  一樣
ràng   zhè ge   shì jiè   yīn wèi   yǒu   le   wǒ   ér yǒu   yī diǎn diǎn   de   bù   yī yàng
allow This one world    because  have is  I   And there is a little bit  of  no  same
I want the world to be a little bit better because of me.
而  我  的  世界  不過  就是  妳  的  心
ér   wǒ   de   shì jiè   bù guò   jiù shì   nai   de   xīn
and I   of  world    but     That is  nǎi  of  heart
And you are the only person that is going to make my world better.
喂  幹  嘛
wèi   gàn   ma
hey  trunk ma
Hello. Yes?
我  只會  唸  書
wǒ   zhǐ huì   niàn   shū
I   Only will recite book
I am a nerd
我  只會  唸  書
wǒ   zhǐ huì   niàn   shū
I   Only will recite book
I am a bookworm.
從  國中  到  高  中
cóng   guó zhōng   dào   gāo   zhōng
from  secondary  arrive high central
Ever since junior high and high school.
我  就  只會  唸  書
wǒ   jiù   zhǐ huì   niàn   shū
I   just Only will recite book
All I did was studying
卻  還  是  考  不好
què   hái   shì   kǎo   bù hǎo
still still is   examine not good
I still screwed it up.
不管  妳  念  哪  間學校
bù guǎn   nai   niàn   nǎ   jiān xué xiào
Regardless of nǎi  recall where School
No matter which university you go to
有  件事  我  想  跟  妳  說
yǒu   jiàn shì   wǒ   xiǎng   gēn   nai   shuō
have Something I   think  with nǎi  speak
there is something that I want to say to you.
拜  託  你
bài   tuō   nǐ
bow  entrust you
Please.
不要  現在  跟  我  講  你  喜歡  我
bù yào   xiàn zài   gēn   wǒ   jiǎng   nǐ   xǐ huan   wǒ
Do not  now       with I   explain you like     I
Don't tell me you like me now
我  喜歡  妳
wǒ   xǐ huan   nai
I   like     nǎi
I do like you
妳  早就  知道了  啊
nai   zǎo jiù   zhī dào le   a
nǎi  Long ago Got it      ah
and you knew that already.
那  你  要  跟  我  說什  麼  啦
nà   nǐ   yào   gēn   wǒ   shuō shén   me   la
that you need with I   Say it     insignificant la
What do you want to tell me, then?
聯  考  放  榜  了
lián   kǎo   fàng   bǎng   le
connect examine put   placard is
The results were out.
阿  和  考  上了  清  大  經濟
ā   hàn   kǎo   shàng le   qīng   dà   jīng jì
a  and  examine On the    clear big economic
A-Ho got into Economics Major in National Tsing Hua University
朝  未來  出國  留  學  的  路  邁進
cháo   wèi lái   chū guó   liú   xué   de   lù   mài jìn
dynasty future   Go abroad stop learning of  road Move forward
which means he made one step forward to his overseas dream.
該  邊  考  上了  逢  甲  資  工
gāi   biān   kǎo   shàng le   féng   jiǎ   zī   gōng
should side  examine On the    flatter armor property labor
Groin got into Information Engineering at Feng Chia University
也  算是  踏上  了  科  學  園  區  之路
yě   suàn shì   tà shàng   le   kē   xué   yuán   qū   zhī lù
also Be        set foot on is  section learning garden area Road
to become one of those Science Park smart engineers.
老  曹  呢  考  上了  成  大  化  工
lǎo   cáo   ne   kǎo   shàng le   chéng   dà   huà   gōng
old  surname this examine On the    completed big change labor
Tsao got into Chemical Engineering at Cheng Kung University.
看  樣子  以後  要  去  美國  職  籃  是有  一點  難  度
kàn   yàng zi   yǐ hòu   yào   qù   美國  zhí   lán   shì yǒu   yī diǎn   nán   dù
look Look like after   need go  美國 duty basket there is a little difficult degree
So I guess it's most unlikely that he would make it into NBA.
沈  佳  宜  雖然  失  常
chén   jiā   yí   suī rán   shī   cháng
sink  good suitable although lose common
Although Shen Chia-Yi didn't do as well as she expected
但  還  是  考  上了  師  範  學院
dàn   hái   shì   kǎo   shàng le   shī   fàn   學院
only still is   examine On the    teacher pattern 學院
she still got into University of Education
想到  將來  沈  佳  宜  當  老師  的  樣子  就  覺得  非常  適合  她
xiǎng dào   jiāng lái   chén   jiā   yí   dāng   lǎo shī   de   yàng zi   jiù   jué de   fēi cháng   shì hé   tā
think      future     sink  good suitable that  teacher  of  Look like just feel    very much  Suitable for she
I could totally imagine Shen Chia-Yi being a teacher, it really suits her.
送  你
sòng   nǐ
dispatch you
Here, for you.
這  什麼
zhè   shén me
this what
What is this?
我  自己  畫  的
wǒ   zì jǐ   huà   de
I   self   draw of
I drew it myself.
有  點  醜
yǒu   diǎn   chǒu
have dot   homely
Not my best work
不過  還可以
bù guò   hái kě yǐ
but     is acceptable
but I think it's okay.
謝謝  囉
xiè xiè   luō
Thank you nag
Thanks.
沈  佳  宜  上  大學  以後
chén   jiā   yí   shàng   大學  yǐ hòu
sink  good suitable on     大學 after
Shen Chia-Yi, promise me something.
不要  太  快  讓  別  的  男  生  追到  妳
bù yào   tài   kuài   ràng   bié   de   nán   shēng   zhuī dào   nai
Do not  very rapid allow separate of  male life   Catch up  nǎi
Don't let boys get you too soon after you go to college.
好不好
hǎo bù hǎo
ok
Ok?
你  在  說什  麼  啊
nǐ   zài   shuō shén   me   a
you in   Say it     insignificant ah
What are you talking about?
(    你  是  我  最  珍貴  的  人  ）
(    nǐ   shì   wǒ   zuì   zhēng uì   de   rén   ）
(  you is   I   most precious  of  man  ）
You Are the Apple of My Eye.
喔  對了  還有  勃  起
ō   duì le   hái yǒu   bó   qǐ
cry correct and also suddenly onward
Oh, yes, as for the masturbating Boner.
一直  打  手  槍  的  勃  起  重  考
yī zhí   dǎ   shǒu   qiāng   de   bó   qǐ   zhòng   kǎo
Always  strike hand  spear  of  suddenly onward heavy  examine
He decided to stay and take the college entrance exam again.
重  考  重  考  陪  我  重  考  啦
zhòng   kǎo   zhòng   kǎo   péi   wǒ   zhòng   kǎo   la
heavy  examine heavy  examine accompany I   heavy  examine la
Take the entrance exam next year with me please!
我  也來  到  人生  的  下一站
wǒ   yě lái   dào   rén shēng   de   xià yí zhàn
I   Also come arrive life       of  next stop
I have also come to the next stage in my life
一間  沒有  沈  佳  宜  的  大學
yī jiàn   méi yǒu   chén   jiā   yí   de   大學
one      No       sink  good suitable of  大學
a school without Shen Chia-Yi
沒想到  我  第一  個  牽  手  的  女孩  不是  沈  佳  宜
méi xiǎng dào   wǒ   dì yī   ge   qiān   shǒu   de   nǚ hái   bù shì   chén   jiā   yí
did not expect I   first  piece drag  hand  of  girl    not     sink  good suitable
I never thought that Shen Chia-Yi would not be the first girl that I hold hands with.
而是  而是  一個  叫
ér shì   ér shì   yī gè   jiào
Instead Instead One    call
Instead of her, it was a girl named...
叫什  麼
jiào shén   me
Called     insignificant
Named...
你  好  我  叫  許可  欣
nǐ   hǎo   wǒ   jiào   xǔ kě   xīn
you good I   call  license happy
Hello, my name was Hsu Ke-Shin.
你  好  我  叫  柯  景  騰
nǐ   hǎo   wǒ   jiào   kē   jǐng   téng
you good I   call  stalk scenery fly
Hi, my name is Ko Ching-Teng.
宿舍  有  很多  奇  奇怪  怪  的  傳說
宿舍  yǒu   hěn duō   qí   qí guài   guài   de   chuán shuō
宿舍 have a lot of strange strange  strange of  legend
There were many weird stories in the dormitory.
大部分  都  跟  鬼  有  關
dà bù fèn   dōu   gēn   guǐ   yǒu   guān
most       all  with ghost have close
Most of them were ghost stories.
不過
bù guò
but
But
其中  有  一個  跟  四腳  獸  有  關  的  傳說
qí zhōng   yǒu   yī gè   gēn   sì jiǎo   shòu   yǒu   guān   de   chuán shuō
among them have One    with Four feet beast have close of  legend
there's one story about a four-legged beast.
絕對  是  真的
jué duì   shì   zhēn de
absolute is   Really
It was definitely real...
我  的  室  友  來自  四面八方
wǒ   de   shì   yǒu   lái zì   sì miàn bā fāng
I   of  room friend From    in all directions
My roommates came from all walks of life.
孝  綸  是個  肌肉  狂  整天  舉  啞  鈴
xiào   lun   shì gè   jī ròu   kuáng   zhěng tiān   jǔ   yǎ   líng
obedience lún  Is      muscle  insane All day     raise dumb bell
Hsiao-Lun was a muscle maniac, who did nothing but lifted weights all day long.
超級  宅  的  義  智
chāo jí   zhái   de   yì   zhì
super    residence of  righteousness wisdom
The ultimate weirdo is Yi-Chi.
隨時  都  在  看  動  漫  幾乎  不去  上  課
suí shí   dōu   zài   kàn   dòng   màn   jī hū   bù qù   shàng   kè
at any time all  in   look move  spreading almost Do not go on     lesson
He was never in the classroom because he's always reading Manga.
從  大一  就  開始  準備  考  研究所  的  建  漢
cóng   dà yī   jiù   kāi shǐ   zhǔn bèi   kǎo   研究所  de   jiàn   hàn
from  Freshman just Start    ready     examine 研究所 of  build Chinese
Chien-Han, who started to prepare for graduate school from the day he arrived
無時無刻  都  在  唸  書
wú shí wú kè   dōu   zài   niàn   shū
All the time  all  in   recite book
was studying twenty four seven.
幸  好  我們  還有  共  通  的話  題
xìng   hǎo   wǒ men   hái yǒu   gòng   tōng   de huà   tí
favor good us      and also all   common if      forehead
Luckily, we had some common interests to talk about.
是  不是  飯  島  愛  太  老了
shì   bù shì   fàn   dǎo   ài   tài   lǎo le
is   not     food island love very old
See, Iijima Ai is way too old.
奶  頭  都  黑  掉了
nǎi   tóu   dōu   hēi   diào le
milk head all  black Lost
Her tits have turned dark.
小  澤  圓  看起來  比較  可口
xiǎo   zé   yuán   kàn qǐ lái   bǐ jiào   kě kǒu
small marsh circle Looks like  Comparison tasty
Emmm... Madoza Ozawa looks hotter and yummier
大  浦  安  娜  也不  錯
dà   pǔ   ān   nà   yě bù   cuò
big shore peace elegant nor    error
Anna Ohura is not too bad, either
我  那邊  有  個  叫  人類  補  奸計  劃  的  好  東西
wǒ   nà biān   yǒu   ge   jiào   rén lèi   bǔ   jiān jì   huà   de   hǎo   dōng xi
I   there    have piece call  Humanity mend Treacherous divide of  good thing
I have some nice stuff called the Human Sex Program.
等一下  一起  看  啊
děng yī xià   yì qǐ   kàn   a
Wait         together look ah
Let's watch it together later.
看  卡  通人  物  做  愛  也  太  奇怪  了  吧
kàn   kǎ   通人  wù   zuò   ài   yě   tài   qí guài   le   ba
look card 通人 thing work love also very strange  is  !
Don't you think it's too weird to watch cartoon characters having sex?
還有  跟  狗  還有  跟  鰻  魚  的  咧
hái yǒu   gēn   gǒu   hái yǒu   gēn   mán   yú   de   liě
and also with dog  and also with eel  fish of  grimace
There're ones with dogs and eels, too.
那是  手機  還沒  普及  的  年代
nà shì   手機  hái méi   pǔ jí   de   nián dài
That is 手機 not yet  universal of  Age
That was the time before mobile phones were common.
到了  晚上  一堆  男  生  就  像  集體  中  邪  一樣
dào le   wǎn shàng   yī duī   nán   shēng   jiù   xiàng   集體  zhōng   xié   yī yàng
Arrived at night   pile    male life   just image  集體 central wrong same
At night, all the guys acted like they casted a spell.
在  公共  電話  前  大  排  長  龍
zài   gōng gòng   電話  qián   dà   pái   chǎng   lóng
in   public     電話 forward big row  long   dragon
Everyone one of us was lining up in front the telephone booth
小  可愛  我  好  想你  喔
xiǎo   kě ài   wǒ   hǎo   xiǎng nǐ   ō
small lovely I   good miss you  cry
I miss you so much my sweetie little pumpkin pie
每個  小時  都  固定  想你  十次  啊
měi gè   xiǎo shí   dōu   gù dìng   xiǎng nǐ   shí cì   a
Each one hour      all  fixed    miss you  ten times ah
I miss you 10 times every hour on a regular basis.
真的  啊
zhēn de   a
Really   ah
It's true.
那  你  有  沒有  好  想  我
nà   nǐ   yǒu   méi yǒu   hǎo   xiǎng   wǒ
that you have No       good think  I
So do you miss me this much, too?
一個  小時  想  幾  次
yī gè   xiǎo shí   xiǎng   jǐ   cì
One    hour      think  some order
How many times per hour?
有  沒有  十次
yǒu   méi yǒu   shí cì
have No       ten times
10 times at least?
喂
wèi
hey
Hey.
喂  你  還沒  睡  吧
wèi   nǐ   hái méi   shuì   ba
hey  you not yet  sleep !
You are not asleep yet, are you?
還沒  啊
hái méi   a
not yet  ah
No, not yet.
快  睡  啦
kuài   shuì   la
rapid sleep la
Go to sleep
每天  晚上  我  都  跟  沈  佳  宜  講  電話
měi tiān   wǎn shàng   wǒ   dōu   gēn   chén   jiā   yí   jiǎng   電話
every day at night   I   all  with sink  good suitable explain 電話
I talked to Shen Chia-Yi every night.
有  時  講到  她  睡著
yǒu   shí   jiǎng dào   tā   shuì zhe
have time Talked about she sleep
Sometimes, she fell asleep in the middle of our conversations.
有  時  講到  我  連  吃飯  的  錢  都  用  光  光
yǒu   shí   jiǎng dào   wǒ   lián   chī fàn   de   qián   dōu   yòng   guāng   guāng
have time Talked about I   join  eat      of  money all  use   light  light
Sometimes I spent all my money on phone calls and left no money for food.
迎  新  晚  會  下  禮拜  啊
yíng   xīn   wǎn   huì   xià   lǐ bài   a
receive new  night can  under worship ah
Welcome party? Next week.
下  禮拜
xià   lǐ bài
under worship
Next week.
那  我  跟  妳  說  喔
nà   wǒ   gēn   nai   shuō   ō
that I   with nǎi  speak cry
Listen.
妳  可不可以  不要  下去  跳舞
nai   kě bù kě yǐ   bù yào   xià qù   tiào wǔ
nǎi  can we       Do not  Go on   dancing
Can you please not dance with anyone?
不要  下去  跳舞  為什  麼
bù yào   xià qù   tiào wǔ   為什  me
Do not  Go on   dancing  為什 insignificant
Why not?
因為
yīn wèi
because
Because...
雖然  我  還沒  追到  妳  啊
suī rán   wǒ   hái méi   zhuī dào   nai   a
although I   not yet  Catch up  nǎi  ah
Ok, I know we are not seeing each other yet.
不過  那些  追  都  沒  追  過  妳  的  男  生
bù guò   nà xiē   zhuī   dōu   méi   zhuī   guò   nai   de   nán   shēng
but     those   pursue all  not  pursue pass nǎi  of  male life
But those guys who you don't even know.
怎麼  可以  牽  妳  的  手
zěn me   kě yǐ   qiān   nai   de   shǒu
how     can    drag  nǎi  of  hand
Can you not let them hold your hands?
我  自己  都  沒  牽  過  耶
wǒ   zì jǐ   dōu   méi   qiān   guò   yé
I   self   all  not  drag  pass ye
I haven't even held them myself.
那  你  呢
nà   nǐ   ne
that you this
What about you?
你  沒  下去  跳  啊
nǐ   méi   xià qù   tiào   a
you not  Go on   jump  ah
You didn't dance with anyone?
我  就  不  相信  你  沒有  牽  其他  女生  的  手
wǒ   jiù   bù   xiāng xìn   nǐ   méi yǒu   qiān   qí tā   nǚ shēng   de   shǒu
I   just no  Believe    you No       drag  other  Girls     of  hand
I don't believe you didn't hold any girl's hands.
是有  稍微  牽  一下  啦
shì yǒu   shāo wéi   qiān   yí xià   la
there is a little  drag  a bit   la
Oh, well... yeah, but only a little bit.
不過  那是  因為
bù guò   nà shì   yīn wèi
but     That is because
That's because...
我  把  對方  想  成  妳  啊
wǒ   bǎ   duì fāng   xiǎng   chéng   nai   a
I   take other side think  completed nǎi  ah
I imagined that she was you.
你  少  噁心  了  我  才不  相信  咧
nǐ   shǎo   ě xīn   le   wǒ   cái bù   xiāng xìn   liě
you few   nausea is  I   never   Believe    grimace
Oh please, I don't believe you.
真的  啦
zhēn de   la
Really   la
Really.
那  我  也可以  把  對方  想  成  是  你  啊
nà   wǒ   yě kě yǐ   bǎ   duì fāng   xiǎng   chéng   shì   nǐ   a
that I   Can also be take other side think  completed is   you ah
Then I can also imagine the guy I dance with was you.
不要  鬧  啦
bù yào   nào   la
Do not  quarrel la
No man, I'm for real.
好  啦  說  真的  喔
hǎo   la   shuō   zhēn de   ō
good la  speak Really   cry
All right, I am serious.
不可以  被  牽  喔
bù kě yǐ   bèi   qiān   ō
Can not   by   drag  cry
Don't let anyone hold your hands.
嗯  掰  掰
n   bāi   bāi
ń  rip  rip
Bye.
終於  上  大學  後  的  第一  個  聖誕  節  來了
zhōng wū   shàng   大學  hòu   de   dì yī   ge   shèng dàn   jié   lái le
at last   on     大學 after of  first  piece Christmas  holiday coming
Finally, it was the first Christmas after we entered college.
喂
wèi
hey
Hey.
我們  這樣  算  約會  嗎
wǒ men   zhè yàng   suàn   yuē huì   ma
us      such      count appointment ?
Is this considered a date?
幹  嘛  問  我
gàn   ma   wèn   wǒ
trunk ma  ask  I
Why ask me?
台北  怎麼  那麼  冷
tái běi   zěn me   nà me   lěng
Taipei   how     like that cold
Why is it so cold in Taipei?
換  我  換  我  快點
huàn   wǒ   huàn   wǒ   kuài diǎn
change I   change I   Faster
Hurry up, my turn for a picture!
快點  啦  快走  了
kuài diǎn   la   kuài zǒu   le
Faster     la  Brisk walking is
Hurry up! It's leaving.
沒有  拍  到
méi yǒu   pāi   dào
No       clap arrive
Oops, I didn't get it.
你
nǐ
you
You.
不要  跑
bù yào   pǎo
Do not  run
Come back.
柯  景  騰
kē   jǐng   téng
stalk scenery fly
Ko Ching-Teng.
你  真的  很  喜歡  我  嗎
nǐ   zhēn de   hěn   xǐ huan   wǒ   ma
you Really   very like     I   ?
Do you really like me a lot?
喜歡  啊
xǐ huan   a
like     ah
Yes, I do.
很  喜歡  啊
hěn   xǐ huan   a
very like     ah
Very much
我  總  覺得  你  把  我  想  得  太好了
wǒ   zǒng   jué de   nǐ   bǎ   wǒ   xiǎng   dé   tài hǎo le
I   collect feel    you take I   think  obtain Great
I always feel that you give me too much credit
我  根本  沒有  你  想  的  那麼  好
wǒ   gēn běn   méi yǒu   nǐ   xiǎng   de   nà me   hǎo
I   fundamental No       you think  of  like that good
I'm not as good as you think
你  喜歡  我  讓  我  覺得  有  點  怪  怪  的
nǐ   xǐ huan   wǒ   ràng   wǒ   jué de   yǒu   diǎn   guài   guài   de
you like     I   allow I   feel    have dot   strange strange of
I feel weird about the fact that you like me.
哪裡  奇怪
nǎ lǐ   qí guài
where  strange
What's so weird about it?
我  也會有  你  不知道  的  一面  啊
wǒ   yě huì yǒu   nǐ   bù zhī dào   de   yī miàn   a
I   There will be you do not know of  one side ah
There is another side of me that you don't know about
在家  裡  我  也會  很  邋  遢
zài jiā   lǐ   wǒ   yě huì   hěn   lā   tà
At home  inside I   Will also be very rags careless
I am very sloppy at home.
嗯  …
n   …
ń  …
Emm...
也會有  起  床  氣
yě huì yǒu   qǐ   chuáng   qì
There will be onward bed     air
I get very grumpy when I wake up early.
也會  因為  一點  小事  就  跟  我  妹  發脾氣
yě huì   yīn wèi   yī diǎn   xiǎo shì   jiù   gēn   wǒ   mèi   fā pí qì
Will also be because  a little Small matter just with I   younger sister loose the temper
And I get pissed off with my little sister at times just for minor stuff
我  就
wǒ   jiù
I   just
I am... you know.
很  普通  啊
hěn   pǔ tōng   a
very ordinary ah
Very ordinary.
說不定  你  喜歡  上  的
shuō bu dìng   nǐ   xǐ huan   shàng   de
maybe         you like     on     of
Maybe, the person that you like
只是  你  想像  出來  的  我
zhǐ shì   nǐ   xiǎng xiàng   chū lái   de   wǒ
just     you imagine      come out of  I
is in your imagination
我  沒  那麼  會想  像
wǒ   méi   nà me   huì xiǎng   xiàng
I   not  like that Would think image
I am not that imaginative.
真的
zhēn de
Really
Look.
你  仔細  想想
nǐ   zǐ xì   xiǎng xiǎng
you careful Think about it
Think carefully.
你  有  那麼  喜歡  我  嗎
nǐ   yǒu   nà me   xǐ huan   wǒ   ma
you have like that like     I   ?
Do you like me that much?
喜歡  啊
xǐ huan   a
like     ah
Hell yeah.
你  很  幼稚  耶
nǐ   hěn   yòu zhì   yé
you very naive    ye
You are so childish.
你  都  沒有  仔細  想
nǐ   dōu   méi yǒu   zǐ xì   xiǎng
you all  No       careful think
You didn't even think through it.
你  想  好再  跟  我  說
nǐ   xiǎng   hǎo zài   gēn   wǒ   shuō
you think  Good again with I   speak
Think about it carefully before you tell me.
沈  佳  宜  是  什麼  意思  呢
chén   jiā   yí   shì   shén me   yì si   ne
sink  good suitable is   what     meaning this
What did Shen Chia-Yi mean?
她是  不是  想  委  婉  的  拒絕  我  呢
tā shì   bù shì   xiǎng   wěi   wǎn   de   jù jué   wǒ   ne
She is  not     think  appoint amiable of  Refuse  I   this
Was she trying to turn me down in a nice way?
我  很  害怕
wǒ   hěn   hài pà
I   very Afraid
I was afraid.
一直  以來  我  都  以為  我  自己  是個  超  有  自信  的  人
yī zhí   yǐ lái   wǒ   dōu   yǐ wéi   wǒ   zì jǐ   shì gè   chāo   yǒu   zì xìn   de   rén
Always  since   I   all  think   I   self   Is      surpass have confidence of  man
For a long time, I always thought that I am a confident guy.
但  那  時  我  才  發現
dàn   nà   shí   wǒ   cái   fā xiàn
only that time I   talent Find
At that moment, I realized that
原來  在  喜歡  的  女孩  面前  我  是個  膽小  鬼
yuán lái   zài   xǐ huan   de   nǚ hái   miàn qián   wǒ   shì gè   dǎn xiǎo   guǐ
original  in   like     of  girl    before     I   Is      timid     ghost
I was really a coward in front of the girl I liked.
妳  許  什麼  願  啊
nai   xǔ   shén me   yuàn   a
nǎi  allow what     desire ah
What do you wish for?
自己  寫  自己  的  不可以  偷  看
zì jǐ   xiě   zì jǐ   de   bù kě yǐ   tōu   kàn
self   write self   of  Can not   burglar look
Write your own, no peeking.
這麼  小氣
zhè me   xiǎo qì
so      stingy
Come on, I just want to have a look.
沈  佳  宜
chén   jiā   yí
sink  good suitable
Shen Chia-Yi
我  很  喜歡  妳
wǒ   hěn   xǐ huan   nai
I   very like     nǎi
I like you very much
非常  喜歡  妳
fēi cháng   xǐ huan   nai
very much  like     nǎi
I like you a lot.
總有  一天  我  一定  要  追到  妳
zǒng yǒu   yī tiān   wǒ   yī dìng   yào   zhuī dào   nai
always    one day  I   for sure need Catch up  nǎi
One day you will be mine.
百分之  一千  萬  一定  會  追到  妳
bǎi fēn zhī   yī qiān   wàn   yī dìng   huì   zhuī dào   nai
percent      one thousand innumerable for sure can  Catch up  nǎi
One day, I will make you mine.
你  想  知道  答案  嗎
nǐ   xiǎng   zhī dào   dá àn   ma
you think  know     answer ?
Do you want to know the answer?
我  現在  就  可以  告訴  你
wǒ   xiàn zài   jiù   kě yǐ   gào su   nǐ
I   now       just can    tell    you
I can tell you right now.
不要
bù yào
Do not
No
我  沒有  問  妳
wǒ   méi yǒu   wèn   nai
I   No       ask  nǎi
I didn't ask you.
所以  妳  也不  可以  拒絕  我
suǒ yǐ   nai   yě bù   kě yǐ   jù jué   wǒ
and so  nǎi  nor    can    Refuse  I
So you can't turn me down.
你  真的  不想  知道
nǐ   zhēn de   bù xiǎng   zhī dào
you Really   Do not want to know
You really don't want to know?
拜  託  不要  現在  告訴  我
bài   tuō   bù yào   xiàn zài   gào su   wǒ
bow  entrust Do not  now       tell    I
Please don't tell me now.
請  讓  我  繼續  喜歡  妳
qǐng   ràng   wǒ   jì xù   xǐ huan   nai
ask   allow I   carry on like     nǎi
Just let me keep on liking you.
每一  個  男  生  都  想  在  自己  心  上  人面  前
měi yī   ge   nán   shēng   dōu   xiǎng   zài   zì jǐ   xīn   shàng   人面  qián
Each one piece male life   all  think  in   self   heart on     人面 forward
Every guy wants to show his strongest side.
展現  自己  最強  的  一面
zhǎn xiàn   zì jǐ   zuì qiáng   de   yī miàn
Show       self   strongest  of  one side
Especially in front of the girl he likes.
而  我  又  應該  展現  什麼  給  沈  佳  宜  看  呢
ér   wǒ   yòu   yīng gāi   zhǎn xiàn   shén me   gěi   chén   jiā   yí   kàn   ne
and I   and  should    Show       what     give sink  good suitable look this
So what should I show to Shen Chia-Yi?
我  想  了  很久  終於  有  一天  我  悟  出了  答案
wǒ   xiǎng   le   hěn jiǔ   zhōng wū   yǒu   yī tiān   wǒ   wù   chū le   dá àn
I   think  is  long time at last   have one day  I   realize Out     answer
It took me a long time before the answer suddenly hit me one day.
你  就  去  廁所  尿  尿  是  會  怎樣  啊
nǐ   jiù   qù   cè suǒ   niào   niào   shì   huì   zěn yàng   a
you just go  WC      urine urine is   can  how       ah
Why can't you just go pee in the toilet?
很  遠  耶
hěn   yuǎn   yé
very distant ye
Man, it's far.
你  要  出門  啊
nǐ   yào   chū mén   a
you need Go out   ah
Hey, are you going out?
順便  幫  我  拿去  倒  一下
shùn biàn   bāng   wǒ   ná qù   dào   yí xià
By the way assist I   Take it inverted a bit
Empty this for me on your way out, will you?
有  沒有  搞  錯  啊
yǒu   méi yǒu   gǎo   cuò   a
have No       clear error ah
You fucking serious?
幫  同  學  倒  尿  也是  友情  的  …
bāng   tóng   xué   dào   niào   yě shì   yǒu qíng   de   …
assist same  learning inverted urine Also too Friendship of  …
Come on, just do me a favor...
你們  不覺  得
nǐ men   不覺  dé
you     不覺 obtain
Don't you guys think.
是  時候  戰鬥  了  嗎
shì   shí hou   zhàn dòu   le   ma
is   time     fighting  is  ?
It's time to battle?
我們  來
wǒ men   lái
us      come
Come on.
打架  吧
dǎ jià   ba
fight   !
Let's fight
我  要  辦  比賽
wǒ   yào   bàn   bǐ sài
I   need manage game
I am organizing a competition.
有  沒有  人  要  參加  的
yǒu   méi yǒu   rén   yào   cān jiā   de
have No       man  need participate of
Anyone wants to join me?
有  沒有  人  要  參加  比賽
yǒu   méi yǒu   rén   yào   cān jiā   bǐ sài
have No       man  need participate game
Anyone wants to join the competition?
有  沒有  人  要  打架  的
yǒu   méi yǒu   rén   yào   dǎ jià   de
have No       man  need fight   of
Anyone wants to fight?
我  有  辦  打架  比賽
wǒ   yǒu   bàn   dǎ jià   bǐ sài
I   have manage fight   game
Fighting competition, anyone?
要  不要  參加  比賽
yào   bù yào   cān jiā   bǐ sài
need Do not  participate game
Do you want to fight in a competition?
要  不要  參加  格  鬥  比賽
yào   bù yào   cān jiā   gé   dòu   bǐ sài
need Do not  participate pattern struggle game
Do you want to fight in a combat tournament?
有  沒有  人  要  打架
yǒu   méi yǒu   rén   yào   dǎ jià
have No       man  need fight
Anyone wants to fight?
有  沒有  人  要
yǒu   méi yǒu   rén   yào
have No       man  need
Anyone wants to join?
我  可以  看完  嗎
wǒ   kě yǐ   kàn wán   ma
I   can    Read     ?
Can I stay until you guys finish?
一般  運動  有  什麼  了  不起
yī bān   yùn dòng   yǒu   shén me   le   bù qǐ
general sport     have what     is  Can not afford to
What's the big deal with the regular sports?
當然  自由  格  鬥  比較  屌  啊
dāng rán   zì yóu   gé   dòu   bǐ jiào   diao   a
of course free    pattern struggle Comparison diǎo  ah
Combat is definitely cooler.
真的  啦  妳  一定  要  來  看  喔
zhēn de   la   nai   yī dìng   yào   lái   kàn   ō
Really   la  nǎi  for sure need come look cry
Seriously, you have to be here
我  剛  已經  貼  出海  報  了
wǒ   gāng   yǐ jīng   tiē   chū hǎi   bào   le
I   hard  already  paste To the sea report is
I just put out posters.
到時候  一定  大  爆  滿
dào shí hou   yī dìng   dà   bào   mǎn
By the time  for sure big crackle fill
It's going to be a full house.
你  為什  麼  要  辦  這麼  危險  的  比賽
nǐ   為什  me   yào   bàn   zhè me   wéi xiǎn   de   bǐ sài
you 為什 insignificant need manage so      Danger    of  game
Why do you want to organize such a dangerous competition?
你們  學校  都  不用  唸  書  的  嗎
nǐ men   學校  dōu   bù yòng   niàn   shū   de   ma
you     學校 all  No need to recite book of  ?
Don't you guys need to study and look after your marks?
就是  因為  大家  都  只會  唸  書
jiù shì   yīn wèi   dà jiā   dōu   zhǐ huì   niàn   shū
That is  because  everyone all  Only will recite book
Exactly! People study way too hard.
所以  才  需要  運動  一下
suǒ yǐ   cái   xū yào   yùn dòng   yí xià
and so  talent need    sport     a bit
That's why they need to exercise
我  要  幫  他們  特  訓
wǒ   yào   bāng   tā men   tè   xùn
I   need assist they    special teach
I want to give them some trainings.
還不  就是  打架
hái bù   jiù shì   dǎ jià
Not yet That is  fight
It's just a fight.
這麼  說  也可以  啦
zhè me   shuō   yě kě yǐ   la
so      speak Can also be la
Fine, if you really want to put it that way
有  時候  我  真的  很不  瞭解  你
yǒu   shí hou   wǒ   zhēn de   hěn bù   liǎo jiě   nǐ
have time     I   Really   Very bad To understanding you
I really don't get you sometimes.
簡單  啦
jiǎn dān   la
simple    la
You can nail this easily
我  以為  大學  裡  都是  娘  炮
wǒ   yǐ wéi   大學  lǐ   dōu shì   niáng   pào
I   think   大學 inside Are all  mother cannon
I thought everyone in college was a pussy
我  錯了
wǒ   cuò le
I   wrong
I was wrong.
有  個  硬  漢  叫  建  偉
yǒu   ge   yìng   hàn   jiào   jiàn   wěi
have piece hard  Chinese call  build great
There was a tough guy named Chien-Wei.
他  是  胎  拳  社  的  副  主  將  黑  帶
tā   shì   tāi   quán   shè   de   fù   zhǔ   jiāng   hēi   dài
he  is   embryo fist  company of  assist master will   black take
He was the second chair of the taekwondo club, a black belt.
看起來  很  臭  屁
kàn qǐ lái   hěn   chòu   pì
Looks like  very smell fart
He looked cocky.
看起來  很  強
kàn qǐ lái   hěn   qiáng
Looks like  very strong
And he looked tough.
正合我意
zhèng hé wǒ yì
Coincide with me
Just the kind of guy that I was looking for.
比  照  天下  第一  武  道  大會  的  規定
bǐ   zhào   tiān xià   dì yī   wǔ   dào   dà huì   de   guī dìng
liken shine world     first  military path General Assembly of  Regulations
We follow the rules of the highest martial arts order in the world.
不可以  殺死  對方
bù kě yǐ   shā sǐ   duì fāng
Can not   Kill    other side
No killing.
不可以  出  界
bù kě yǐ   chū   jiè
Can not   leave boundary
You cannot go outside of the boundaries.
不可以  踢  小雞  雞
bù kě yǐ   tī   xiǎo jī   jī
Can not   kick chick    chickens
No kicking on penises.
倒地  後  數  到  十  沒有  爬起來  也  算  輸
dǎo dì   hòu   shù   dào   shí   méi yǒu   pá qǐ lái   yě   suàn   shū
Fell to the ground after number arrive ten  No       climb up   also count transport
You lose if you are knocked down and unableto get up after the referee counts to 10.
預備
yù bèi
preparation
Ready!
穿上
chuān shàng
Put on
Put it on.
三  小  啊
sān   xiǎo   a
three small ah
What the hell?
穿上  它  我  才敢  打你
chuān shàng   tā   wǒ   cái gǎn   dǎ nǐ
Put on       it  I   Dare to dare Beat you
Wear it so I know I won't kill you.
穿  你的  屁股  啦
chuān   nǐ de   pì gu   la
penetrate your   butt   la
Go fuck yourself.
開始
kāi shǐ
Start
Go
我  要  殺死  你
wǒ   yào   shā sǐ   nǐ
I   need Kill    you
I am going to kill you.
快  羚羊  拳
kuài   líng yáng   quán
rapid antelope   fist
Punch him with Gazelle punch.
站起來
zhàn qǐ lái
stand up
Stand up.
柯  騰
kē   téng
stalk fly
Ko-Teng.
趕快  啦
gǎn kuài   la
hurry up  la
Hurry up.
快  反擊
kuài   fǎn jí
rapid Counterattack
Fight back.
柯  騰  快  反擊
kē   téng   kuài   fǎn jí
stalk fly   rapid Counterattack
Ko-Teng, fight back.
打  他的  肝臟
dǎ   tā de   gān zàng
strike his    liver
Beat him up.
站起來  打  他  起來
zhàn qǐ lái   dǎ   tā   qǐ lái
stand up     strike he  stand up
Stand up and beat him, stand up.
1…2…3…4…5…6…7… One... Two... Three... Four... Five... Six... Seven.
柯  騰  站起來
kē   téng   zhàn qǐ lái
stalk fly   stand up
Ko-Teng stand up.
你  再不  起來
nǐ   zài bu   qǐ lái
you No again stand up
Stand up now.
我  就  要  數  完了  耶
wǒ   jiù   yào   shù   wán liǎo   yé
I   just need number Finished it ye
Time is running out.
柯  騰
kē   téng
stalk fly
Ko-Teng.
快  反擊
kuài   fǎn jí
rapid Counterattack
Fight back.
那  誰  好  正  喔
nà   sheí   hǎo   zhèng   ō
that who   good right  cry
Who is that? She's so hot.
剛剛  比賽  結束  的  時候  我  都  沒有  看到  妳
gāng gāng   bǐ sài   jié shù   de   shí hou   wǒ   dōu   méi yǒu   kàn dào   nai
just       game    End      of  time     I   all  No       see      nǎi
Hey! I didn't see you when the game was over
我  還  以為  被  打  昏  了  耶
wǒ   hái   yǐ wéi   bèi   dǎ   hūn   le   yé
I   still think   by   strike dusk is  ye
I thought I was knocked out...
妳  剛剛  有  看到  那  男  的  嗎
nai   gāng gāng   yǒu   kàn dào   nà   nán   de   ma
nǎi  just       have see      that male of  ?
Did you see that guy?
他  超  厲害  的  耶
tā   chāo   lì hài   de   yé
he  surpass Powerful of  ye
He kicked my ass so bad
我  一直  閃  不開  他的  腳
wǒ   yī zhí   shǎn   bù kāi   tā de   jiǎo
I   Always  flash not open his    foot
I couldn't get away from him.
很好  玩  嗎
hěn hǎo   wán   ma
well     joke ?
Was it fun?
還不  錯  啊
hái bù   cuò   a
Not yet error ah
Not bad!
妳  來  看  我  超  開心  的  耶
nai   lái   kàn   wǒ   chāo   kāi xīn   de   yé
nǎi  come look I   surpass Happy    of  ye
I was so excited when I saw you!
我  問你  很好  玩  嗎
wǒ   wèn nǐ   hěn hǎo   wán   ma
I   ask you well     joke ?
Answer my question, was it fun?
幹  嘛  啦
gàn   ma   la
trunk ma  la
Now what?
你  辦  這  什麼  奇怪  的  比賽  啊
nǐ   bàn   zhè   shén me   qí guài   de   bǐ sài   a
you manage this what     strange  of  game    ah
Why did you insist on organizing such a weird competition?
你  辦  這  比賽  的  意義  到底  在  哪裡
nǐ   bàn   zhè   bǐ sài   de   yì yì   dào dǐ   zài   nǎ lǐ
you manage this game    of  meaning in the end in   where
What's the meaning of it?
妳  不覺  得很  炫  嗎
nai   不覺  de hěn   xuàn   ma
nǎi  不覺 Very much shine ?
Don't you think it's super cool?
兩  個  男人  之間  一定  要  分  出  勝  負  那  種  …
liǎng   ge   nán rén   zhī jiān   yī dìng   yào   fēn   chū   shèng   fù   nà   zhǒng   …
two    piece man      between   for sure need divide leave victory load that seed   …
That kind of... win or lose between two men.
還不  就是  打架
hái bù   jiù shì   dǎ jià
Not yet That is  fight
It's just violence.
柯  景  騰
kē   jǐng   téng
stalk scenery fly
Ko Ching-Teng.
你  特地  辦  一個  比賽  把  自己  搞  受傷
nǐ   tè dì   bàn   yī gè   bǐ sài   bǎ   zì jǐ   gǎo   shòu shāng
you specially manage One    game    take self   clear Injured
You organized a game to get yourself hurt.
你  怎麼會  這麼  幼稚  啊
nǐ   zěn me huì   zhè me   yòu zhì   a
you how come    so      naive    ah
Why are you so childish?
幼稚
yòu zhì
naive
Childish?
對  就是  幼稚
duì   jiù shì   yòu zhì
to   That is  naive
Right, childish.
很  幼稚
hěn   yòu zhì
very naive
Very childish.
我  問你
wǒ   wèn nǐ
I   ask you
Let me ask you something.
你  辦  這  奇怪  的  比賽  到底  讓  你  學到  什麼
nǐ   bàn   zhè   qí guài   de   bǐ sài   dào dǐ   ràng   nǐ   xué dào   shén me
you manage this strange  of  game    in the end allow you Learned  what
What exactly did you learn from this game?
學
xué
learning
"Learn"?
不  見  得  做什麼  事情  都  一定  要  學到  什麼  吧
bù   jiàn   dé   zuò shén me   shì qíng   dōu   yī dìng   yào   xué dào   shén me   ba
no  see   obtain doing what   thing     all  for sure need Learned  what     !
Why do I have to learn something from everything that I do?
至少  讓  你  學到  了  辦  這  種  比賽  會  受傷
zhì shǎo   ràng   nǐ   xué dào   le   bàn   zhè   zhǒng   bǐ sài   huì   shòu shāng
at least  allow you Learned  is  manage this seed   game    can  Injured
At least you learned that having a competition like this will get yourself hurt.
而  受  這  種  傷  一點  必要  都  沒有
ér   shòu   zhè   zhǒng   shāng   yī diǎn   bì yào   dōu   méi yǒu
and receive this seed   wound  a little necessary all  No
And it is totally unnecessary.
你  真的  很  幼稚
nǐ   zhēn de   hěn   yòu zhì
you Really   very naive
You are so childish.
你  身上  的  傷  我  只能  說是  你  活  該
nǐ   shēn shang   de   shāng   wǒ   zhǐ néng   shuō shì   nǐ   huó   gāi
you Body        of  wound  I   Can only  Said to be you live should
See those bruises on your face? You deserve it
我  幼稚
wǒ   yòu zhì
I   naive
I am childish?
妳  知  不知道  這  格  鬥  賽  對  我  來說  是  很  棒  的  經驗  啊
nai   zhī   bù zhī dào   zhè   gé   dòu   sài   duì   wǒ   lái shuō   shì   hěn   bàng   de   jīng yàn   a
nǎi  know do not know this pattern struggle compete to   I   For example is   very stick of  experience ah
Do you know this competition is a fantastic experience for me?
妳  可不可以  單純  替  我  高興  就  好啊
nai   kě bù kě yǐ   dān chún   tì   wǒ   gāo xìng   jiù   hǎo a
nǎi  can we       simple    change I   happy     just Okay
Can't you just be happy for me?
你  以後  還要  辦  這  種  比賽
nǐ   yǐ hòu   hái yào   bàn   zhè   zhǒng   bǐ sài
you after   But also manage this seed   game
So you are going to do it again?
當然  要  辦  啊
dāng rán   yào   bàn   a
of course need manage ah
Of course I will do it again.
為什  麼不  辦
為什  me bù   bàn
為什 Why not? manage
Why not?
幼稚
yòu zhì
naive
Grow up will you?
妳  為什  麼  總要  否定  對  我  很  重要  的  東西  呀
nai   為什  me   zǒng yào   fǒu dìng   duì   wǒ   hěn   zhòng yào   de   dōng xi   ya
nǎi  為什 insignificant Eventually negative  to   I   very important  of  thing    yeah
Why do you always look down on things that matter to me?
對  你  很  重要  的  東西  竟然是  讓  你  傷害  你  自己  嗎
duì   nǐ   hěn   zhòng yào   de   dōng xi   jìng rán shì   ràng   nǐ   shāng hài   nǐ   zì jǐ   ma
to   you very important  of  thing    Turned out to be allow you hurt       you self   ?
Things that matter to you are things that hurt you?
對  啦
duì   la
to   la
Fine
我  就是  幼稚
wǒ   jiù shì   yòu zhì
I   That is  naive
I am childish.
才會  追  妳  這  種  努力  用  功  讀書  的  女生
cái huì   zhuī   nai   zhè   zhǒng   nǔ lì   yòng   gōng   dú shū   de   nǚ shēng
Will only pursue nǎi  this seed   Effort use   achievement reading of  Girls
And that's why I would go after such a good school girl like you
我  就是  幼稚  才有  辦法  追  妳  這麼  久
wǒ   jiù shì   yòu zhì   cái yǒu   bàn fǎ   zhuī   nai   zhè me   jiǔ
I   That is  naive    Only have Method  pursue nǎi  so      long
I am this naive so I could chase you for so long.
那  你  就  不要  追  了  啊
nà   nǐ   jiù   bù yào   zhuī   le   a
that you just Do not  pursue is  ah
Stop trying then.
笨  蛋
bèn   dàn
foolish eggs
Idiot.
對  啦  我  就是  笨  蛋  啦
duì   la   wǒ   jiù shì   bèn   dàn   la
to   la  I   That is  foolish eggs la
Right! I am an idiot.
大  笨  蛋
dà   bèn   dàn
big foolish eggs
Moron.
大  笨  蛋  才能  追  妳  那麼  久
dà   bèn   dàn   cái néng   zhuī   nai   nà me   jiǔ
big foolish eggs Ability to pursue nǎi  like that long
Only a moron can keep on trying to chase after you for such a long time.
你  什麼  都  不懂
nǐ   shén me   dōu   bù dǒng
you what     all  Do not understand
You don't understand anything.
我  就是  什麼  都  不懂  啦
wǒ   jiù shì   shén me   dōu   bù dǒng   la
I   That is  what     all  Do not understand la
No, I don't understand anything.
成長  最  殘酷  的  部  份  就是
chéng zhǎng   zuì   cán kù   de   bù   fèn   jiù shì
growing up   most cruel   of  part portion That is
The cruelest part in “growing up”
女孩  永遠  比  同年  齡  的  男孩  成熟
nǚ hái   yǒng yuǎn   bǐ   tóng nián   líng   de   nán hái   chéng shú
girl    forever    liken same year  age   of  boy      mature
is that girls are always more mature than guys of the same age.
女孩  的  成熟  沒有  一個  男孩  招架  得住
nǚ hái   de   chéng shú   méi yǒu   yī gè   nán hái   招架  得住
girl    of  mature     No       One    boy      招架 得住
No guys can handle girls at their age.
大  吵  一  架
dà   chǎo   yī   jià
big argue one rack
What? A big fight?
所以  這  次  吵  完  架  就  不會  在一起  了  喔
suǒ yǐ   zhè   cì   chǎo   wán   jià   jiù   bù huì   zài yī qǐ   le   ō
and so  this order argue complete rack just will not Together   is  cry
Does that mean you are not going to be a couple after this?
你  有  什麼  毛病  啊
nǐ   yǒu   shén me   máo bìng   a
you have what     Faulty    ah
What's your problem?
真的  假  的  不  打算  和  好
zhēn de   jiǎ   de   bù   dǎ suàn   hàn   hǎo
Really   falsehood of  no  intend   and  good
For real? Not plans of making up?
也就  是說  我  有  機會  囉
yě jiù   是說  wǒ   yǒu   jī huì   luō
Also    是說 I   have opportunity nag
Oh yes, so I have a chance now?
老  曹  自  以為  熱  血
lǎo   cáo   zì   yǐ wéi   rè   xiè
old  surname self think   hot blood
Tsao took off right away on his motorcycle
騎著  摩托車  從  台  南  直接  衝  到  台北
qí zhe   摩托車  cóng   tái   nán   zhí jiē   chōng   dào   tái běi
Ride on 摩托車 from  platform south direct   rush   arrive Taipei
and rode from Tainan to Taipei.
準備  跟  沈  佳  宜  告  白
zhǔn bèi   gēn   chén   jiā   yí   gào   bái
ready     with sink  good suitable tell white
He was ready to confess his love to Shen Chia-Yi.
阿  和  則  買  了  最近  一  班  的  火車  票
ā   hàn   zé   mǎi   le   zuì jìn   yī   bān   de   huǒ chē   piào
a  and  rule buy  is  recent   one class of  train    ticket
A-Ho, on the other hand, bought a ticket for the next train.
結論  是
jié lùn   shì
in conclusion is
It turned out that
火車  比較  快
huǒ chē   bǐ jiào   kuài
train    Comparison rapid
the train is faster
雖然  我們  一直  很有  話  聊
suī rán   wǒ men   yī zhí   hěn yǒu   huà   liáo
although us      Always  Very much speech somewhat
I know we have always been good friends.
可是  其實  我  早就  知道  你  喜歡  的  是  柯  騰
kě shì   qí shí   wǒ   zǎo jiù   zhī dào   nǐ   xǐ huan   de   shì   kē   téng
but     in fact I   Long ago know     you like     of  is   stalk fly
But somehow I always knew that Ko-Teng is the one.
我  一直  學  不會  的  事
wǒ   yī zhí   xué   bù huì   de   shì
I   Always  learning will not of  thing
Being childish is something that
就是  你  最  討厭  的  幼稚
jiù shì   nǐ   zuì   tǎo yàn   de   yòu zhì
That is  you most hate     of  naive
I can never learn.
可是  每次  你  罵  柯  騰  幼稚  的  時候  我  都  很  嫉妒
kě shì   měi cì   nǐ   mà   kē   téng   yòu zhì   de   shí hou   wǒ   dōu   hěn   jí dù
but     Each    you accuse stalk fly   naive    of  time     I   all  very Jealousy
Even though you said you hate childish guys.
因為  其實  你  罵  他  幼稚  的  時候
yīn wèi   qí shí   nǐ   mà   tā   yòu zhì   de   shí hou
because  in fact you accuse he  naive    of  time
Every time when you called Ko-Teng childish
真的  很  漂亮
zhēn de   hěn   piào liang
Really   very Pretty
I can tell how much you likethat childishness in him.
你  跟  我  說這  些  做什麼
nǐ   gēn   wǒ   shuō zhè   xiē   zuò shén me
you with I   Say this  some doing what
Why are you telling me this now?
如果  我  什麼  都  不做
rú guǒ   wǒ   shén me   dōu   bù zuò
in case I   what     all  Do not do
If I don't do anything now
你們  遲早會  和  好
nǐ men   chí zǎo huì   hàn   hǎo
you     Sooner or later and  good
you guys will get back together eventually.
對不對
duì bù duì
right
Right?
對不起
duì bù qǐ
I am sorry
I am sorry.
這  一次  我  想  趁  人  之  危
zhè   yī cì   wǒ   xiǎng   chèn   rén   zhī   wēi
this once   I   think  rip off man  it   dangerous
Since you guys are not in good terms now, I would like to take my chances.
看見  那個  畫  面  老  曹  的  機  車  重新  發動  繼續  往前
kàn jiàn   nà gè   huà   miàn   lǎo   cáo   de   jī   chē   chóng xīn   fā dòng   jì xù   wǎng qián
see       that one draw face  old  surname of  machine cart Reappear   launch   carry on Forward
When Tsao saw A-Ho and Shen Chia-Yi walked across the street, he took off again.
這  一次  他  不知不覺  就  繞  了  台灣  整整  一圈
zhè   yī cì   tā   bù zhī bù jué   jiù   rào   le   tái wān   zhěng zhěng   yī quān
this once   he  unconsciously  just around is  Taiwan   full         A circle
This time, he rode his way around the whole island.
老  曹  繞  回  台  南  時
lǎo   cáo   rào   huí   tái   nán   shí
old  surname around return platform south time
When Tsao made it to Tainan
因為  恍  神  醒來  已經  騎  到了  嘉  義
yīn wèi   huǎng   shén   xǐng lái   yǐ jīng   qí   dào le   jiā   yì
because  seemingly god   wake up   already  ride Arrived excellent righteousness
he took the wrong exit so he went straight to Chiayi.
於是  老  曹  乾脆  又  繼續  往上  騎  再接  再  厲  又  繞  了  台灣  一圈
wū shì   lǎo   cáo   gān cuì   yòu   jì xù   wǎng shàng   qí   zài jiē   zài   lì   yòu   rào   le   tái wān   yī quān
then    old  surname simply   and  carry on Go up       ride Re-connect again whetstone and  around is  Taiwan   A circle
Then he thought why not just take another round around Taiwan.
不過  這  次  他  在  中  途  停下來  載  我
bù guò   zhè   cì   tā   zài   zhōng   tú   tíng xià lái   zài   wǒ
but     this order he  in   central way stop          load I
This time, he stopped to picked me up.
幹  嘛
gàn   ma
trunk ma
What?
操
cāo
conduct
Fuck.
幹  嘛
gàn   ma
trunk ma
What do you want?
還  手  啦
hái   shǒu   la
still hand  la
Hit me back.
你  以為  我  想  啊
nǐ   yǐ wéi   wǒ   xiǎng   a
you think   I   think  ah
What's your freaking problem?
白  癡  耶
bái   chī   yé
white silly ye
Idiot?
失  戀  了
shī   liàn   le
lose love  is
I was heart broken
我  失去  了  沈  佳  宜
wǒ   shī qù   le   chén   jiā   yí
I   lose    is  sink  good suitable
I had lost Shen Chia-Yi.
我  的  青春  什麼  都  不  剩  了
wǒ   de   qīng chūn   shén me   dōu   bù   shèng   le
I   of  youth      what     all  no  leftovers is
There was nothing left in me
失  戀  那  幾個  月  我  認識  了  很多  女生
shī   liàn   nà   jǐ gè   yuè   wǒ   rèn shi   le   hěn duō   nǚ shēng
lose love  that several moon I   understanding is  a lot of Girls
I met quite a lot of girls after I lost Shen Chia-Yi.
只是  那些  女生  的  名字  清  一  色  都是  四個  字
zhǐ shì   nà xiē   nǚ shēng   de   míng zì   qīng   yī   sè   dōu shì   sì gè   zì
just     those   Girls     of  first name clear one color Are all  Four   letter
It's just that they all happened to be Japanese.
為此  我  感到  相當  空虛
wèi cǐ   wǒ   gǎn dào   xiāng dāng   kōng xū
to this end I   feel     quite       emptiness
For that, I felt there was something missing in my heart.
櫻  木  花  道  說  的  好
yīng   mù   huā   dào   shuō   de   hǎo
cherry tree flower path speak of  good
Sakuragi Hanamichi was right.
左手  只是  輔助
zuǒ shǒu   zhǐ shì   fǔ zhù
Left hand just     Auxiliary
You can only use one hand, your left hand.
因為  右手  要  拿  滑  鼠
yīn wèi   yòu shǒu   yào   ná   huá   shǔ
because  Right hand need take slip rat
Because you need your right hand on the mouse.
我們  這樣  每天  打  手  槍  到底有  什麼  意義
wǒ men   zhè yàng   měi tiān   dǎ   shǒu   qiāng   dào dǐ yǒu   shén me   yì yì
us      such      every day strike hand  spear  In the end there is what     meaning
What's the point of us masturbating all day long?
意義  是  蝦  小
yì yì   shì   xiā   xiǎo
meaning is   shrimp small
Who cares?
林  北  只  聽過  精液
lín   běi   zhǐ   tīng guò   jīng yè
forest north only Heard of it semen
As long as I get to ejaculate, who cares!
沒  聽過  意義
méi   tīng guò   yì yì
not  Heard of it meaning
I am coming, I am coming, I AM COMING!
現在  光是  大學  畢  業  已經  不夠
xiàn zài   guāng shì   大學  bì   yè   yǐ jīng   bù gòu
now       just       大學 end profession already  not enough
Even though getting a diploma might not be crucial
雖然  說  學  歷  並不  代表  一切
suī rán   shuō   xué   lì   bìng bù   dài biǎo   yī qiè
although speak learning past And not  representative all
but a bachelor degree seems to be not enough
我  跟  阿  和  之間  有  很長  一段  時間  沒有  聯絡
wǒ   gēn   ā   hàn   zhī jiān   yǒu   hěn zhǎng   yī duàn   shí jiān   méi yǒu   lián luò
I   with a  and  between   have very long  A paragraph time      No       connection
I admit that I might be childish, just like how Shen Chia-Yi described me.
面對  自己  的  好  朋友
miàn duì   zì jǐ   de   hǎo   péng yǒu
face      self   of  good friend
A-Ho has been a really good friend of mine.
卻  連  裝  一下  祝福  的  語氣  都  覺得  勉強
què   lián   zhuāng   yí xià   zhù fú   de   yǔ qì   dōu   jué de   miǎn qiáng
still join  dress   a bit   blessing of  Tone   all  feel    reluctantly
But I just couldn't bring myself to congratulate him.
雖然  我們  現在  念  不同  的  大學
suī rán   wǒ men   xiàn zài   niàn   bù tóng   de   大學
although us      now       recall different of  大學
It'd be nice to plan things ahead.
可是  我們  可以  討論  看看  研究所  的  方向
kě shì   wǒ men   kě yǐ   tǎo lùn   kàn kàn   研究所  de   fāng xiàng
but     us      can    discuss  Look at it 研究所 of  direction
We should start thinking about graduate schools.
如果  說  妳  是  真的  想  當  老師  的話
rú guǒ   shuō   nai   shì   zhēn de   xiǎng   dāng   lǎo shī   de huà
in case speak nǎi  is   Really   think  that  teacher  if
If you really want to be a teacher.
那  我  建議  妳  可以  去  選  教育  研究所
nà   wǒ   jiàn yì   nai   kě yǐ   qù   xuǎn   jiào yù   研究所
that I   Suggest  nǎi  can    go  choose education 研究所
Then getting a Master of education would be nice.
這樣  子  以後  月  薪  也可以  多  一點  嘛  幾千塊  錢  吧  至少
zhè yàng   zi   yǐ hòu   yuè   xīn   yě kě yǐ   duō   yī diǎn   ma   jǐ qiān kuài   qián   ba   zhì shǎo
such      offspring after   moon fuel Can also be much a little ma  Thousands of pieces money !   at least
At least people will pay you more in the future.
阿  和  和  沈  佳  宜  只  在一起  短短  的  五個  月
ā   hàn   hàn   chén   jiā   yí   zhǐ   zài yī qǐ   duǎn duǎn   de   wǔ gè   yuè
a  and  and  sink  good suitable only Together   Short      of  Five   moon
A-Ho was with Shen Chia-Yi for only five months.
不過  那  也  夠  讓  我  嫉妒  的  了
bù guò   nà   yě   gòu   ràng   wǒ   jí dù   de   le
but     that also enough allow I   Jealousy of  is
But that was more than enough to make me jealous like hell.
幹  有  鬼  啊
gàn   yǒu   guǐ   a
trunk have ghost ah
Fuck, what's happening?
靠北  啊
kào běi   a
By North ah
Shit.
有  鬼  啊  有  鬼  啊
yǒu   guǐ   a   yǒu   guǐ   a
have ghost ah have ghost ah
Fuck, what's going on!
快  閃  啊  閃  啊  有  鬼  啊  有  鬼  殺  來了
kuài   shǎn   a   shǎn   a   yǒu   guǐ   a   yǒu   guǐ   shā   lái le
rapid flash ah flash ah have ghost ah have ghost kill coming
Ghost! Ghost! Let's get the hell out of here!
鬼  在  哪裡  鬼  在  哪裡
guǐ   zài   nǎ lǐ   guǐ   zài   nǎ lǐ
ghost in   where  ghost in   where
Shit... ghost? Where? Where?
太  扯  了
tài   chě   le
very raise is
This is crazy, man!
我  媽媽  說  我  家  附近  的  旅館  整個  倒下  來
wǒ   mā mā   shuō   wǒ   jiā   fù jìn   de   旅館  zhěng gè   dào xià   lái
I   mum    speak I   house nearby  of  旅館 entire    Fall down come
My mom just called and said that the hotel next to my house just collapsed.
你  家  不是  在  台北  嗎
nǐ   jiā   bù shì   zài   tái běi   ma
you house not     in   Taipei   ?
You are from Taipei, aren't you?
震  央  在  台北
zhèn   yāng   zài   tái běi
shake center in   Taipei
So the epicenter is in Taipei?
這裡  人  太多  了  基  地  台  超  載
zhè lǐ   rén   tài duō   le   jī   dì   tái   chāo   zài
Here    man  too much is  foundation land platform surpass load
It's too crowded here, the system is probably overloaded.
人  少  的  地方  搞  不好  才會  通  耶
rén   shǎo   de   dì fāng   gǎo   bù hǎo   cái huì   tōng   yé
man  few   of  place    clear not good Will only common ye
Try to give it a shot at somewhere less crowded.
這  理論  對  嗎
zhè   lǐ lùn   duì   ma
this theory  to   ?
Are you sure?
不知道
bù zhī dào
do not know
I don't know.
喂
wèi
hey
Hello.
柯  騰  啊
kē   téng   a
stalk fly   ah
Ko-Teng?
我  沒事
wǒ   méi shì
I   Nothing
I am safe, don't worry.
可  街上  都是  人  耶
kě   jiē shàng   dōu shì   rén   yé
may Street     Are all  man  ye
Everyone is out on the street, though.
嚇  死  我  了
xià   sǐ   wǒ   le
scare die I   is
Thank god
我  剛  聽說  震  央  在  台北
wǒ   gāng   tīng shuō   zhèn   yāng   zài   tái běi
I   hard  heard      shake center in   Taipei
I heard that the epicenter is in Taipei.
整個  旅館  都  垮  下來
zhěng gè   旅館  dōu   kuǎ   xià lái
entire    旅館 all  fail Down
And the whole building collapsed
總之
zǒng zhī
In short
anyway.
你  沒事  就  好
nǐ   méi shì   jiù   hǎo
you Nothing  just good
Good to hear that you are safe.
謝謝
xiè xiè
Thank you
Thank you.
那
nà
that
Alright then
沒事  我  就  …
méi shì   wǒ   jiù   …
Nothing  I   just …
better go.
我  很  感動
wǒ   hěn   gǎn dòng
I   very Moving
Wait a minute
真的
zhēn de
Really
I am touched, really.
妳  感動  個  頭  啦
nai   gǎn dòng   ge   tóu   la
nǎi  Moving    piece head la
Yeah right.
妳  可是  我  追  了  N  年  的  女生  耶
nai   kě shì   wǒ   zhuī   le   N  nián   de   nǚ shēng   yé
nǎi  but     I   pursue is  N year  of  Girls     ye
You are the girl that I chased for years!
要是  妳  不  見了
yào shi   nai   bù   見了
if       nǎi  no  見了
Who else is going to share this memory with me
我  找  誰  回憶  我們  的  故事  啊
wǒ   zhǎo   sheí   huí yì   wǒ men   de   gù shì   a
I   search who   Memories us      of  story   ah
if you are gone.
你  還說  呢
nǐ   hái shuō   ne
you Said      this
Hey, come on.
這  兩年  你  都  沒  打  給  我
zhè   liǎng nián   nǐ   dōu   méi   dǎ   gěi   wǒ
this Two years   you all  not  strike give I
You didn't even try to contact me in the past two years.
你  也沒  打  給  我  好不好
nǐ   yě méi   dǎ   gěi   wǒ   hǎo bù hǎo
you also not strike give I   ok
You didn't call either.
真  敢  講
zhēn   gǎn   jiǎng
real  venture explain
How dare you mention it.
那  妳  最近  都  在  幹  嘛
nà   nai   zuì jìn   dōu   zài   gàn   ma
that nǎi  recent   all  in   trunk ma
So, what have you been doing lately?
沒  幹  嘛  啊
méi   gàn   ma   a
not  trunk ma  ah
Nothing much, really.
還不  就  上  課  唸  書
hái bù   jiù   shàng   kè   niàn   shū
Not yet just on     lesson recite book
Same old thing, studying.
那  你  呢
nà   nǐ   ne
that you this
What about you?
你  該  不會  常  翹  課  吧
nǐ   gāi   bù huì   cháng   qiào   kè   ba
you should will not common lift  lesson !
Still skipping classes?
當然  啊
dāng rán   a
of course ah
Of course
我  本來  就  不喜歡  唸  書  啊
wǒ   běn lái   jiù   bù xǐ huan   niàn   shū   a
I   originally just dislike     recite book ah
I never liked studying anyway
我  是  為了  妳  才  念  的  耶
wǒ   shì   wèi le   nai   cái   niàn   de   yé
I   is   in order to nǎi  talent recall of  ye
I only studied because of you.
哇  說  的  這麼  好聽
wa   shuō   de   zhè me   hǎo tīng
vomit speak of  so      Nice
Wow! So sweet.
那天  晚上  我們  聊  了  很多  回憶
nèi tiān   wǎn shàng   wǒ men   liáo   le   hěn duō   huí yì
That day  at night   us      somewhat is  a lot of Memories
We had a long chat that night, talking about the old days.
好多  好多  用  功  讀書  只為了  更  靠近  她  的  日子
hǎo duō   hǎo duō   yòng   gōng   dú shū   zhǐ wèi le   gèng   kào jìn   tā   de   rì zi
many     many     use   achievement reading Just for    more  near     she of  day
The old days when I tried everything to get closer to her.
那  妳  有  男朋友  了  嗎
nà   nai   yǒu   nán péng yǒu   le   ma
that nǎi  have boyfriend     is  ?
So, do you have a boyfriend now?
要  你  管  啊
yào   nǐ   guǎn   a
need you manage ah
It's none of your business.
我
wǒ
I
I...um...
後來  跟  阿  和  在一起  過
hòu lái   gēn   ā   hàn   zài yī qǐ   guò
later    with a  and  Together   pass
I... was with A-Ho for a while
我  知道  啊
wǒ   zhī dào   a
I   know     ah
I know
我  有  聽  他  說
wǒ   yǒu   tīng   tā   shuō
I   have hear  he  speak
I heard.
但  後來  為什  麼分  手
dàn   hòu lái   為什  me fēn   shǒu
only later    為什 What points hand
Why did you guys split up?
我  一直  不想  問  他  想到  就  度  爛
wǒ   yī zhí   bù xiǎng   wèn   tā   xiǎng dào   jiù   dù   làn
I   Always  Do not want to ask  he  think      just degree rotten
I didn't want to ask him cause that just made me want to kick his ass.
他  對  妳  不好  嗎
tā   duì   nai   bù hǎo   ma
he  to   nǎi  not good ?
Was he mean to you?
也不  是
yě bù   shì
nor    is
Not really
我  只是  覺得  阿  和  不夠  喜歡  我
wǒ   zhǐ shì   jué de   ā   hàn   bù gòu   xǐ huan   wǒ
I   just     feel    a  and  not enough like     I
I just felt that he didn't like me that much.
阿  和  很  喜歡  妳
ā   hàn   hěn   xǐ huan   nai
a  and  very like     nǎi
No, A-Ho was crazy about you, head over heels!
被  你  喜歡  過  很難  覺得  別人  有  那麼  喜歡  我
bèi   nǐ   xǐ huan   guò   hěn nán   jué de   bié rén   yǒu   nà me   xǐ huan   wǒ
by   you like     pass It is difficult feel    other people have like that like     I
Having being loved by you makes it harder for me to feel other's love.
哇  這麼  感  人  啊
wa   zhè me   gǎn   rén   a
vomit so      feel man  ah
You are kidding me right?
你  不要  破壞  氣  氛  喔  現在
nǐ   bù yào   pò huài   qì   fēn   ō   xiàn zài
you Do not  damage   air gas  cry now
Don't ruin it now.
沈  佳  宜
chén   jiā   yí
sink  good suitable
Hey, Shen Chia-Yi.
我  可不可以  問  妳
wǒ   kě bù kě yǐ   wèn   nai
I   can we       ask  nǎi
Can I ask you a question?
為什  麼  當時  沒有  想要  和  我  在一起  啊
為什  me   dāng shí   méi yǒu   xiǎng yào   hàn   wǒ   zài yī qǐ   a
為什 insignificant then      No       Want to    and  I   Together   ah
Why didn't you want to be with me at that time?
常常  聽到  人家  說  啊
cháng cháng   tīng dào   rén jiā   shuō   a
often        Hear it   People   speak ah
You know...
戀愛  最美  好  的  時候
liàn ài   zuì měi   hǎo   de   shí hou
in love  most beautiful good of  time
People always say that the most wonderful time of a relationship
就是  暖  昧  的  時候
jiù shì   nuǎn   mèi   de   shí hou
That is  warm  obscure of  time
happens before it really happens.
等到  真正  在一起  了
děng dào   zhēn zhèng   zài yī qǐ   le
wait until real        Together   is
When two people are together.
很多  感覺  都  會  消失  不  見
hěn duō   gǎn jué   dōu   huì   xiāo shī   bù   jiàn
a lot of feel     all  can  disappear no  see
The magic vanishes easily.
所以  我  就  想  乾脆  就  讓  你  再  追  我  久  一點
suǒ yǐ   wǒ   jiù   xiǎng   gān cuì   jiù   ràng   nǐ   zài   zhuī   wǒ   jiǔ   yī diǎn
and so  I   just think  simply   just allow you again pursue I   long a little
So I thought it'd be better if I let you chase me longer.
不然  等  你  追到  我  之後  就  變  懶  了  那  我  不是  很  虧  嗎
bù rán   děng   nǐ   zhuī dào   wǒ   zhī hòu   jiù   biàn   lǎn   le   nà   wǒ   bù shì   hěn   kuī   ma
otherwise wait  you Catch up  I   after that just change lazy is  that I   not     very lose ?
Otherwise, if we got together right away, it'd be less fun.
妳  真的  很  雞  巴  耶
nai   zhēn de   hěn   jī   bā   yé
nǎi  Really   very chickens desire ye
Man, that's slack!
沈  佳  宜
chén   jiā   yí
sink  good suitable
Shen Chia-Yi.
妳  相信  有  平  行  時  空  嗎
nai   xiāng xìn   yǒu   píng   xíng   shí   kōng   ma
nǎi  Believe    have peace go    time empty ?
Do you believe in parallel universe?
也許  在  那個  平  行  時  空  裡  我們  是  在一起  的
yě xǔ   zài   nà gè   píng   xíng   shí   kōng   lǐ   wǒ men   shì   zài yī qǐ   de
Maybe  in   that one peace go    time empty inside us      is   Together   of
Maybe in that universe, we are together.
真  羨慕  他們  啊
zhēn   xiàn mù   tā men   a
real  envy     they    ah
How I envy them.
謝謝你  喜歡  我
xiè xiè nǐ   xǐ huan   wǒ
thank you   like     I
Thank you for liking me.
我  也  很  喜歡
wǒ   yě   hěn   xǐ huan
I   also very like
Yes.
當年  喜歡  妳  的  我
dāng nián   xǐ huan   nai   de   wǒ
then       like     nǎi  of  I
Thank you for letting me like you in those years.
妳  永遠  是  我  眼中  的  蘋果
nai   yǒng yuǎn   shì   wǒ   yǎn zhōng   de   píng guǒ
nǎi  forever    is   I   Eyes       of  apple
You are always the apple of my eye.
大  四  了
dà   sì   le
big four is
Then it came to Senior year.
我  身邊  的  每一  個人  都  在  準備  考  研究所
wǒ   shēn biān   de   měi yī   gè rén   dōu   zài   zhǔn bèi   kǎo   研究所
I   Around     of  Each one people  all  in   ready     examine 研究所
Everyone around me was preparing for grad schools
我  不曉得  我  將來  想做  什麼
wǒ   bù xiǎo de   wǒ   jiāng lái   xiǎng zuò   shén me
I   do not know I   future     Want to do it what
I had no idea what I wanted to do at that time.
可是  每個人  都  在  唸  書  弄得  我  很  緊張
kě shì   měi gè rén   dōu   zài   niàn   shū   nòng de   wǒ   hěn   緊張
but     everyone    all  in   recite book Confused I   very 緊張
Everyone was studying so hard and it made me nervous.
只好  跟著  大家  一起  跑  圖書館
zhǐ hǎo   gēn zhe   dà jiā   yì qǐ   pǎo   圖書館
Had to   Follow   everyone together run  圖書館
So I decided to join them in the library.
但  莫名  其  妙  的  我  卻  開始  在  網路  上  寫  起了  小說
dàn   mò míng   qí   miào   de   wǒ   què   kāi shǐ   zài   網路  shàng   xiě   qǐ le   小說
only Inexplicable his mysterious of  I   still Start    in   網路 on     write get up 小說
And out of the blue, I started to write stories on my blog.
老  曹  退  伍  後  沒去  美國  打  NBA
lǎo   cáo   tuì   wǔ   hòu   méi qù   美國  dǎ   NBA
old  surname retreat five after Did not go 美國 strike NBA
Tsao didn't make his way to NBA.
反而  跑  去  二  手  車  廠  賣  車
fǎn ér   pǎo   qù   èr   shǒu   chē   chǎng   mài   chē
instead run  go  two hand  cart factory sell cart
He ended up selling second hand cars.
他  是  天生  好  手
tā   shì   tiān shēng   hǎo   shǒu
he  is   Born        good hand
And it turned out he's pretty good at it.
平均  每  兩天  就  可以  賣出  一  台車
píng jūn   měi   liǎng tiān   jiù   kě yǐ   mài chū   yī   tái chē
average   every Two days    just can    To sell  one Trolley
On average, he sells one car every other day.
嚇  死人  了
xià   sǐ rén   le
scare dead    is
Unbelievable.
引  擎  聲  它  騙  不了  人  的
yǐn   qíng   shēng   tā   piàn   bù liǎo   rén   de
attract support sound  it  swindle No more than that man  of
The engine never lies.
來
lái
come
Here.
你的  右腳  輕  踩  一下  油  門
nǐ de   yòu jiǎo   qīng   cai   yí xià   yóu   mén
your   Right foot light cǎi  a bit   oil  gate
Put your foot on the gas gently.
是  不是  還沒  改  喔
shì   bù shì   hái méi   gǎi   ō
is   not     not yet  change cry
Hear that sound?
還沒  改  之前  它  的  聲  線  就  已經  非常  的  飽滿
hái méi   gǎi   zhī qián   tā   de   shēng   xiàn   jiù   yǐ jīng   fēi cháng   de   bǎo mǎn
not yet  change prior to  it  of  sound  thread just already  very much  of  full
It's this powerful before we upgrade it, can you imagine if we do?
當  它  上路  之後  轉  速  到達  兩千  TURBO
dāng   tā   shàng lù   zhī hòu   zhuǎn   sù   dào dá   liǎng qiān   TURBO
that  it  On the road after that shift  quick Arrivals two thousand TURBO
I bet it is going to run over 2000 rpm when it hits the road.
馬  力  可說是  隨  傳  隨  到
mǎ   lì   kě shuō shì   suí   chuán   suí   dào
horse power Can be said to be follow summon follow arrive
The horsepower is beyond your imagination.
怎麼樣  啊  喜歡  吧
zěn me yàng   a   xǐ huan   ba
how is it    ah like     !
What do you think? You like it?
喜歡
xǐ huan
like
I like it.
喜歡  的話  我們  上路  開  一段  怎麼樣
xǐ huan   de huà   wǒ men   shàng lù   kāi   yī duàn   zěn me yàng
like     if      us      On the road open A paragraph how is it
Well then, how about we take this beast out for a ride?
好
hǎo
good
Okay.
GO
該  邊  考  上了  公  務  員
gāi   biān   kǎo   shàng le   gōng   wù   yuán
should side  examine On the    fair  affairs member
Groin passed the government worker's exam.
在  永  和  市  立  圖書館  當  行政  課  員
zài   yǒng   hàn   shì   lì   圖書館  dāng   xíng zhèng   kè   yuán
in   long  and  market stand 圖書館 that  administrative lesson member
He is now working as a librarian.
每天  都  在  騙  無知  的  小  美  眉
měi tiān   dōu   zài   piàn   wú zhī   de   xiǎo   měi   méi
every day all  in   swindle ignorance of  small beautiful eyebrows
Which he gets to play perform magic to young innocent girls every day.
同  學  看清楚  這  本  書  吹  口氣  吧
tóng   xué   kàn qīng chu   zhè   běn   shū   chuī   kǒu qì   ba
same  learning See clearly   this root book blow  Tone    !
See this book? Blow on it.
看  仔細  喔
kàn   zǐ xì   ō
look careful cry
Now, pay attention.
你  神  經  病  啊
nǐ   shén   jīng   bìng   a
you god   through illness ah
Are you nuts?
給  我  站住
gěi   wǒ   zhàn zhù
give I   stop
Stop there.
阿  和  那個  胖  子  在  當  保  險  業  務
ā   hàn   nà gè   pàng   zi   zài   dāng   bǎo   xiǎn   yè   wù
a  and  that one fat   offspring in   that  protect dangerous profession affairs
A-Ho became an insurance sales man.
很  喜歡  開  車  的  他
hěn   xǐ huan   kāi   chē   de   tā
very like     open cart of  he
He loves driving his car.
平均  一天  有  十二  個  小時  都  待  在  車  上  雖然  有  點  狼  狽
píng jūn   yī tiān   yǒu   shí èr   ge   xiǎo shí   dōu   dài   zài   chē   shàng   suī rán   yǒu   diǎn   láng   bèi
average   one day  have twelve  piece hour      all  treat in   cart on     although have dot   wolf  animal
Every day he spends about 12 hours in it, even though it's tough
但  他  一定  會  成功  的
dàn   tā   yī dìng   huì   chéng gōng   de
only he  for sure can  success     of
I do believe he will succeed one day.
畢竟  他  可是  我們  之間  唯  一  追到  過  沈  佳  宜  的  人  啊
bì jìng   tā   kě shì   wǒ men   zhī jiān   wéi   yī   zhuī dào   guò   chén   jiā   yí   de   rén   a
after all he  but     us      between   only one Catch up  pass sink  good suitable of  man  ah
After all he is the only person who has officially dated Shen Chia-Yi.
喂  李  先生  嗎
wèi   lǐ   xiān shēng   ma
hey  plum Mr          ?
Hello, is this Mr. Lee?
是  是  我  是
shì   shì   wǒ   shì
is   is   I   is
Yes, speaking.
對  啊  就是  上次  跟  您  提過  的  那個  壽  險  型  保  單  喔
duì   a   jiù shì   shàng cì   gēn   nin   tí guò   de   nà gè   shòu   xiǎn   xíng   bǎo   dān   ō
to   ah That is  Last time with you  mentioned of  that one lifespan dangerous pattern protect single cry
Hi, remember the insurance plan that I talked to you about last time?
我  已經  把  資料  都  準備  好了
wǒ   yǐ jīng   bǎ   zī liào   dōu   zhǔn bèi   hǎo le
I   already  take data     all  ready     All right
I have already gathered all the information for you.
那是  不是  跟  您  約  個  時間  到  您  公司  去  跟  您  做  個  詳細  的  說明
nà shì   bù shì   gēn   nin   yuē   ge   shí jiān   dào   nin   公司  qù   gēn   nin   zuò   ge   xiáng xì   de   shuō míng
That is not     with you  treaty piece time      arrive you  公司 go  with you  work piece detailed  of  Description
Just wondering when is a good time to pay you a visit in your office.
勃  起  大學  畢  業  後  先去  當兵  然後  立刻  飛去  美國  念  碩  士
bó   qǐ   大學  bì   yè   hòu   xiān qù   dāng bīng   rán hòu   lì kè   fēi qù   美國  niàn   shuò   shì
suddenly onward 大學 end profession after Go first Soldier    then     Immediately Fly away 美國 recall great scholar
Boner flew to America for graduate school immediately after his military service.
勃  起  的  英  文  很  爛
bó   qǐ   de   yīng   wén   hěn   làn
suddenly onward of  petal literature very rotten
Boner's English sucked
我  真  不知道  他  是  哪  來  的  勇氣  去  美國  玩  大  冒險
wǒ   zhēn   bù zhī dào   tā   shì   nǎ   lái   de   yǒng qì   qù   美國  wán   dà   mào xiǎn
I   real  do not know he  is   where come of  courage  go  美國 joke big adventure
I don't know how the hell he had the guts to go to the States.
大概  真的  很想  換  個國  家  打  手  槍  吧
dà gài   zhēn de   hěn xiǎng   huàn   gè guó   jiā   dǎ   shǒu   qiāng   ba
probably Really   Want to    change Country house strike hand  spear  !
Perhaps he wanted to masturbate in a different country.
如果  書念  不會  就  儘管  回來  知道  嗎
rú guǒ   shū niàn   bù huì   jiù   jǐn guǎn   huí lái   zhī dào   ma
in case Read the book will not just in spite of come back know     ?
If you can't stand it, just come back, understand?
媽  妳  不要  亂  講話  啦
mā   nai   bù yào   luàn   jiǎng huà   la
mother nǎi  Do not  confusion Speak      la
Ma, stop talking nonsense
媽媽  是  跟  你  說  真的  啦
mā mā   shì   gēn   nǐ   shuō   zhēn de   la
mum    is   with you speak Really   la
I am serious.
你  如果  書念  不好  就  回來
nǐ   rú guǒ   shū niàn   bù hǎo   jiù   huí lái
you in case Read the book not good just come back
If it's too hard, then just come back
媽媽  不會  罵  你  啦
mā mā   bù huì   mà   nǐ   la
mum    will not accuse you la
I will not blame you, I promise.
媽  我  知道  啦
mā   wǒ   zhī dào   la
mother I   know     la
Fine, I got it.
來  跟  爸爸  說  再見  一下
lái   gēn   bà ba   shuō   zài jiàn   yí xià
come with father speak Goodbye   a bit
Okay, it's dad's turn to say good-bye now.
勃  起  這  一  飛  兩年  又  過去  了
bó   qǐ   zhè   yī   fēi   liǎng nián   yòu   guò qù   le
suddenly onward this one fly  Two years   and  past    is
Two years gone by while Boner was overseas.
對了  還有  胡  家  瑋
duì le   hái yǒu   hú   jiā   wěi
correct and also recklessly house rare
Oh, yes, and there is Hu Chia-Wei.
那一  個  只會  畫  智  障  光頭  的  胡  家  瑋
nà yī   ge   zhǐ huì   huà   zhì   zhàng   guāng tóu   de   hú   jiā   wěi
That one piece Only will draw wisdom separate Bald head  of  recklessly house rare
That girl who always drew retarded stuff in her books.
現在  有  了  另外  一個  名字
xiàn zài   yǒu   le   lìng wài   yī gè   míng zì
now       have is  In addition One    first name
She now has another name.
彎  彎
wān   wān
bend bend
Wan Wan.
所以  囉  最後  會  實現  夢想  的
suǒ yǐ   luō   zuì hòu   huì   shí xiàn   mèng xiǎng   de
and so  nag  At last  can  achieve   dream       of
So it proves that those who realize their dreams
往往  不是  最有  才華  的  人
wǎng wǎng   bù shì   zuì yǒu   cái huá   de   rén
often      not     Most     Talented of  man
are often not the most clever ones in school.
而是  直到  最後  也  絕不  放棄  的  那一  個人
ér shì   zhí dào   zuì hòu   yě   jué bù   fàng qì   de   nà yī   gè rén
Instead until    At last  also no way  give up  of  That one people
But they are definitely those who persist till the end
我  很  高興  我  看  走  眼  了
wǒ   hěn   gāo xìng   wǒ   kàn   zǒu   yǎn   le
I   very happy     I   look walk eye  is
I am very glad that I was wrong.
當  勃  起  把  外國  學  歷  騙  回  台灣  的  時候
dāng   bó   qǐ   bǎ   wài guó   xué   lì   piàn   huí   tái wān   de   shí hou
that  suddenly onward take Foreign  learning past swindle return Taiwan   of  time
When Boner came home with a foreign degree
我  接到  了  一  通  電話
wǒ   jiē dào   le   yī   tōng   電話
I   Received is  one common 電話
I received a phone call.
喂
wèi
hey
Hello.
喂  老朋友  在  忙  嗎
wèi   lǎo péng yǒu   zài   máng   ma
hey  Old friend    in   busy  ?
Hello, old friend, are you busy?
當然  忙  啊
dāng rán   máng   a
of course busy  ah
Of course I am busy
不管  這  件事  第一  個  要  告訴  你
bù guǎn   zhè   jiàn shì   dì yī   ge   yào   gào su   nǐ
Regardless of this Something first  piece need tell    you
I don't care, there is something that I want you to be the first to know.
怎樣
zěn yàng
how
What is it?
有  空  讓  我  再  追  妳  一次  啊
yǒu   kōng   ràng   wǒ   zài   zhuī   nai   yī cì   a
have empty allow I   again pursue nǎi  once   ah
You got time for me to go after you again?
這  次  恐怕  不行  喔
zhè   cì   kǒng pà   bù xíng   ō
this order I am afraid No       cry
Not this time, I am afraid.
為什  麼
為什  me
為什 insignificant
Why?
欸  快  一點  啦
āi   kuài   yī diǎn   la
sigh rapid a little la
Hurry up!
今天  大  日子  耶
jīn tiān   dà   rì zi   yé
today     big day    ye
It's a big day today.
欸  你  想  讓  新娘  子  等  你  一個人  喔
āi   nǐ   xiǎng   ràng   xīn niáng   zi   děng   nǐ   yī gè rén   ō
sigh you think  allow bride      offspring wait  you A person   cry
You want to make the bride wait for you?
乾  杯
gān   bēi
dry  cup
Cheers.
後悔  了  吧
hòu huǐ   le   ba
regret   is  !
Regret it now?
當年  我  這麼  好  追  你們  全  都  去  追  沈  佳  宜  啦
dāng nián   wǒ   zhè me   hǎo   zhuī   nǐ men   quán   dōu   qù   zhuī   chén   jiā   yí   la
then       I   so      good pursue you     whole all  go  pursue sink  good suitable la
I was so available back then, but you guys all went for Shen Chia-Yi.
那  我  現在  追  還  來得及  嗎
nà   wǒ   xiàn zài   zhuī   hái   lái de jí   ma
that I   now       pursue still Come and get it ?
So does that mean I still have a chance?
你  很  爛  耶
nǐ   hěn   làn   yé
you very rotten ye
You suck!
其實  啊
qí shí   a
in fact ah
I got to tell you something
我  以前  沒有  認真  追  過  沈  佳  宜
wǒ   yǐ qián   méi yǒu   rèn zhēn   zhuī   guò   chén   jiā   yí
I   before   No       serious   pursue pass sink  good suitable
I wasn't really serious about chasing after Shen Chia-Yi before.
為什  麼
為什  me
為什 insignificant
Why?
因為  我  看  你們  大家  都  追  她
yīn wèi   wǒ   kàn   nǐ men   dà jiā   dōu   zhuī   tā
because  I   look you     everyone all  pursue she
I just didn't want to miss out.
所以  我  才跟  著  追  她  的  啊
suǒ yǐ   wǒ   cái gēn   jiáo   zhuī   tā   de   a
and so  I   Only with it manifest pursue she of  ah
Everyone went after her, so I did, too.
比起  我  啊
bǐ qǐ   wǒ   a
Compared to I   ah
In comparison to me
我  真的  覺得  你們  很不  要  臉  耶
wǒ   zhēn de   jué de   nǐ men   hěn bù   yào   liǎn   yé
I   Really   feel    you     Very bad need face  ye
I must say, you guys are shameless.
人家  現在  已經  成為  別人  的  新娘  子  了
rén jiā   xiàn zài   yǐ jīng   chéng wéi   bié rén   de   xīn niáng   zi   le
People   now       already  become     other people of  bride      offspring is
She is the bride today, but none of you is the groom.
你們  竟然  還有  臉  來  參加  這個  婚禮
nǐ men   jìng rán   hái yǒu   liǎn   lái   cān jiā   zhè ge   hūn lǐ
you     actually  and also face  come participate This one wedding
How dare you guys show your faces at this wedding.
真的  是有  夠  厚  臉  皮  的
zhēn de   shì yǒu   gòu   hòu   liǎn   pí   de
Really   there is enough thick face  skin of
Shameless!
許  博  淳
xǔ   bó   chún
allow gamble honest
Hsu Bo-Chun.
我  聽  你  在  喇  叭
wǒ   tīng   nǐ   zài   lǎ   bā
I   hear  you in   horn trumpet
Kiss my ass.
喝酒  啦
hē jiǔ   la
drink   la
Just drink!
好歹  我  也  曾經  追到  過  好不好
hǎo dǎi   wǒ   yě   céng jīng   zhuī dào   guò   hǎo bù hǎo
Whatever the outcome I   also once       Catch up  pass ok
Oh, please, I have dated her, haven't I?
那是  詐  胡  啦
nà shì   zhà   hú   la
That is cheat recklessly la
That was a scam.
對  啊  詐  胡  啦
duì   a   zhà   hú   la
to   ah cheat recklessly la
Exactly, cheater!
對了  對了
duì le   duì le
correct correct
Hey,
我們  來  打個  賭
wǒ men   lái   dǎ gè   dǔ
us      come Make a fight bet
let's make a bet.
我們  猜  拳
wǒ men   cāi   quán
us      guess fist
Let's do paper, scissors stone.
最  輸  的  那一  個人
zuì   shū   de   nà yī   gè rén
most transport of  That one people
The loser
等一下  要  在  新郎  新娘  進  場  的  時候  伸  腳  把  新郎  絆倒
děng yī xià   yào   zài   xīn láng   xīn niáng   jìn   chǎng   de   shí hou   shēn   jiǎo   bǎ   xīn láng   bàn dào
Wait         need in   bridegroom bride      advance field  of  time     extend foot  take bridegroom stumble
will have to trip the groom when they walk in later.
太  突然  了  啦  超  糗  的
tài   tú rán   le   la   chāo   qiǔ   de
very suddenly is  la  surpass embarrassing of
What the hell was that? It's embarrassing!
你們  這樣  很  壞  耶  一點  都  不懂  得  祝福
nǐ men   zhè yàng   hěn   huài   yé   yī diǎn   dōu   bù dǒng   dé   zhù fú
you     such      very bad   ye  a little all  Do not understand obtain blessing
You guys are mean. Can't you just show some love to the couple?
你  不懂  啦
nǐ   bù dǒng   la
you Do not understand la
You won't understand.
如果  你  真的  非常  喜歡  過  一個  女生  就  會  知道
rú guǒ   nǐ   zhēn de   fēi cháng   xǐ huan   guò   yī gè   nǚ shēng   jiù   huì   zhī dào
in case you Really   very much  like     pass One    Girls     just can  know
If you really like a girl.
要  真心  祝福  她  跟  別人  永遠  幸福  快樂  根本  是  不可能  的  事
yào   zhēn xīn   zhù fú   tā   gēn   bié rén   yǒng yuǎn   xìng fú   kuài lè   gēn běn   shì   bù kěn éng   de   shì
need sincere   blessing she with other people forever    happy    happy    fundamental is   impossible  of  thing
It is impossible to see her marry to another guy and still bless them.
對  啊
duì   a
to   ah
That's right.
像  我們  這  種  背後  放  箭  的  才  叫做  真愛
xiàng   wǒ men   zhè   zhǒng   bèi hòu   fàng   jiàn   de   cái   jiào zuò   zhēn ài
image  us      this seed   behind   put   arrow of  talent Called it Love
True love means someone should sneak up and stabs the groom in the back.
對  真愛
duì   zhēn ài
to   Love
Correct.
絆  死  他
bàn   sǐ   tā
loop die he
Trip him!
我  錯了
wǒ   cuò le
I   wrong
But I am wrong.
原來  當  你  真的  非常  非常  喜歡  一個  女孩
yuán lái   dāng   nǐ   zhēn de   fēi cháng   fēi cháng   xǐ huan   yī gè   nǚ hái
original  that  you Really   very much  very much  like     One    girl
In fact, when you really like a girl, you'd be happy for her.
當  她  有  人  疼  有  人  愛
dāng   tā   yǒu   rén   téng   yǒu   rén   ài
that  she have man  aches have man  love
When you see her finding her Mr. Right.
你  會  真心  真  意  的  祝福  她
nǐ   huì   zhēn xīn   zhēn   yì   de   zhù fú   tā
you can  sincere   real  thought of  blessing she
You will want them to be together.
永遠  幸福  快樂
yǒng yuǎn   xìng fú   kuài lè
forever    happy    happy
And to live happily ever after.
來  靠近  一點  喔
lái   kào jìn   yī diǎn   ō
come near     a little cry
Come closer.
再  一個  來  喔
zài   yī gè   lái   ō
again One    come cry
One more, ready
一  二  三  來
yī   èr   sān   lái
one two three come
1, 2, 3, go.
好  OK
hǎo   OK
good OK
OK
恭喜  恭喜  新婚  愉快
gōng xǐ   gōng xǐ   xīn hūn   yú kuài
Congratulations Congratulations Newly married happy
Congratulations, happy marriage.
快快  快
kuài kuài   kuài
Fast       rapid
Come, quickly
我  要  在  沈  佳  宜  旁邊
wǒ   yào   zài   chén   jiā   yí   páng biān
I   need in   sink  good suitable next to
I want to stand next to Shen Chia-Yi.
我們  要  拍  多  一點
wǒ men   yào   pāi   duō   yī diǎn
us      need clap much a little
We should take more photos.
要  拍  美  一點  喔
yào   pāi   měi   yī diǎn   ō
need clap beautiful a little cry
How do I look? Get a pretty one for me.
好  來  喔  來  喔
hǎo   lái   ō   lái   ō
good come cry come cry
All right. Here it comes.
準備  好了
zhǔn bèi   hǎo le
ready     All right
Ready.
來  一  二  三  來
lái   yī   èr   sān   lái
come one two three come
Ok, one, two, three, go.
再一次  喔  來  喔  來  喔  來  喔  再一次  喔  來
zài yī cì   ō   lái   ō   lái   ō   lái   ō   zài yī cì   ō   lái
one more time cry come cry come cry come cry one more time cry come
One more, one, two, three... done.
OK
謝謝
xiè xiè
Thank you
Thank you.
新郎  大哥  打個  商量
xīn láng   dà gē   dǎ gè   shāng liáng
bridegroom Big brother Make a fight discuss
Hey, man, we have a suggestion.
什麼  商量
shén me   shāng liáng
what     discuss
About what?
我們  紅  包  包  這麼  多
wǒ men   hóng   bāo   bāo   zhè me   duō
us      red   wrap wrap so      much
See, the thing is that we have loaded you with cash.
想  親  新娘  不知道  可不可以  耶
xiǎng   qīn   xīn niáng   bù zhī dào   kě bù kě yǐ   yé
think  relatives bride      do not know can we       ye
Don't you think we have the right to kiss the bride?
新娘  說  好  我  就  沒  問題  呀
xīn niáng   shuō   hǎo   wǒ   jiù   méi   wèn tí   ya
bride      speak good I   just not  problem yeah
Well, I am fine if she says fine.
好啊
hǎo a
Okay
Well, fine.
想  親  新娘  可以
xiǎng   qīn   xīn niáng   kě yǐ
think  relatives bride      can
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
不過  呢  等一下  你們  要  怎樣  親  新娘
bù guò   ne   děng yī xià   nǐ men   yào   zěn yàng   qīn   xīn niáng
but     this Wait         you     need how       relatives bride
You can kiss the bride.
就  要  先  怎麼  親  我
jiù   yào   xiān   zěn me   qīn   wǒ
just need first how     relatives I
But you have to kiss me first.
這樣  才  公平  啊
zhè yàng   cái   gōng píng   a
such      talent fair       ah
Kiss me the way you want to kiss her, so that's fair.
沒  聽說  過來  賓  要  親  新娘
méi   tīng shuō   guò lái   bīn   yào   qīn   xīn niáng
not  heard      come     guest need relatives bride
Bullshit!
還要  過  關  斬  將  的
hái yào   guò   guān   zhǎn   jiāng   de
But also pass close cut   will   of
What kind of rule is that?
對  啊
duì   a
to   ah
Yeah, no way.
你  這樣  太  小氣  了  啦
nǐ   zhè yàng   tài   xiǎo qì   le   la
you such      very stingy   is  la
Don't be stingy.
這樣  不對  啦
zhè yàng   bù duì   la
such      wrong   la
That is not right.
那  就  沒  辦法  囉
nà   jiù   méi   bàn fǎ   luō
that just not  Method  nag
Well then... sorry.
哈哈  哈  你們  打  的  如意  算  …
hā hā   hā   nǐ men   dǎ   de   rú yì   suàn   …
Haha   ha  you     strike of  Wishful count …
Ha, ha... Look at yourself, guys.
幹  嘛  啊
gàn   ma   a
trunk ma  ah
What?
昨天  謝謝
zuó tiān   xiè xiè
yesterday Thank you
Thank you for yesterday.
真的  假  的  啦
zhēn de   jiǎ   de   la
Really   falsehood of  la
Are you for real?
還  愛心  考  卷  咧
hái   ài xīn   kǎo   juǎn   liě
still Love    examine scroll grimace
A quiz made out of love...
你  錯  很多  耶
nǐ   cuò   hěn duō   yé
you error a lot of ye
You made so many mistakes.
你回去  沒  看  參  考  書  就  直接  寫  對不對
你回去  méi   kàn   cān   kǎo   shū   jiù   zhí jiē   xiě   duì bù duì
你回去 not  look intervene examine book just direct   write right
You did the problems without reading the exercise book, didn't you?
沈  佳  宜
chén   jiā   yí
sink  good suitable
Shen Chia-Yi.
妳  超  正  點  的
nai   chāo   zhèng   diǎn   de
nǎi  surpass right  dot   of
You were so cool when you shouted at him.
哭  起來  也  超  正  的
kū   qǐ lái   yě   chāo   zhèng   de
weep stand up also surpass right  of
You look so pretty when you cry, too.
雖然  我  還沒  追到  妳
suī rán   wǒ   hái méi   zhuī dào   nai
although I   not yet  Catch up  nǎi
Even though we are not seeing each other yet.
不過  那些  追  都  沒  追  過  妳  的  男  生
bù guò   nà xiē   zhuī   dōu   méi   zhuī   guò   nai   de   nán   shēng
but     those   pursue all  not  pursue pass nǎi  of  male life
But those guys who you don't even know.
怎麼  可以  牽  你的  手
zěn me   kě yǐ   qiān   nǐ de   shǒu
how     can    drag  your   hand
Can you not let them hold your hands?
我  自己  都  沒  牽  過
wǒ   zì jǐ   dōu   méi   qiān   guò
I   self   all  not  drag  pass
I haven't even held them myself.
你  特地  辦  個  比賽  把  自己  搞  受傷
nǐ   tè dì   bàn   ge   bǐ sài   bǎ   zì jǐ   gǎo   shòu shāng
you specially manage piece game    take self   clear Injured
You held this game and got yourself hurt.
你  怎麼會  這麼  幼稚  啊
nǐ   zěn me huì   zhè me   yòu zhì   a
you how come    so      naive    ah
How can you be so childish?
幼稚
yòu zhì
naive
Childish?
就是  幼稚
jiù shì   yòu zhì
That is  naive
Yes, childish.
很  幼稚
hěn   yòu zhì
very naive
Very childish and totally immature.
笨  蛋
bèn   dàn
foolish eggs
Idiot.
對  啦  我  就是  笨  蛋  啦
duì   la   wǒ   jiù shì   bèn   dàn   la
to   la  I   That is  foolish eggs la
Yes, I am an idiot.
大  笨  蛋
dà   bèn   dàn
big foolish eggs
Moron.
大  笨  蛋  才會  追  妳  這麼  久
dà   bèn   dàn   cái huì   zhuī   nai   zhè me   jiǔ
big foolish eggs Will only pursue nǎi  so      long
Only a moron can keep on trying to chase you for such a long time.
你  什麼  都  不懂
nǐ   shén me   dōu   bù dǒng
you what     all  Do not understand
You don't understand anything.
我  就是  什麼  都  不懂  啦
wǒ   jiù shì   shén me   dōu   bù dǒng   la
I   That is  what     all  Do not understand la
You're right, I don't!
對不起
duì bù qǐ
I am sorry
Sorry
是  我  太  幼稚  了
shì   wǒ   tài   yòu zhì   le
is   I   very naive    is
I was the immature one.
其實  會  解  這  種  題目  有  什麼  了  不起  的
qí shí   huì   jiě   zhè   zhǒng   題目  yǒu   shén me   le   bù qǐ   de
in fact can  loosen this seed   題目 have what     is  Can not afford to of
Being able to solve these tricky math questions does not help anything in life!
我  敢  跟  妳  賭
wǒ   gǎn   gēn   nai   dǔ
I   venture with nǎi  bet
You want to bet?
十年  後  我  連  LOG  是  什麼  都  不知道
shí nián   hòu   wǒ   lián   LOG  shì   shén me   dōu   bù zhī dào
ten years after I   join  LOG is   what     all  do not know
I won't even know what “log” means ten years later.
還  是  可以  活得  好好  的
hái   shì   kě yǐ   huó de   hǎo hǎo   de
still is   can    Live to live Well     of
And it doesn't make my life any harder.
嗯
n
ń
Emmmm.
妳  不  相信
nai   bù   xiāng xìn
nǎi  no  Believe
You don't believe me
我  相信  啊
wǒ   xiāng xìn   a
I   Believe    ah
I do believe you.
相信  還  那麼  用  功  讀書
xiāng xìn   hái   nà me   yòng   gōng   dú shū
Believe    still like that use   achievement reading
Then, why do you still work so hard?
人生  本來  就  有  很多  事  是  徒勞無功  的  啊
rén shēng   běn lái   jiù   yǒu   hěn duō   shì   shì   tú láo wú gōng   de   a
life       originally just have a lot of thing is   Futile          of  ah
You don't expect returns from everything you do.
你  想  知道  答案  嗎
nǐ   xiǎng   zhī dào   dá àn   ma
you think  know     answer ?
Do you want to know the answer?
如果  柯  景  騰  跟  我  告  白  的話  我  會  很  高興  的
rú guǒ   kē   jǐng   téng   gēn   wǒ   gào   bái   de huà   wǒ   huì   hěn   gāo xìng   de
in case stalk scenery fly   with I   tell white if      I   can  very happy     of
If Ko Ching-Teng comes and confesses to me I will be very happy.
沈  佳  宜
chén   jiā   yí
sink  good suitable
Shen Chia-Yi
我  喜歡  妳
wǒ   xǐ huan   nai
I   like     nǎi
I like you very much.
(Ok, let's be together)
真  羨慕  他們  呢
zhēn   xiàn mù   tā men   ne
real  envy     they    this
How I envy them.
謝謝你  喜歡  我
xiè xiè nǐ   xǐ huan   wǒ
thank you   like     I
Thank you for liking me.
那  我  就  繼續  幼稚  下去  囉
nà   wǒ   jiù   jì xù   yòu zhì   xià qù   luō
that I   just carry on naive    Go on   nag
Well then, I am just going to keep on acting childish.
一定  要  喔
yī dìng   yào   ō
for sure need cry
Sure, why not!
(Happy Marriage, to the apple of my eye)
洋  基  耶
yáng   jī   yé
ocean foundation ye
Hey, Yankees.
真的  耶
zhēn de   yé
Really   ye
Yeah!
阿  建
ā   jiàn
a  build
A- Chian.
柯  騰
kē   téng
stalk fly
Hey, Ko-Teng.
你  有  沒有  想過  把  我們  的  故事  寫成  小說  啊
nǐ   yǒu   méi yǒu   xiǎng guò   bǎ   wǒ men   de   gù shì   xiě chéng   小說  a
you have No       Thought about it take us      of  story   Written in 小說 ah
Have you thought about writing our story?
早就  想  啦
zǎo jiù   xiǎng   la
Long ago think  la
Of course I did!
只是  還想  不  到書  名  不知道  怎麼  開頭
zhǐ shì   hái xiǎng   bù   dào shū   míng   bù zhī dào   zěn me   kāi tóu
just     Think too  no  To the book name  do not know how     beginning
I just haven't come up a good name to start with.
我  打  手  槍  那  件事  可不可以  不要  寫
wǒ   dǎ   shǒu   qiāng   nà   jiàn shì   kě bù kě yǐ   bù yào   xiě
I   strike hand  spear  that Something can we       Do not  write
Hey, can you leave out the part which I was masturbating?
一定  寫
yī dìng   xiě
for sure write
Sorry man... that has to be in the story.
如果  你  真的  要  寫  的話
rú guǒ   nǐ   zhēn de   yào   xiě   de huà
in case you Really   need write if
If you really are going to write it.
記得  把  我  寫  帥  一點  啊
jì de   bǎ   wǒ   xiě   shuài   yī diǎn   a
remember take I   write commander a little ah
Don't forget to let your readers know how handsome I am.
順便  幫  我  徵  女  友
shùn biàn   bāng   wǒ   zhēng   nǚ   yǒu
By the way assist I   summon woman friend
By the way, can you put in some dating advertisements for me, too!
拜  託  你  不是  要  追  彎  彎
bài   tuō   nǐ   bù shì   yào   zhuī   wān   wān
bow  entrust you not     need pursue bend bend
Come on, I thought you are going after Wan Wan?
都  追  啦
dōu   zhuī   la
all  pursue la
Haha, doesn't really matter.
This is the last image we shot before wrapping up shooting.
The director conspired with the make-up artist to prank the cast.
And painted Michelle Chen's face into...